<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns Tech Blog</title>
    <description>This is my blog about version-controlled social production of open source technology ... feel free to reach out to me and tell me how I can be of service to you!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 20:50:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 20:50:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Burn It Down FIRST -- Why Criticism Trumps Building Stupid Shit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I really, really, really HATE safe spaces! Safe, criticism-free zones might just be the most pathological development in American history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://markbruns.github.io/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;You know that I like moldy ecosystems as much as the next guy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but … I am wondering,”So what if &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kasita.com/is-the-tiny-house-trend-dead/&quot;&gt;the tiny house trend is becoming ordinary, untrendy and boring&lt;/a&gt; … does that really matter if the tiny house trend dies as a trend and becomes a stable, mature and more solid STANDARD?” In a way, I think the demise of the trendiness would be a GREAT thing … the longer-term survival of the tiny house STANDARD might depend upon letting the more extreme and goofy ideas just die before they hurt anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardization sounds simple … as long as we can get others to standardize on our way of doing things … but standardization is HARD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardization means that there are some hard, practical choices and decisions that some of the principal players might need to make … these decisions are VOLUNTARY choices, but they must be intensely considerate of other people’s ideas, in order to allow standardization to be possible.  Nothing gets accepted as STANDARD unless there is almost unanimous consensus … almost NO designers are considerate enough by nature to produce true STANDARDS.  They dream of producing a standard; they can imagine that they are the Kind of France and mandate their standard on everyone else, but in spite of how mortal designers love to imagine that they can have the power of Steve Jobs, the fact is that there was one Steve Jobs and he has left the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kasita.com/#about&quot;&gt;Kasita container-esque idea&lt;/a&gt; HAS TO escape the Austin cartoon of itself [or the Portlandia cartoon of Portland] orbit … as well as the tiny house trend orbit … or it will die. I believe Kasita homes and Kasita parks and the Kasita concept MIGHT have the capacity to do that – since, the Kasita concept is one of the VERY FEW tiny house ideas that could survive the collapse of the tiny house trend universe if that is actually happening … &lt;strong&gt;but I am SKEPTICAL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my skepticism is driven by Kasita designers’ iPhone-ey focus on design RATHER than than Android/Linux focus on open source STANDARDIZATION and very long-term extensibility … which is an intensely practical matter of function … and the next generation’s functionality … and functionality for the generations after that.  Most of my skepticism is driven by my skepticism for ALL design ideas … ALL political ideas … ALL ideas … especially those which are merely whimsical or quirky or trendy or hip.  Some people are attached to their moldy, funky non-standard ideas in the same way that hoarders are attached boxes full of unique crap covered in black mold … the uniquer, moldier and funkier, the deeper the attachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A lot of houses and ghettos of houses in the world of ideas that should be burnt down … before they hurt someone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My critique of ANY tiny house idea, especially a proprietary, non-standard or one-off quirky hipster idea, is driven by a simple, deliberately harsh and nasty question, “After I die, could the executor of my estate pick up the phone and call a listing agent or some sort of broker/auctioneer who would readily convince someone else to buy [or even just assume ownership of at no cost] the cute little toy and live in the box? Does the idea still work long after the joke’s not funny any more and everyone in the world thinks it’s just a boring, disgusting, ubiquitous piece of trash (ie worse than a some hoarder’s mobile home rats nest in a trailer park)?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remodeling, re-appliance-ing, re-customizing homes is a completely banal idea, but it is a significant standard, structural, strategic ADVANTAGE of residential construction that we should not ignore, any more than we should ignore how water expands when it freezes or how turds strongly prefer to flow downhill.  We should ask if the basic shell of idea re-saleable like a 20’ shipping container or is the cute little quirky rat’s nest a disgusting liability that somebody will either have to nuke and make the sand glow OR some poor slob sweating in a hazmat suit will have to dispose of, like a hoarder’s collection of potentially hazardous, too-precious-to-part-with trash?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW … have you tried a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ebay.com/bhp/20-ft-shipping-container&quot;&gt;20’ shipping container&lt;/a&gt; on for size recently?  I’m guessing that a shipping container would fit you better than anything else you will find in the tiny house menagerie of goofball ideas … and it’s probably is a good way to transport any possession you need anywhere in the world [and if you need more things than a 20’ shipping container, you might need to re-prioritize and 5S your life] … and guess what, unlike other tiny house ideas which are basically about as marketable as a used condom, there’s actually a pretty vibrant MARKET for used shipping containers, after you get done with your shipping container, regardless of what kind of hipster slob you are.  In other words, before you ask me to put my shoulder to the wheel or invest in any tiny house venture, convince me that the idea driving your business will make your business a better value than investing in a bunch of 20’ shipping containers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/open/source/2016/08/31/Burn-It-Down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/open/source/2016/08/31/Burn-It-Down.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>open</category>
        
        <category>source</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why go to Mars when there are fungi here we haven&#39;t met yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea for this post STARTEED as sort of a riff on Feynman’s “There’s plenty of room at the bottom,” except the GIGANTIC difference is that a person cannot LIVE at the nano level … whereas a person can LIVE by spending a portion every single day becoming more knowledgable about things like soil and fungi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can START with the gigantic life-saving and life-improving stuff.  Understanding herbicide transformation is necessary for pesticide development for their safe and efficient use, as well as for developing pesticide bioremediation strategies for contaminated soil and water. Recent studies persuasively demonstrated the key role of soil white-rot fungi in biotransformation of various anthropogenic environmental contaminants. However, often this common knowledge is not associated with specific metabolic processes of fungi and therefore cannot be transformed into specific recommendations for agricultural practice.  Beyond just bioremediation of pollutants, think about how much more we don’t know about building and conditioning of soils for optimal productivity?  If we are so smart about soils, what stops us from making it possible for everyone to be surrounded by a luxurious garden and living foodscape?  The answer is that we are most decidedly NOT THAT SMART when it comes to soils and everything that soils could offer us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course oceans are very important, but since most humans live on land, human life is almost entirely based on what soil ecosystems.  Of course oceans are a significant source of protein and the importance of oceans certainly cannot be dismissed, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://core.ecu.edu/geology/woods/SEARESOURCES.htm&quot;&gt;less than 3% of the food consumed by humans comes from the oceans&lt;/a&gt;. – I have no problem whatsoever with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Ocean_Sampling_Expedition&quot;&gt;smart people who like oceans disagreeing with me on the importance of soils&lt;/a&gt;, as long as they are willing to back up their argument with actions and agree to move PERMANENTLY offshore. Very few humans live permanently on/in the ocean. It is interesting that oceans cover most of the Earth’s surface, but there has not been a universally accepted “Law of the Sea” and, frankly property rights do matter when it comes to caring for resource that is essential for sustaining life.  Soil sustains life.  What keeps a human alive should be something that every human knows something about. Soil should be one of those most important topics, something essential for EVERY human being to be at least somewhat knowledgable about … because soil issues drive life issues, food issues, water issues and climate issues. The LACK of this knowledge leads to some catastrophically erroneous choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people [erroneously] believe that the largest problem facing humanity involves carbon in the atmosphere … whether this is a concern or not, these people seem to completely ignore that 2,700 Gt of C stored in soils worldwide.  As almost all knowledgable gardeners or farmers would tell you, they would like to have more … MUCH more … organic material in their soil.  As anyone who loves growing things, anyone who loves having dirt under their fingernails, knows and there is a capacity to double, triple or quadruple the soil organic carbon in most soils under cultivation or in human use.  This is significant because there is only 780 Gt of C is in the atmosphere and a small percentage of humans believe that it should be two-thirds of that amount … guess what … taking 260 Gt of C from the atmosphere and sequestering it as soil organic matter represents less than a 10% increase C … never mind that the even with that extra 10%, those soils would still be C-deficient when compared with what would be optimum for productivity and health of those soils. This matters because if we assume that world’s oceans cannot be managed as a carbon sink [which is slightly debatable, but perhaps true because of property rights issues] it becomes clear that the carbon “problem” should be thought of as a globally distributed soil issue, not a matter of sequestering a giant amount of carbon is a single location.  It soil carbon is a matter that scales IF each human on the planet STARTS giving a tiny amount of thought to where and how the food is grown that they eat, ie the appropriate metaphor is not something cataclysmically moronic, eg visions of a pencil lead the size of New Mexico, but instead each citizen should be responsible for knowing enough about soil to produce their own food if they had to. In other words, the fear mongering of the climate change people is not at all helpful – FEAR-driven policy is catastrophic. KNOWLEDGE-driven policy is helpful. We can do a much better job of utilizing our soils for a variety of different issues – better knowledge of soils not only solves the carbon  issue, adding soil organic carbon will improve soil quality and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTHER issue with soil ecosystems involves essential compounds like antibiotics that originated from studies of soils.  People fail to realize how fundamentally these discoveries have transformed human existence … the real problem with this fundamental ignorance is the lack of understanding that we have only just scratched the surface.  We do not understand a tenth or even one-percent of what soil ecosystems have to offer … we do not even understand enough to know how small the fraction of that one-percent is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of how incomplete our knowledge is, consider how soil has, for millions of years, provides the environment for many different fungal species. These different species play an absolutely role in recycling nutrients through decay and breaking down of materials. Of course, these fungi produce different compounds [many essential for other species] in their digestive process but they do not just recycle nutrients by digest decaying plant matter. Fungi are attacked by bacteria which favor the same growing conditions and food stocks, but molds have defense mechanisms such as antimicrobial agents that prevent of the bacteria from making new cell walls and reproducing … as Penicillium chrysogenum … the ability of P. chrysogenum to produce antimicrobial agent penicillin appears to have evolved over hundreds of thousands or millions of years in soils in damp, consistent temperature environments in temperate and subtropical regions [which also favor bacterial growth]. Even though most humans now take penicillin for granted … few know that the sexual stage of P. chrysogenum was discovered only a few years ago, in 2013, by mating cultures in the dark on oatmeal agar supplemented with biotin, after the mating types (MAT1-1 or MAT1-2) of the strains had been determined using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction&quot;&gt;PCR&lt;/a&gt; amplification … the tools and technologies to do meaningful things are still being invented, as we stumble into things that we can’t “see” yet …  so we really don’t even know that much at all yet about how we would begin to set up practical methods to select and breed what has been one of the most important fungi to human beings … but others species, with uses we haven’t really discovered or conceived of yet, are almost necessarily more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When one considers that approximately 70,000 fungal species have been described, but the total number of fungal species is estimated to be well over 1.5 million and then one begins to understand that human beings have only begun to select and breed a very limited number of these fungal species for specific compounds and uses … when we factor in the chemical, bacterial, plant and animal interactions inside our soil ecosystems … it becomes almost painfully clear that our knowledge of soil ecosystems is teensy, especially in comparison to the human-scale crops and livestock that humans developed and perfected for over ten thousand years before even understanding that things like bacteria and fungi existed. Part of the lack of understanding is scale – in order to really understand micro interactions, it’s necessary to be able to observe at the nano scale. But it’s also matter of understanding ecosystem complexities to frame the questions about co-evolution and stumbling into things, inventing new approaches and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Fleming#Accidental_discovery&quot;&gt;making those REALLY BIG  mistakes&lt;/a&gt;, eg, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.helmholtz-muenchen.de/ibis/&quot;&gt;bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metabolomics&quot;&gt;metabolomics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction&quot;&gt;PCR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metagenomics&quot;&gt;metagenomics&lt;/a&gt; … and doing everything to SCALE THE KNOWLEDGABLE EXPLORATION of how and why the microbial world of soil ecosystems works the way it does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bioremediation,</category>
        
        <category>antibiotics,</category>
        
        <category>enzymes,</category>
        
        <category>metagenomics,</category>
        
        <category>soil</category>
        
        <category>ecosystems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The END of the American Experiment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dodd-Frank COMPLETELY changed my retirement plans … in a small way, that’s okay, I guess … life SHOULD come along and completely change things for a person; the’s the beauty of life.  In a much larger way, though, it is a really bad deal for America, Americans and all those who are allies and friends of Americans … in a nutshell, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/dodd-franks-effect-on-small-banks-is-muted-1443993212&quot;&gt;Dodd-Frank has eliminated NEW banking or financial company startup genesis, it has driven banks to merge and consolidate and, unsurprisingly, fewer and larger banks have effective monopolies in some markets boosting their pricing power, so profits of the fewer and larger banks have increased even as customers pay more for a shrinking or stagnant array of services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Dodd-Frank was passed, I had planned to work like a fiend, save everything I earned, invest diligently and then keep re-investing until I could retire at 59 1/2 [since a large portion of what eventually would be my liquid net worth was in IRA/401(k) accounts] to develop an investment company and start-up accelerator [primarily for fintechs] to encourage others to work, save and invest in startups – of course that including getting others to start their own small banks and investment companies.  After Dodd-Frank, I decided to retire early, there was no longer a point in saving, I gave away most of my assets [except for enough to cover my expenses and not be destitute] and I decided to “go Galt” writing, doing research, improving my health, preparing for the inevitable COLLAPSE.  So far the collapse has been unfolding in an especially stagnant fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a high birthrate of new employer firms … there is absolutely NO WAY to get the growth that will be necessary to responsibly handle the debt and contingent liabilities our nation as acquired through its copious expansion of entitlements … a diverse financial ecosystem with robust array of capital alternatives are essential for spurring the birthrate and initial expansion of new employer firms …. Dodd-Frank has killed the goose that laid the golden eggs; look at the disaster it has caused in banking, particularly in small banking and small financial companies – there’s been fewer than a handful of new small banking and small financial companies formed since Dodd-Frank … I do not see an alternative to an inevitable COLLAPSE, but I believe that sooner would be much better than later … while there are still people who remember what banking was like before Dodd-Frank, before Sarbanes-Oxley, before … voters started imagining that government could somehow protect them from their own greed, ignorance and irrational fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I worry that I might be over-confident or lacking in humility, I spend time looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodd%E2%80%93Frank_Wall_Street_Reform_and_Consumer_Protection_Act&quot;&gt;public perception of Dodd-Frank, not just the legislation but the actual regulatory implementation&lt;/a&gt; … few things have the absolute soul-crushing, slit-your-wrists-and-hope-no-one-finds-you quality of Dodd-Frank&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/collapse,/retirement/2016/08/21/Dodd-Franked.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/collapse,/retirement/2016/08/21/Dodd-Franked.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>collapse,</category>
        
        <category>retirement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Antifragile Government</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been watching and re-watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civilization:_Is_the_West_History%3F&quot;&gt;Niall Ferguson’s series on the six killer apps of Western Civilization&lt;/a&gt;. As I have been watching this program, I have also been thinking and reading supporting historical materials with an eye to understanding the demise of different empires and I am almost dumbfounded by the degree to which most people in great empires have always tended to forget the importance of their empire’s foundations, what made them great in the first place.  Thus, I completely agree with the whole premise of the show and highly recommend that others watch and re-watch the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot know if the number of “killer apps” is exactly six or the degree to which these “apps” are interrelated and basically share other deeper dependencies, but six killer apps is probably a good way for framing the discussion.  I believe that we should emphasize some things about those apps differently – the show [like any show broadcast for popular consumption] was constructed [or watered down] TO BE POPULAR and thus avoid any controversy or appearance of toughness or antifragility that would cause people to dismiss the entire show or even question the BBC, Ferguson and those funding the production of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I don’t face the same “lowest-common-denominator” constraint that Ferguson and the BBC did in 2011, so I can state that the six killer apps that made western civilization more antifragile, thus likely to gain from the disorder of history are: 1) intense competition [as a substitute for war], 2) the scientific method and widespread practical discovery, research and debugging, especially outside of academia or domains coercively dominated by the church, governments or similar political/religious institutions, 3) property rights and the Constitutional rule of law [providing the foundation for economic/cultural mobility within the republic and the world], 4) evidence-based environmental health and safety, awareness of fitness [for greater productivity and discipline by key individuals] and some key medical technologies, 5) free markets providing creative destruction of less efficient businesses and diverse alternatives for consumers and employees, 6) freedom of religious or philosophical thought [which underpins the motivation for things like a strong work ethic].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I DISAGREE rather strongly with Ferguson on his conclusion, that we simply need to believe in ourselves … we do need understand our history; that need is what drives Ferguson’s conclusion, as well as his occupational choice … so it’s rather obvious that Ferguson’s conclusion is a HISTORIAN’s conclusion.  That would be fine, but to simply believe in ourselves, to revel in our own greatness … or, what is now, PAST greatness, PAST conquests, PAST victories … might work for a popular show on television, but as a practical operational code, it will create a bunch of backward-looking pride-filled entitled, but impotent little monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom of religion and the philosophical quest still matters … not for experts, academics, high-priests – but for EVERY SINGLE PERSON. It is necessary to understand that the important part of “freedom of religion” is the FREEDOM part … freedom of inquiry, freedom to doubt, freedom to question … but we should acknowledge the practical necessity of having some sort of a belief system. Demanding that everyone must give up their religion is nothing more than demanding conformance to a belief in giving up religion.  One form of zealotry is as EVIL as another. History is replete with examples of the oppression and then stagnation that comes from conformity or uniformity in adherence to any religion or absence or religion (eg, Atheism or ~absence of religion~ and unquestioning faith in authoritarian communist State was the state religion of the USSR).  Freedom of religion serves the purpose of looking forward, for the quest for appropriate vision. As a practical matter all humans must heuristically believe in some higher power, a greater good, a larger agenda or philosophical objective to aspire to and motivate practical plans and SMART goals for conquering the next frontier … it is entirely illogical, meaningless, circular happy talk to tell people we must aspire to believe in ourselves or our pasts … we must look forward.  That means believing in Reality as it really is, not as we hope it might be, fear it might be or as others want us to believe it might be.  We must OPTIMISTICALLY see Reality as our friend; Reality is the ONLY reason we are here. Reality is the ONLY way forward. Instead of boastfully believing in ourselves, I believe that we should humbly seek to understand Reality as it really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our future Reality involves crisis, probably greater crisis than we have experienced at any time in the last two-thirds of a century. It is becoming increasingly apparent some sort of really serious breakdown in the American government is almost certain, perhaps sooner rather than later.  If it is sooner, then something like even civil war [or at least a declaration of martial law, suspension of Constitutional rights] will be likely within the next decade. I am optimistic because I believe that disruption and chaos can be extremely transformative opportunities for human growth. That absolutely does NOT mean that they are easy; it means than disruption and growth is far, far better than stagnation and drudgery. We are heading into very interesting times; these times will not be one bit easy at all; people will suffer and die and wish for less interesting times BUT tough times are necessary to shed weakness, lay the foundation for future post-traumatic growth. There are those who will believe with their full hearts and souls that these times are “end times” but WE humans do not get to decide when THE END is … it is far more likely that these are simply extremely difficult times that will push us and everything about our human institutions harder than we can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to understanding the way forward lies in understanding the essential nature of antifragility and things that gain from disorder and chaos. Small things, like cockroaches, fungus or bacteria, gain from chaos and that applies to our institutions. It is the increasingly centralized nature of our institutions that makes them and the populations that depend upon them weak. The problems of centralization cannot be solved through the same modes of command-and-control thinking that created them. Instead, antifragile solutions will require distributed innovation from decentralized, diverse populations of freethinking innovators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human species can endure far more than any human would ever want to because although herds of dependent humans who look to experts are weak, independent humans who look to their direct experience and Reality-driven knowledge are antifragile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/government/2016/08/17/Antifragile-Government.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/government/2016/08/17/Antifragile-Government.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Government</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pine64 And The Essential Element of a Hobbyist Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My Pine64 boards showed up last week … actually before I expected to receive them … I have come to expect people who organize and run crowdfunding campaigns for hardware underestimate how difficult it will be to meet any significant project deadline … hardware is HARD.  Shipping hardware and dealing with all of the issues that come from customers attempting to use harder is REALLY hard … but building an open source community around open source hardware is HARDER still … maybe IMPOSSIBLY hard … THAT is WHY I backed the Kickstarter project, not to build and open source community … but maybe to watch it happen, maybe to help make it happen, MOSTLY to see how and why community building comes up short … or what can be done differently next time … and I am absolutely certain that there WILL BE a next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, cultivating an open source community seems to be a matter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.safaribooksonline.com/library/view/cultivate-conference-2016/9781491959701/&quot;&gt;cultivation of leadership&lt;/a&gt; when you do not have the authority to supervise, order or command behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is the project important enough to get people on board, why is the project important enough to motivate you to become a significant participant and leader?  (For example, I do not yet know if Pine64 is really worth my time … I was hopeful, so I forked over some cash to support the initial build, but beyond that … )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you maintain a heartbeat?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/kickstarter/2016/06/05/Pine64.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kickstarter/2016/06/05/Pine64.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>KickStarter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personal Financial Independence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;1) The most essential thing to understand is personal finance is not about investments, it is about YOU, about your independence … YOUR independence means that you make the rules AFTER you pay your way … so personal finance is about YOU, your weaknesses, how much you need comfort, how much you depend upon reinforcement from others. It is certainly NOT about some investment or another, particularly not something that is popular with all of your friends, eg a home purchase.  The person who looks to the opinions of others or measures his wealth according to how well others are doing will NEVER have enough wealth and will always be impoverished. Stop being needy; stop groveling; stop whining, stop being an entitled victim. Do NOT waste ANY time making excuses or thinking that somebody else has it easy. Stop imagining that somebody else should bail you out or invest in your idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Ditch your addictions; ditch the relationships that are not going anywhere; ditch the baggage. First do no harm … especially to your independence. You are an adult and old enough to know that you should not impose your costs on other people. Addicts always have a way of rationalizing robberies, leaching from friends/parents or other ways that somebody else should pay for their addiction.  If you are addicted to bad things, you need to limit the damage those things are doing to you.  It’s not just about the obvious additions like heroin, alcohol or tobacco … addictions include things like tv watching, social media, worthless friends or some other non-value-added distraction. You might believe that you are not an addict, that you can take or leave the thing without any consequences – if that’s true, just avoid the thing for a couple months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Invest in your productivity every single day … do as much as what is possible for you, do not worry about the impossible – that will come. Get in shape so that you can get in shape so that you can get in shape and the impossible will become possible.  Whether you are a morning person or not, get up at 4:39 AM and CRUSH your workout … even if your workout is almost nothing. Physical fitness drives mental fitness. You do not need a gym or dojo membership or a lot of equipment – you can do burpees, pushups, do yoga, take the stairs, clean the house, do yard work. When you start CRUSHING each day’s workout, tomorrow’s workout will mattering and pulling you forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Invest in your health, nutrition and diet every single day … do what is possible, do not worry about the impossible.  Eat better today than you did yesterday and commit to doing this every day for the rest of your life. You know what you should eat; you know what you can afford. For most of eating better is a matter of eating LESS, particularly of one or two things we know we should avoid. If you slip up and have a Krispy Kreme or something you know you shouldn’t have eaten, do not dwell on it – just eat better tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Avoid distractions and costly habits and addictions; avoid friends with addictions who refuse to deal with their addictions. Instead work more on things of value to others that you enjoy. Most creative people and multi-millionaires are working fiendishly on seven to ten serious projects … none of these people are one-off wonders, none of the truly productive or creative people define themselves by the superior tastes in microbrews, food or art … they define themselves with their work. You cannot tell which of these projects will pay off or when it will pay off – the important thing is to keep working obsessively on what you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Control your projector. Inoculate your mind with the kinds of ideas that you want to shape your thinking. The best ideas are the old school ideas that have been around for 2000 years and still inspire current thinking. For example, read and internalize &lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2015/05/28/a-dozen-things-ive-learned-from-seneca-the-younger-about-venture-capital-startups-business-and-life/&quot;&gt;what Seneca said about wealth&lt;/a&gt; … Google “Seneca” routinely to find new reflections from brilliant people on how they apply the words of Seneca to their lives.  In order to escape poverty, it’s essential that you look HARD at how you are spending money and either invent, find or STEAL better ways to enjoy life more while spending less. When you have developed ways to get your cost of living down to $0/day, you don’t need much of a fortune to be fabulously wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) You are the average of your five closest old friends; since this applies to them as well, it is up to you to work with them to increase your average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Curate a set of 100 mentors … blogs, podcasts, YouTube channels … Nicolas Nassim Taleb, Barry Ritholz, Niall Ferguson, Milton Friedman, Thomas Sowell, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8RDCtMEHFLM&quot;&gt;Dave Grossman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkqcY4CAuBFNFho6JgygCnA&quot;&gt;Jocko Willink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/&quot;&gt;Bruce Schneier&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Curate a reading list of 100 books you are reading, re-reading … you do not necessarily need to start right away with Seth Klarman’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://files.leopolds.com/books/Margin.of.Safety.1st.Edition.1991.Klarman.pdf&quot;&gt;Margin of Safety&lt;/a&gt; but eventually you must read it because of what it has to say about discipline, effort, mindset and absolute control of emotions BEFORE investing large amounts of capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Be extremely careful with the use of credit … it is best if you can pay off your debts, but sometimes [eg an existing debt from the past, an accident, an unforeseen medical expense] that is just not feasible.  Realize that debt is not JUST about paying interest to use money, it is ALSO something that constrains your flexibility and options in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11) Before you have to … start thinking about how you are going to completely reinvent yourself.  The next phase of your life may not be what you expect. Your retirement almost certainly will not be what you expect.  Start thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2015/10/reinventing-yourself/&quot;&gt;writing your own guide for completely reinventing yourself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12) Be able to find your way around the world of patents … and scientific literature … and Github repos … and data APIs …  do not EVER, EVER, EVER trust some factcheck organization to give you the truth.  What all factcheck organizations specialize in is the evil art of crafting LIES that look sciencey, look like facts, look truthy. The scientific method still works but that means that YOU must use the method – the fundamental truth of the scientific method is that you do not ever simply trust anyone who claims that they have used the scientific method [so you needn’t check their work].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13) Money is not paper or metal or digital; money is TRUST. For most people, money is basically magic because they trust the system of currency even though it is far beyond anything that they can know well enough to trust. You may want to participate in traditional assets, but you should also invest in different things that you know and know that you can trust … tools, seeds, soil, knowledge, networks, weapons and other hard assets that give you options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14) As Teddy Roosevelt said, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/t/theodorero100965.html&quot;&gt;“Do what you can, with what you have, where you are.”&lt;/a&gt; This means taking honest, careful FULL inventory of what resources are available to you and instead of whining about not having the best, making the best of that stock of resources. ANY time spent being jealous or envious or wanting what someone else has, wanting something beyond your means or beyond what you can do with what you have is time WASTED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15) Read everything you can find to get ideas, but do not trust experts. Experts might be remarkable in their ability to generate ideas, but the ONLY way for you to trust something is for YOU to have TRIED it. Invest in what you KNOW works; do NOT invest heavily in what some expert you believe tells you will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16) Death is certain. Not just for humans, but we also know that the entropy of the universe is always increasing. Everything dies. What you can affect is the window of time before death … in other words, invest effort in appreciating, utilizing and exploiting NOW to the fullest and practice getting better at doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17) Beyond investing in your own productivity and accelerating the development of your own productivity (ie learning how to learn and improving your ability to learn how to learn), also work at investing the productivity of the team than you work with (eg, Github codegraph, GitHub for Teams, Github API).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18) Take a serious inventory of your skills while being mindful of our place in history. You are going to have workout, to get after it, to CRUSH your mental and physical workouts as you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/investor/2014/01/27/active-productive-assets-the-answer-to-the-conundrum-of-potential-financial-ruin/2/#487e43325be7&quot;&gt;skill yourself up&lt;/a&gt;. Invest in your own intellectual property.  Make yourself useful to others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/finance,/investment,/independence/2016/05/21/Personal-Finance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/finance,/investment,/independence/2016/05/21/Personal-Finance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>finance,</category>
        
        <category>investment,</category>
        
        <category>independence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lean Government</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people believe in government in the same way that four-year-olds believe in Santa Claus.  They believe because the rest of the human species has lied to them and it has never occurred to them that they had a choice in questioning their belief in government.  So governments persist … for the same reason that any group of four-year-olds will persist in their belief in Santa Claus – nothing will derail that that belief, because the four-year-olds WANT to believe in Santa … governments persist because people DESPERATELY, HOPELESSLY, UNFAILINGLY need to believe in governments [because deep down, they’re all little kids who still really WANT to believe in Santa].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments have ALWAYS existed to protect the interests of already powerful, wealthy and general affluence who want to preserve their power and wealth … there’s nothing especially dark or conspiratorial going here – government is MOSTLY just a matter of preserving the rules of the game, eg the currency in your wallet can be spent; if you buy a car, you get title to the car to prove you own it … but we should remember that the already powerful have the inside track on preserving and EXPANDING their power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does technology have to do with it?  Technology is inherently DISRUPTIVE of power … even though powerful and wealthy citizens are good at investing in [and sometimes subverting] technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But technology can also disrupt the inefficiencies that the powerful exploit to control government. Government does not have to be inefficient … even if the gross inefficiency of government will probably be what ultimately brings about the mass annihilation of all humans and other lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government does not have to be coercive … believe it or not, instead of broadcasting propaganda to the masses, a government could actually LISTEN to what individual human beings want in order to boost the efficiency of government.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/government/2016/03/24/Lean-Government.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/government/2016/03/24/Lean-Government.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Government</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prediction Markets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe much in polls anymore … it’s not just that the polling data is limited to the people who are in the phone database of the pollsters; most people really HATE to be polled and accordingly have all kinds of incentives for telling pollsters everything other than the truth just so that the pollster will leave them alone.  The big reason that I detest polls is the euphoric over-reaction that people have following media hype and mainstream media news coverage – TEMPORARILY hot candidates do much better in polls than prediction markets.  Prediction market traders see past the hype and discount for future success and/or failure, not just current standing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in prediction markets because prediction markets are driven by knowledgable people who want to trade or bet real hard-earned cash on their insights.  As we might expect prediction markets are extremely accurate indication of where the electorate is at a given time – the prediction markets result from election day almost always matches up exactly with the final result before the networks have called the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s look at prediction markets … first look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/politics/2016RepNomination&quot;&gt;current GOP Presidential nomination race&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4174&quot;&gt;September 8 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Bush appears to be weak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4184&quot;&gt;September 16 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Trump, Rubio … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4187&quot;&gt;September 17 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4212&quot;&gt;September 27 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4222&quot;&gt;October 4 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4234&quot;&gt;October 11 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Bush has been almost overtaken by Rubio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4247&quot;&gt;October 18 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Bush, Trump  … the Establishment front-runner is now Rubio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4263&quot;&gt;October 25 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Bush, Trump … Bush continues to slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4277&quot;&gt;November 1 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Bush … Bush is overtaken by Trump&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4290&quot;&gt;November 8 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Cruz … Bush is overtaken by Cruz who has 12%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4305&quot;&gt;November 15 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Cruz … Rubio climbs to 48%, Trump 19%, Cruz 13%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4314&quot;&gt;November 22 2105&lt;/a&gt; …  Rubio, Trump, Cruz … Rubio still at 48%, Trump 22% (which may be Trump’s peak), Cruz 13%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4325&quot;&gt;November 29 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Cruz … the Establishment front-runner Rubio appears to have peaked at 48%, Trump 24%, Cruz 14%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4340&quot;&gt;December 6 2105&lt;/a&gt; …  Rubio, Trump, Cruz … the Establishment front-runner Rubio at 40% is sliding, Trump at 27% (which also may be Trump’s peak), Cruz at 15%&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/markets/2015/12/24/Prediction-Markets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/markets/2015/12/24/Prediction-Markets.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Markets</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to Reinvent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a starter list … read it over, agree/disagree, change it, improve it, reinvent your own list for reinventing yourself.  This one is mine [in its current revision]; I &lt;em&gt;plageurized, cheated, stole&lt;/em&gt; and reinvented it after reading and re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2013/12/the-ultimate-cheat-sheet-for-reinventing-yourself-2/&quot;&gt;James Altucher’s THE ULTIMATE CHEAT SHEET FOR REINVENTING YOURSELF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A) Learn to &lt;em&gt;plageurize, cheat, steal&lt;/em&gt; but make the REINVENTION your OWN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OWN your life. Put that life together with the free stuff that you find laying around, but do not just accumulate a pile of junk.  Shaping the stuff that you have laying around into your reinvented future takes ingenuity, vision and EFFORT.  Fixing and polishing your reinvented life is not easy before it is a success; get used to being second-guessed and disrepected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B) Worry about NOW. 5S your life. Focus on your health, your breathing, your diet, the small details.  Fall in love with the person you are becoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by moving the needle on your level of fitness and productivity, so that you have more time and energy to tackle other areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take baby steps, but program yourself each day to have better habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C) Reinvention never stops … start today, but realize that you cannot reinvent yourself in a month or a year, you need to work a five-year plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’a all about the Plan-Do-Check-Act cycle. Every day, every week, every month, every year you need to invest a small amount of time in checking your progress doing what you’ve planned, taking action to bring your performance in line with the plan, then re-calibrating the plan and doing it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a description of what you might expect in the five year plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year One: you are flailing, drinking from the firehose, reading and absorbing everything, you are learning fast, but you’re a like baby … life is tough.
Year Two: you are still “selling snake oil” but know who you need to talk to and network with, i.e. you understand the movers, dice, cards and board layout of your new game.
Year Three: your plan is good enough to start making some money, but it isn’t anything to brag about and probably is not a living yet.
Year Four: your plan is providing an okayish living
Year Five: your plan is starting to compound and give you indications that it might generate real wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it works better, faster than that, great … but don’t expect and prepare yourself mentally for it to be worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D) Give everything away; ditch your baggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanna be more effing tough, you need to develop the SKILLS to be able to continually start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screw pride! Waste your time in dick measuring contests and your core competency is LOSING dick measuring contests. #TheresAlwaysABiggerDick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E) You need a mentor of some sort another.  You also need to mentor others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of mentors; here are three archetypes … there are more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Respected master. Be EXTREMELY CAREFUL. Do NOT join a cult. Certainly do no seek to be a cult leader … be careful when others follow you.
2) Indirect. Books, podcasts, vlogs, blogs, social media
3) Ordinary “average joe.””  Everyone has unique skill, knowledge about something. Every person could be your mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F) Program yourself to not be passive and programmed, be more skeptical, ask more questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THINK! Become a listening leader – seek out people who are DIFFERENT than you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G) Be more humble. You are not humble enough right now, you will be humiliated. Get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think you can reinvent yourself easier, faster, better or without giving up everything – then you too damned arrogant, too full of pride, not really ready, willing or able to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do NOT succumb to your own PR and start imagining that you walk on water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H) It’s not about the money … well, okay to some degree it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people say “it’s not about the money” they should make sure they have a different measuring stick; money is not a bad measuring stick to start with, but you need a better WHY than just money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about just doing what you love?” There will be many days when you don’t love what you are doing. If you are doing it just for love then it will take much much longer than five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is just a positive perception from our brain. Some days you will be unhappy. Our brain is a tool we use. It’s not who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I) When can you say, “I do X!” where X is your new career or your new enterprise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J) When can I start doing X?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read … listen to mentors, but don’t waste all day reading.
Write … dream, but don’t spend all day dreaming … write down your dreams and start sketching out a plan.
Plan-Do-Check-Act … start spec-ing out the idea for your business/life. Get going today. Get up tomorrow and do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K) How will this business or new life of mine ever make money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, it won’t you will have to scramble for a couple years, working at other jobs or somehow scraping together the money to live on and begin starting your business.  Starting a business necessarily involves doing OTHER things … full-time … stop believing that you are entitled to be carried while you start your business … you don’t get to watch televison or relax anymore if you want to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first “alpha” year, you must reconceive your customer – to do this you have to work doing the research to develop a competitive situational awareness in your niche to understand what you will need to do to be one of the best 200-300 people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second “beta” year, you will work hard at doing what you need to do to launch your prototype product or service and then correcting the flaws so that you move beyond the “beta” level to begin getting solid paying customers and building your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By year three you’ve put in 5,000-7,000 hours and you launch the real deal … something that is good enough to be in the top 200-300 in the world in anything. The top 200 in almost any field makes a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By year four you will scale that up and polish to take out the non-value-added distractions to allow you to make a decent, comfortable living. Some people stop at year four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By year five you’re in the top 30-50 so you can actually invest in compounding your succcess to make genuine wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M) What is “it”? How do I know what I should do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever area you feel like reading 500 books about. Go to the bookstore and find it. If you get bored three months later go back to the bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to get disillusioned. That’s what failure is about. Success is better than failure but the biggest lessons are found in failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very important: There’s no rush. You will reinvent yourself many times in an interesting life. You will fail to reinvent many times. That’s fun also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many reinventions make your life a book of stories instead of a textbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people want the story of their life to be a textbook. For better or worse, mine is a book of stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why reinvention happens every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;N) The choices you make today will be in your biography tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make interesting choices and you will have an interesting biography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;N1) The choices you make today will be in your biology tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O) What if I like something obscure? Like biblical archaeology or 11th-century warfare?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat all of the steps above, and then in year five you will make wealth. We have no idea how. Don’t look to find the end of the road when you are still at the very first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P) What if my family wants me to be an accountant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many years of your life did you promise your family? Ten years? Your whole life? Then wait until the next life. The good thing is: you get to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose freedom over family. Freedom over preconceptions. Freedom over government. Freedom over people-pleasing. Then you will be pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q) My mentor wants me to do it HIS way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s fine. Learn HIS way. Then do it YOUR way. With respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully nobody has a gun to your head. Then you have to do it their way until the gun is put down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R) My spouse is worried about who will support/take care of kids?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then after you work 16 hours a day, seven days a week being a janitor, use your spare time to reinvent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who is reinventing ALWAYS has spare time. Part of reinvention is collecting little bits and pieces of time and re-carving them the way you want them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;S) What if my friends think I’m crazy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What friends?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T) What if I want to be an astronaut?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a reinvention. That’s a specific job. If you like “outer space” there are many careers. Richard Branson wanted to be an astronaut and started Virgin Galactic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U) What if I like to go out drinking and partying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this post again in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V) What if I’m busy cheating on my husband or wife or betraying a partner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this post again in two or three years when you are broke and jobless and nobody likes you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W) What if I have no skills at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read “B” again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X) What if I have no degree or I have a useless degree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read “B” again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y) What if I have to focus on paying down my debt and mortgage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read “R” again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Z) How come I always feel like I’m on the outside looking in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein was on the outside looking in. Nobody in the establishment would even hire him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone feels like a fraud at some point. The highest form of creativity is born out of skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AA) I can’t read 500 books. What one book should I read for inspiration?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BB) What if I’m too sick to reinvent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reinvention will boost every healthy chemical in your body: serotonin, dopamine, oxytocin. Keep moving forward and you might not get healthy but you will get healthier. Don’t use health as an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, reinvent your health first. Sleep more hours. Eat better. Exercise. These are key steps to reinvention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CC) What if my last partner screwed me and I’m still suing him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop litigating and never think about him again. Half the problem was you, not him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DD) What if I’m going to jail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect. Reread “B.” Read a lot of books in jail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EE) What if I’m shy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your weaknesses your strengths. Introverts listen better, focus better, and have ways of being more endearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FF) What if I can’t wait five years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on being alive in five years then you might as well start today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GG) How should I network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make concentric circles. You’re at the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next circle is friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next circle is online communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is meetups and coffees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is conferences and thought leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is customers and wealth-creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start making your way through the circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HH) What happens when I have ego about what I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 6-12 months you’ll be back at “B”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II) What if I’m passionate about two things? What if I can’t decide?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine them and you’ll be the best in the world at the combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JJ) What if I’m so excited I want to teach what I’m learning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start teaching on YouTube. Start with an audience of one and see if it builds up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KK) What if I want to make money while I sleep?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In year four, start outsourcing what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LL) How do I meet mentors and thought leaders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have enough knowledge (after 100-200 books), write down 10 ideas for 20 different potential mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of them will respond. Write down 10 more ideas for 20 new mentors. Repeat every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put together a newsletter for everyone who doesn’t respond. Keep repeating until someone responds. Blog about your learning efforts. Build community around you being an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MM) What if I can’t come up with ideas?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then keep practicing coming up with ideas. The idea muscle atrophies. You have to build it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for me to touch my toes if I haven’t been doing it every day. I have to do it every day for a while before I can easily touch my toes. Don’t expect to come up with good ideas on day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NN) What else should I read?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFTER books, read websites, forums, magazines. But most of that is garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OO) What if I do everything you say but it still doesn’t seem like it’s working?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will work. Just wait. Keep reinventing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try and find the end of the road. You can’t see it in the fog. But you can see the next step and you do know that if you take that next step eventually you get to the end of the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PP) What if I get depressed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sit in silence for one hour a day. You need to get back to your core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this sounds stupid then don’t do it. Stay depressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QQ) What if I don’t have time to sit in silence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then sit in silence for two hours a day. This is not meditation. This is just sitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RR) What if I get scared?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep 8-9 hours a day and never gossip. Sleep is the No. 1 key to successful health. It’s not the only key. It’s just No. 1. Some people write to me and say, “I only need four hours of sleep” or “in my country sleeping means laziness.” Well, those people will fail and die young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about gossip? The brain biologically wants to have 150 friends. Then when you are with one of your friends you can gossip about any of the other 150. If you don’t have 150 friends then the brain wants to read gossip magazines until it thinks it has 150 friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be as stupid as your brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SS) What if I keep feeling like nothing ever works out for me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend 10 minutes a day practicing gratitude. Don’t suppress the fear. Notice the anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also allow yourself to be grateful for the things you do have. Anger is never inspirational but gratitude is. Gratitude is the bridge between your world and the parallel universe where all creative ideas live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TT) What if I have to deal with personal bullshit all the time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find new people to be around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who is reinventing herself will constantly find people to try and bring her down. The brain is scared of reinvention because it might not be safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biologically, the brain wants you to be safe and reinvention is a risk. So it will throw people in your path who will try to stop you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to say “no.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UU) What if I’m happy at my 9-t0-5 job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine. Good luck. You are not one of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VV) Why should I trust you – you look like a failure to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do NOT trust me.  But be VERY VERY cynical of someone who portrays himself as a master with all of the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WW) Will you be my mentor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have just read this entire post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/11/30/Reinvention.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/11/30/Reinvention.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Monk Thing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am just an OLD MONK, but after seeing friends and family again over Thanksgiving, I have been thinking a LOT about how I should TRAIN now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that my training not at all about me anymore, it’s mostly about what I should do so that I can more effectively work with others or assist others in THEIR training.  When an old monk survives long enough, he becomes more interested in next generation training (i.e. I want to train for the FUTURE threat, not my survival or the threat of yesterday or today). Some time ago, I started looking into training SYSTEMS … there are old school martial arts traditions, but there are plenty of worthy modern examples also such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.combatical.com/&quot;&gt;Marine Corps Martial Arts close combat training&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kravmaga-ikmf.com/krav-maga/train-in-israel/warriors-quest/&quot;&gt;Israeli Krav Maga training&lt;/a&gt;.  Since I respect traditions, I realize that I am not really any different from those who have come before me.  I am just an OLD MONK … but I am obligated to train others because I survived to be an old monk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some fairly simple and timeless rules that emerge …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-daily-practice-that-supports-and-sustains-you-and-advances-your-art&quot;&gt;Create a daily practice that supports and sustains you and advances your art.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Get up and get moving, move throughout the day. Try to eat better each day than you did the day before
2) Do the HARD THING that you fear most first so that your mind is clear to write, code, implement, debug
3) Play with principles and your original extension of principles rather than memorizing specific techniques, quotes, phrases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rest-and-relax-without-engaging-in-bad-unmindful-habits&quot;&gt;Rest and relax without engaging in bad unmindful habits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) If you need a distraction from your pathetic life, you’re doing it wrong.
2) Use or don’t use sex or stimulants or drugs or asceticism, but do not allow addiction to rule you.
3) Practice the habits of mindfulness, especially in your rest and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-essence-of-being-a-warrior-is-never-quitting-on-yourself&quot;&gt;The essence of being a warrior is never quitting on yourself.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Relapse is a necessary part of recovery, recovery is necessary to beat addiction. Don’t let relapse lead you back to addiction.
2) Celebrate your victories by working on your humility; never be satisfied – always think about the ways that you could have done something better or helped others more.
3) Be more anonymous, but rule by example. Avoid dick measuring competitions. Work harder at channeling desire for wealth, power, fame, sex, comfort into helping others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-can-be-dead-serious-without-losing-your-sense-of-humor&quot;&gt;You can be dead serious without losing your sense of humor.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Practice giving humor speeches or being a standup comic.
2) Have a point, but illustrate your point with humor, koans, riddles.
3) Shut up and listen.  Work on being a better listener.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/to/learn/2015/11/30/The-Monk-Thing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/to/learn/2015/11/30/The-Monk-Thing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        <category>to</category>
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
