<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns</title>
    <description>Every so often I realize that I am a collection of bad habits that I work very hard to maintain; I'm trying to knock that off ... https://xkcd.com/1579/</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 14:57:31 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 14:57:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Amazon Kindle Template</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Aim to write an INSANELY useful book for a reader who was at your level before you have learned what you have learned the HARD way … think of your audience as you, five or ten or twenty years ago … what can you tell that audience that will get them up to your level of understanding in a tenth or one-hundredth of the time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, this means that you should begin by writing an impassioned, stream-of-consciousness, extra-shitty no-filters SUPER HONEST first draft … ABSOLUTELY NO FILTERS.  RAW.  UNEDITED. PURE TANGLED CRAP!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can suck … because the first draft is for nothing other than basic wild-ass THINKERING and a chaotic BRAIN DUMP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the revision-upon-revision after thousands of levels of revisions ever amount to anything, after a decent final product emerges, the first draft can be THROWN AWAY … so what if it sucks … the point is put ideas down and START getting your head wrapped around the project … the point is to NOT BE PARALYZED by some ridiculous need to type out a first draft of EXCELLENCE … your draft might somehow be entirely excellent and creatively brilliant beyond words, but it doesn’t have to be – that is NOT the objective of a first draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start working with an outline for your books and steadily IMPROVE your outline as you refine your style. If you want, try starting with a 10-chapter outline format … make yours better than this; this can be copied to be your starting point for an extra extra-shitty first draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;preface&quot;&gt;Preface&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write this AFTER the entire book is in final form. Nobody will probably read this … except for those who really want to understand the book, understand your motivations, doubts, thought processes … AND your view from the mountain top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;grand-introduction&quot;&gt;Grand Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, you will write this AFTER the other chapters are pretty close to being in final form, but don’t get carried away with your excitement about different details in subsequent chapters.  Start off by remembering your aim to write an INSANELY useful book for your reader … introduce the book in the context of the customer NEED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-started-reading-lists-interviews-acquiring-expertise-understand-ultimate-root-cause&quot;&gt;Getting Started, Reading Lists, Interviews, Acquiring Expertise, Understand Ultimate Root Cause&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEFORE anyone starts doing anything, they really have to LEARN a lot the lay of the land … they will have to LEARN how to think, what keywords to use, what the basic jargon is – they need a very basic road map … they need to be addressed as independent thinkers who are developing their own program of research and study … it’s NOT about mastery, that with comes with time and practice … this is about giving some clues about where the bodies are buried so that people can get enough background to be dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;prioritization-risk-management-smart-goal-setting&quot;&gt;Prioritization, Risk Management, SMART Goal Setting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, doing interesting things is going to be dangerous, tricky, uncharted and HARD … that is what life is for human beings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understand-the-problem-in-order-efficiently-brainstorm-a-pdca-plan-for-bests-practices-and-discipline-for-rapidly-achieving-a-better-awareness-of-the-solution-space&quot;&gt;Understand the problem in order efficiently brainstorm a PDCA Plan for bests practices and discipline for rapidly achieving a better awareness of the solution space&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost every problem has been solved before; almost everything has been invented before.  Since an analogous solution has been invented for a problem with analogous circumstances, before you waste a lot of time throwing mud at the wall to see what sticks, consider the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.triz40.com/aff_Principles_TRIZ.php&quot;&gt;40 principles of TRIZ&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://triz-journal.com/contradiction-matrix-40-principles-innovative-problem-solving/&quot;&gt;TRIZ contradiction matrix&lt;/a&gt; to guide your search for the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;designed-experiments-efficiently-in-a-knowledgable-manner&quot;&gt;Designed experiments efficiently in a knowledgable manner&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do NOT experiment for the point of experimenting or demonstrating your “skill” as a data scientist or some sort of precocious idiot who understands a trick or two using statistical inference.  Do not waste time experimenting to prove Ohm’s Law or other experiments that are tantamount to reinventing the wheel. Use orthogonal arrays and similar methods that provide the most information in the shortest time possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;push-past-the-point-of-comfort-but-within-a-zone-of-comparative-strength-not-to-the-breaking-point--develop-a-practical-and-safe-3-step-plan-for-eustress-leading-to-hormesis&quot;&gt;Push past the point of comfort, but within a zone of comparative strength not to the breaking point – develop a practical and safe 3-step plan for eustress leading to hormesis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5324220/&quot;&gt;press-pulse strategies&lt;/a&gt; to make your immune system’s strengths comparatively stronger to fight or even eliminate disease or cancer. According to the paleobiologists, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/40663783_Press-pulse_A_general_theory_of_mass_extinction&quot;&gt;Arens and West (2008)&lt;/a&gt;, the simultaneous occurrence of “Press-Pulse” disturbances were responsible for the extinction of many populations in prior evolutionary epochs. A “press” disturbance or chronic environmental stress on all organisms in an ecological community, promoted extinction through habitat loss, reduced reproduction, and restriction of range and resources. Press disturbances force new biological equilibrium by making previously important species non-viable. The new fittest species could eliminate the weakest species. In contrast to the press disturbances, “pulse” disturbances or acute events that disrupted biological communities to produce high mortality in the immediate aftermath of the pulse disturbance. Since survival of some species could occur following either a press or pulse disturbance, but when both the press and the pulse disturbances coincided the mass extinction of previously important species was more likely. The press-pulse concept can be adopted as a therapeutic strategy for the possible elimination of disease or martial arts or warfare … and it is completely unnecessary to limit the attacks on the disease or enemy to only two dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;master-the-first-step-do-at-least-25-pdca-cycles&quot;&gt;Master the first step, do at least 25 PDCA cycles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point it boils down to work or applied diligence in the agile, continuous delivery of better and better awareness of the solution space … twenty-five Plan-Do-Check-Act cycles rapidly improves your familiarity with the problem and your hunt for the optimal solution, HOWEVER twenty-five PDCA cycles is ONLY about laying the foundation or preparing for a steeper, tougher, harder climb. The first step is about making sure that you are ready AND making sure that the view will be worth the climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;re-strategize-the-second-step-then-master-that-step-with-25-more-pdca-cycles&quot;&gt;Re-Strategize the second step, then master that step with 25 more PDCA cycles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first step, the going was tedious. In the second step, the going gets really tough and downright uncomfortable … it still involves using at least twenty-five Plan-Do-Check-Act cycles, but in this step, expect significant disappointments, doubts, abandonment by “fair weather” supporters, lack of resources and funding … we all know that it is “darkest before the dawn,” but it is downright demoralizing knowing this, knowing the time and that dawn is still hours away, you’re all alone in the bitter cold with no resources and there is serious doubt about whether you can make it to dawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;from-basecamp-for-the-final-ascent-strategize-the-third-step-and-master-it&quot;&gt;From “basecamp” for the final ascent, strategize the third step and master it.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the summit is in view … respect your efforts, fulfill your plan, close the deal, do not be dissuaded from your patient and diligent ATTACK!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;after-mastering-the-third-step-plan-to-sustain-your-gains-as-you-grow-in-other-realms&quot;&gt;After mastering the third step, plan to SUSTAIN your gains as you GROW in other realms.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what! How are you going to use your gains in order to SUSTAIN your pursuit of other challenges?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;appendices-glossaries-cheat-sheets-workbooks-checklists&quot;&gt;Appendices, Glossaries, Cheat Sheets, Workbooks, Checklists&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scalia on Making Your Case&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohno on LEAN Thinking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2015/08/15/Amazon-Template.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2015/08/15/Amazon-Template.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
