<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns Tech Blawg</title>
    <description>This is my blog about version-controlled social production of open source technologies, cultures and revolutions ... and my interconnections to larger, more awesome interconnections in the universe ... https://xkcd.com/1579/</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:28:25 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:28:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design For Immunity</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the GOAL of the Design for Immunity project? We might not think about it as much as we should, but ALL of us basically want to boost our immune system.  We all want to be healthier tomorrow than we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is serious about health [and strengthening immunity against all kinds of attacks] knows that there’s a LOT to think about … almost TOO MUCH … so should think about the scope of the project or about what we might focus on FIRST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a SPECIFIC example … to prove the concept in a practical manner that demonstrates how one might incorporate particular interests, I will be look in at how I can learn about designing, building and continuously improving an edible foodscape on small amount of land that house sits on.  This foodscape will need to provides me with all kinds of antioxidants and phytochemicals and raw foods that I not only LIKE, but also are especially conductive to rebuilding my immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a starting point, for getting a general idea of the “lay of the land” for this project, I will attempt curate an AWESOME annotated reading list that looks at things like the types of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancertutor.com/mirror_lymphoma/&quot;&gt;nutritional programs recommended for those undergoing radiation or chemotherapy or other particular toxic treatments for cancer&lt;/a&gt; … but the background research, derived from curating and annotating a reading list is ONLY for making informed choices about this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MOST important informed choice that I can make about the SCOPE of this particular immunity project is deciding the general strategy that I will use for attacking the opportunity … I will refer to my Design For Immunity approach as a meta-immunity approach … it will be about building the informational infrastructure for continually advancing the PRACTICAL, PERSONAL goal of improving my level of immunity.  To accomplish this, &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; … I recognize the NEED to reach out, build upon what others have done … &lt;em&gt;WE&lt;/em&gt; will be designing a set of cloneable, forkable, open source repositories to construct a dynamic, continuously updatable system that helps people get information and data, learn on their own, build a lifestyle that takes responsibility for caring for ones environment in a way that strengthens immune systems and generally builds health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really about education … data APIs, repositories, MOOCs, JUPYTER notebooks, Electron driven messaging like Slack, online conferences [with LIVEstreamed video and more-or-less immediate interaction]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;analytics&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, people will stop playing defense and just being spooked by the #JustWorryAboutIt passive strategies used by conventional healthcare systems … when get serious about [re]building immunity / fitness / productivity, we will measure, compare and quantitatively optimize. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercatus.org/hoap&quot;&gt;#InsuranceAintHealth&lt;/a&gt; #DontGetSick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;improvement&quot;&gt;Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercatus.org/hoap&quot;&gt;HOAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;genome-wide-association-studies&quot;&gt;Genome Wide Association Studies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/immunity,/against/disease,/evidence/based/health,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/11/19/Design-Against-Disease.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/immunity,/against/disease,/evidence/based/health,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/11/19/Design-Against-Disease.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>evergreen,</category>
        
        <category>DMAIC,</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>For</category>
        
        <category>Immunity,</category>
        
        <category>Against</category>
        
        <category>Disease,</category>
        
        <category>evidence</category>
        
        <category>based</category>
        
        <category>health,</category>
        
        <category>Arm</category>
        
        <category>Thy</category>
        
        <category>Neighbor</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Against Crime</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the entrant’s into &lt;a href=&quot;http://NIJ.gov/MappingChallenge&quot;&gt;mapping challenge&lt;/a&gt; sponsored by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://NIJ.gov&quot;&gt;Natl Institute of Justice&lt;/a&gt; will probably aim their approach to data science prediction and forecasting at mapping BAD OUTCOMES … and there is a lot to be said for place-based crime forecasting algorithms that look at neighborhoods at [future] risk. Okay, crime is interesting enough … and it is certainly very necessary to get serious about law enforcement and neighborhood watch programs and others ways to deal better with crime, BUT …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… what if instead of playing defense [against something negative like crime], we went on offense and started trying to put POSITIVE points on the board for the GOOD changes that we might be able to effect.  What if we looked instead at the predictors that lead to neighborhoods that DO NOT MAKE the news … is it possible for to change our our thinking to AVOID focusing on the sensationalism and crisis that usually follows things like crime?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it isn’t as simple as just applying a 180 degree reverse policy … we cannot really do the same data analytics on good behaviors as we do on reported data for criminal convictions.  Happiness analytics are much more suspect than crime analytics … since we don’t have numbers on people or communities &lt;em&gt;convicted&lt;/em&gt; of being happy, normal, successful or different things that are the opposite of crime, those who want to engage in happiness analytics must &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; more with the use of imperfect inferential statistical methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONE way of looking at good behavior is how productive [and generally higher-earning] behavior gets monetized into something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/c/house-prices-advanced-regression-techniques&quot;&gt;strong housing prices&lt;/a&gt;. We all know some things about housing already – for example, we know that the age of the something like carpet or even a furnace is going to be orders of magnitude less important than location or proximity to a good school or other community amenities.  AFTER we have prepared our data set [by eliminating obvious outliers in the data], we could BEGIN our exploratory analysis by looking at the different housing districts by using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_forest&quot;&gt;random forest model&lt;/a&gt; in order to assure that we are comparing basically similar neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;analytics&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why just look at Ames … let’s look at ALL real estate in Iowa.  Or the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;improvement&quot;&gt;Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design your COMMUNITY for Maintainability … and the maintainability of better neighbors, better neighborhoods, better public utilities, better civic projects … is important as a [derived] value because maintainability means thinking about other people. That includes the differing valid motives, aptitudes, stage of education and levels of capabilities of OTHER developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about building an social architecture or &lt;em&gt;culturescape&lt;/em&gt; that engenders people in the future [after you are gone] to go about maintaining their ability to be creative, productive, independent and free to protect themselves and advance their just causes [without hurting other people]. Of course, it is NECESSARY that choices about maintainability are voluntary – a good argument with a useful tool should be sufficient to convince most people to go along with a policy – coercion, force and mandates are unnecessary. Controlling others or taking away the independence of others is one of the very most immoral things that anyone can do. Open source code and data are part of this – so are distributed information, defense and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/maintainability,/against/crime,/happiness/analytics,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/10/24/Design-Against-Crime.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/maintainability,/against/crime,/happiness/analytics,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/10/24/Design-Against-Crime.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>evergreen,</category>
        
        <category>DMAIC,</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>For</category>
        
        <category>Maintainability,</category>
        
        <category>Against</category>
        
        <category>Crime,</category>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        <category>analytics,</category>
        
        <category>Arm</category>
        
        <category>Thy</category>
        
        <category>Neighbor</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design for Maintainability</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE reason that I am interested in open source is flexibility and extensibility [to a degree] but mostly my interest is about MAINTAINABILITY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintainability does not just spontaneously happen.  Not all that long ago, &lt;strong&gt;it used to be&lt;/strong&gt; [and in some cases still is] true that much, if not most, of the Javascript code hacked together by &lt;em&gt;developers&lt;/em&gt; worldwide is pretty much unmaintainable &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;junk.js&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; … this is not a critique of Javascript or ECMAscript language itself; it is a critique of the sloppy practices that are possible.  Javascript [and simply trusting the Javascript of others or enabling Javascript in the &lt;em&gt;sandbox&lt;/em&gt; represented the web browser] makes lots of crappy, error-prone, spammy and even downright malevolent code possible … but the &lt;em&gt;beauty&lt;/em&gt; [and its potential for sheer evil] of Javascript lies in the combination of ubiquity and expedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it might &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt; but maintenance of the code tends to be a matter of the original developer(s) &lt;em&gt;keeping their heads in the game&lt;/em&gt; and staying engaged to remember how the thing was supposed to work and where the technical debt &lt;em&gt;anti-treasure&lt;/em&gt; or where the treasure troves of dangerous anti-patterns and [intentionally-bad] virus-enabling &lt;em&gt;easter eggs&lt;/em&gt; are buried … in other words, unmaintainable code might expediently &lt;em&gt;get the job done&lt;/em&gt;, but it cannot serve as a foundation.  It definitely should not be something that is built upon, replicated, cloned, widely-distributed … ESPECIALLY when the code includes &lt;em&gt;easter eggs&lt;/em&gt; exploitable weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately the strength of the open source ecosystem is that community includes plenty of really solid computer scientist who understand the reason for producing automate-able tools that serve as antidotes to the creation of new bad Javascript … these professionals in the open source community have recognized that Javascript’s weaknesses are not just a matter of style [as is the case with written documents] but the pervasiveness of bad code replicates even sloppier code – so better practices must be STRONGLY encouraged with tools that do the heavy lifting.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sorrycc/awesome-javascript&quot;&gt;AWESOME transpilers, linters, build tools, pattern repositories for Javascript&lt;/a&gt; and more are constantly being developed, improved and enhanced in the [not always so informal] competition to improve the code of developers around you … but there’s still no substitute for humans who constantly think about maintainability and OTHER USERS … just as there is no substitute for being skeptical of the &lt;em&gt;MAGIC&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;candy&lt;/em&gt; that is distributed based on an intensely widely-used language like Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Guidelines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Placeholder for additional DFM material – tbd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Epilogue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintainability is important as a [derived] value because maintainability means thinking about other people. That includes the differing valid motives, aptitudes, stage of education and levels of capabilities of OTHER developers. It is all about maintaining their ability to be creative, productive, independent and free to protect themselves and advance their just causes [without hurting other people]. Of course, it is NECESSARY that choices about maintainability are voluntary – a good argument with a useful tool should be sufficient to convince most people to go along with a policy – coercion, force and mandates are unnecessary. Controlling others or taking away the independence of others is one of the very most immoral things that anyone can do. Open source code and data are part of this – so are distributed information, defense and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/evergreen,/dfx,/design/for/maintainability/2016/10/18/Design-For-Maintainability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/evergreen,/dfx,/design/for/maintainability/2016/10/18/Design-For-Maintainability.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>evergreen,</category>
        
        <category>Dfx,</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>for</category>
        
        <category>Maintainability</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrity Is Impossible To Achieve Through Imitation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Journalists might &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2015-paul-ford-what-is-code/&quot;&gt;think they know what code is&lt;/a&gt;, but I do not know if journalists are capable of really understanding what code is … or what makes serious software developers or data scientists tick … journalists necessarily reduce the world to what they can understand well enough to write about and that is a very serious limitation on what Reality really is. If you want to understand what code is, you need to emigrate to the world of code and live in it, you cannot understand code by reading what journalists write about it … at best, you can only understand what journalists think about something … the function of media and journalism is not so much to inform as it is to condition the herd of pliant bovines who look to others for their opinions and their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do know is that that if you are going to follow the herd, you’re going to eat a lot of dust and feel terrified a lot of time for no good reason whatsoever … because terrorizing or titillating an audience sells [electronic] papers and there’s an enormous amount of competition in this world to stand out in terrorism or titillation, so the herd gets conditioned. There are herds of people intent on following Trump, following the #NeverTrump movement, following Hillary … all move in lock step with one another and have a variety of ways of whipping other members of the herd into delusional frenzies.  Human beings are much more stupid when they are in herds … if you believe that there is even a RISK of your being in a herd, you really need to change and be your own person. If YOU don’t look out for your integrity, no one else will … there is nothing wrong with being gregarious, outgoing and friendly … there are many benefits to things like voluntary standards and respecting the beliefs, customs, conventions and social norms others … we can certainly learn from others, but &lt;strong&gt;integrity is impossible to achieve through imitation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot fathom why the herd imagines that Presidential elections matter … the population of people that vote for a President matters [because we all must conduct our lives and businesses with those people], but the actual election does not matter.  With the exception of Ronald Reagan [but only, because he was my Commander-In-Chief in 1981-1983, when I was a Federal agent, still deluded by the prospects of a career in public service and his policies thus inordinately, pathologically affected me] no President has actually mattered in terms of how I conduct my life.  I don’t expect that the next one will matter either; I almost want to be proven wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The herd definitely WANTS Presidential elections to matter … because the herd WANTS to be led … the herd desperately needs to find a leader it can believe it, a leader with integrity … because no one in the herd can lead or think for themselves, no one in the herd has a shred of integrity – they have demonstrated time and again that they do not know integrity when integrity slaps them in the face. The want their integrity to go after someone else … they want a “leader” who will blame &lt;em&gt;the other&lt;/em&gt;, the immigrant, the jew, the nigger, the irredeemable, deplorable misogynist. The herd cannot and does not want to know.  The herd cannot and does not want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why the herd imagines that Presidential elections matter … the herd cannot adapt, the herd NEEDS a President who will restrict the ability of citizens to be informed, the herd NEEDS a President who will restrict the ability of citizens to defend themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be part of the herd; you can choose to be part of the minority of people who can think for themselves and defend themselves and therefore are not afraid those who share information … including information on how to produce weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/integrity/2016/10/12/Priorities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/integrity/2016/10/12/Priorities.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>integrity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Knowledge Prospecting and Data-Intensive Economies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is said that travel helps one to find new perspectives, prospect for new interests, meet new friends … and although I believe that could not be more true, I also believe that traveling for the sake of traveling, or crossing places visited off some sort of bucket list, is mostly a non-value-added activity that involves shipping a live body around the planet. Of course, we all know that there ARE interactions and experiences that you simply cannot have in a virtual realm, but the fact of the matter is that information, communication and VR technologies are raising the level of what can be experienced virtually, while the expenses, difficulties and uncertainties of travel are basically unchanged. When the relative costs change, it is necessary to reallocate resources … and this applies just as much to the area of knowledge prospecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For SOME, this means that they can accomplish more in less time … affording MORE time for travel – but for people like me, it means that I can accomplish more [knowledge prospecting] in less time AND because of that I can engage in more pure knowledge prospecting, [scientific] content consumption, data analysis AND I can &lt;strong&gt;do more walking, biking, and GARDENING outdoors&lt;/strong&gt; rather than being cooped up in car, plane or hotel room. In essence, writing code, analyzing data and working remotely, as well as being more engaged in more relationships FROM A DISTANCE allows me to spend more time time getting dirt under my fingernails as I have more time for serious investigation of soil ecosystems and using/developing laboratory tools things like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nanoporetech.com/applications/metagenomics&quot;&gt;GWAS metagenomics and nanopore DNA sequencing technology&lt;/a&gt; in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for me to do this, it is still very much necessary for me to travel in a virtual sense … to learn new skills for communication with others … and, beyond that, to extend and develop new tools for traveling even further … because the revolution in the ability to prospect for knowledge in a virtual fashion is only just beginning … it will change as more and more people adapt and the network effects create new opportunities … in the same way, that personal computers … then client-server networked computers … and the internet and world wide web … and social media, mobile and wireless technologies have changed how people prospect for information and begin to travel virtually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no different than cooking or firing a kiln with fire … or floating or rolling a log then building boats and things that use wheels … or finding that keeping an edge on sharp tools improves with hard metals … or domesticating and breeding plants and animals …  it will be always be necessary for humans to pick up knowledge in realms where they have none … developing and extending new tools makes it possible to explore new realms of knowledge which require the development and extension of new tools … chickens » eggs  »  omelettes and other recipes  »  nutrition and health  »  scientific methods and innovation  » data-intensive economies and extensible open source DevOps … the source of code/technology has to be written for OTHER developers who ultimately will extend the paradigm AND also to accomplish the [OBVIOUS] immediate specific goal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/problem/solving,/extensibility/2016/10/08/Prospecting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/problem/solving,/extensibility/2016/10/08/Prospecting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>problem</category>
        
        <category>solving,</category>
        
        <category>extensibility</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fighting Fires</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You will see all kinds of articles that … instead of inspiring people to work with their communities, neighbors and friends to solve problems … call for people to look to a bigger role for government (e.g. “There oughta be a law to …”).  For example, you might see headlines that say something like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/murders-rose-at-their-fastest-pace-in-a-quarter-century-last-year/&quot;&gt;Murders Rose At Their Fastest Pace In A Quarter Century Last Year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s PARTIALLY true, but it is grossly misleading … murders did NOT increase EVERYWHERE; murders did not increase in MOST jurisdictions where MOST Americans live.  The AVERAGE murder rate for America increased because it increased DRAMATICALLY in SOME jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at the data, we can test certain hypotheses and the data do provide answers … but those answers raise new questions.  That is exactly what getting to root cause is all about.  When the data furnishes an answer, we ordinarily have to ask, &lt;em&gt;“But, WHY did that happen?”&lt;/em&gt;  In fact, the need to asks several levels of WHY is not the exception, it is THE RULE. Experience teaches us that for any particular problem, it is necessary to use data AND to ask &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys&quot;&gt;five levels of WHY&lt;/a&gt; … beyond just drilling down to get simplistic answers, it is necessary to understand the complex cause-and-effect nature of the problem, i.e. we cannot quit solving the problem until we have populated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ishikawa_diagram&quot;&gt;full Ishikawa fishbone diagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In jurisdictions with smaller governments, murders and crimes have decreased … murders and all other crimes have certainly decreased in rather dramatic fashion in those towns/cities/rural areas that have VOLUNTEER fire departments. Crime increases [in some jurisdictions] where people trust and depend upon their governments more and instead of being involved, just feel entitled to government providing for them. It’s NOT a Democratic or Republican thing; it’s NOT an income or poverty thing, even though we ALL know that the ultra-rich always have hired thugs to take care of their things in their sterile, locked-down, &lt;em&gt;lifeless&lt;/em&gt; RICH &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;compounds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – driving down crime for REAL living human beings is primarily about how INVOLVED or ENGAGED people are in their communities, ie do citizens tolerate the &lt;strong&gt;persistence&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;em&gt;broken windows&lt;/em&gt; in their community [because &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; windows get broken everywhere that windows are] OR do they tend to do something about solving community problems together?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to drill down, to REALLY look at the data to see EXACTLY where the breakdown is happening – things are NOT breaking down everywhere. According to NYU Law School’s Brennan Center for Justice, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brennancenter.org/publication/crime-2016-preliminary-analysis&quot;&gt;murder rate in cities is up 13% in 2016&lt;/a&gt; … which is an alarming start of [what hopefully is NOT] a pattern of a double-digit increase on top of another double-digit increase … since murders in the U.S. jumped by 10.8% in 2015, according to FBI data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, there is a LOT of good news in crime data – GENERALLY speaking, in most jurisdictions, crime has been really low and been falling even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t live in an area where crime is falling … well … you and your community are doing it wrong … and the data prove that you are doing it wrong.  If you don’t like the conclusion, go argue with the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the FBI recorded violent crime narrowly falling, by 0.2%. In 2015, the number of violent crimes rose 3.9% and the number of property crimes dropped 2.6% … while crime is dropping in much of the country, and even in some urban environments … but in 44 of the 65 largest police agencies in 2015, the murder rate increased. There are some cities, like Baltimore, DC, Louisville, Chicago, St. Louis, Omaha, Houston and LA where things are seriously screwed-up … compared to the rest of the country, those 44 urban police jurisdictions are bad enough by themselves to significantly raise the murder rates on average for the ENTIRE country … in spite of decreases in MOST of the nation.  It is interesting that the very worst, i.e. Chicago [labeled by some as an “outlier”] are enough to counter the trend of the rest of the nation … and it will get worse before it gets better because there are some “community organizers” out there who are NOT really providing any leadership, but instead are blaming the police and failing to look at the root cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to find the ROOT CAUSE for what is driving the crime increase in some urban hell-holes, here’s a HINT … it AIN’T the police doing the killing … or looting the Walmarts after a riot … or exploiting the unrest and riots for political gain by calling for more protests and riots, ie protests and riots are NOT going to help with what is primarily a self-inflicted problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guess is that it’s like fighting fire … which is MOSTLY about recognizing fire hazards, doing things to DE-ESCALATE the hazard level and making sure that the people you hang around with are also not idiots when it comes to escalation of risk … idiots who play with fire must not be defended and certainly should not be celebrated [or even mourned] when the idiots die in a fire they started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fighting fire is MOSTLY about behaviors … but fire does happen, so fire extinguishers matter … the problem with fires is much less where fire extinguishers are ubiquitous and EVERYONE takes ownership when it comes to preventing fires and calling out idiotic behavior that might lead to fire.  Sometimes things do happen – that’s why EVERYONE has know exactly where several different fire extinguishing devices, water, blankets are and EVERYONE knows how to help put out a fire because they had hands-on training using one within the last year … in other words, if you live in a city with lots of immature, irresponsible, unsupervised uber-entitled children [regardless of what age they are] are running around with gas cans and fire-starting kits expecting the adults in fire departments to put out the fires, your city is going to BURN DOWN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to situations where things are engulfed in flame and BURNING DOWN … even in relatively small fires … another part of fighting fire is about EXIT.  That means there is no good that comes from be being the stupid amateur hero, puts on his superhero cape and CONFRONTS the fire that is already out-of-control.  In other words, back away from the blaze, call in the professionals and do NOT complicate the problem the professionals have to solve by becoming part of the situation.  Do NOT be a hero unless you are a TRAINED PROFESSIONAL who is PAID to develop all of the skills necessary to be a hero, ie support your Fire Dept folks, support your police.  The thing to do with an out-of-control fire is to GET AWAY and let the professionals decide what to do … don’t be too surprised if they decide to let the fire burn what it’s going to burn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/crime,/root/cause/analysis/2016/09/28/Fighting-Fires.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/crime,/root/cause/analysis/2016/09/28/Fighting-Fires.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>crime,</category>
        
        <category>root</category>
        
        <category>cause</category>
        
        <category>analysis</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are the most important technologies for accelerated learning?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe the most important thing is encouragement and nudging people to be TOUGH enough to fit in, to naturalize, assimilate, adapt enough to thrive and not only become native but to produce something of importance or beauty for others in the ecosystem, like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/y/2rpqQTs&quot;&gt;muscari armeniacum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to &lt;em&gt;become native&lt;/em&gt; and then transcend that by producing things of real value?  It is probably a matter of LOVE, commitment and extreme ownership – that means really &lt;em&gt;OWNING&lt;/em&gt; every problem (ie opportunity) that other people run away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;at your own pace&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;on your own&lt;/em&gt; is NEVER really a matter of &lt;em&gt;going it entirely alone&lt;/em&gt; … the best way to really learn or even master something is to teach it to someone else … there are ways to apply the benefits of exposure and network effects, to encourage meaningful social interaction, to elicit others to be involved in progress, to participate in the code code graph, to not just participate but to take on the effort as their own, to hack it, to extend it for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me think about applying the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FreeCodeCamp/FreeCodeCamp&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; method to the natural HARD sciences … it goes beyond mere coding, but coding is extremely important for building tools that explore relationships … like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neo4j.com/use-cases/real-time-recommendation-engine/&quot;&gt;graph databases&lt;/a&gt; and building a tool to find shared knowledge connections or what might be described as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ILjTikVhT9k&quot;&gt;topical interest recommendation engine&lt;/a&gt; … for example, what kinds of understanding can we bring together to give us new frontiers to explore in understanding an aspect of soil ecosystem health and nutritional pathways … of course, understanding informs the approach we use in looking for data … sometimes we simply need to gather a lot more data now, perhaps we can get lots of macro photos (although macro photos are important and there are better technologies for micro and even nano level photography), but also we also think about things like sequential or time-lapse longitudinal panel data gathering, but we can also explore other tools like DNA chips for nutritional genomics of different species in different ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should think about how superheros like us build and use tools … and then use those tools to build and use better tools … and how the incremental daily improvement might not seem all that significant, but when we look back we see how incredibly much things have CHANGED in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lyDLAutA88s&quot;&gt;the last 20 years of building tools to munge data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning,/acceleration/2016/09/24/Evolutionary-Advance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning,/acceleration/2016/09/24/Evolutionary-Advance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning,</category>
        
        <category>acceleration</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WHY won&#39;t updates to GitHub pages load immediately [or with the same latency]?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of LITTLE … and some times, not so little … things that impact your workflow on GitHub … and it’s up to YOU to stay engaged, to have a degree of situational awareness … perhaps patiences … perhaps an understanding of what you need to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgot about what you might believe … you simply are NOT &lt;strong&gt;entitled&lt;/strong&gt; to help from anyone else … including even GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now … the folks at GitHub probably want to help you, but there might be impediments to IMMEDIATELY serving you … maybe you haven’t phrased your question intelligently or in a manner that fits their jargon and linguistic realm … maybe there are problems with people who supply services to them; maybe they have their own glitches or bugs or issues … there are all kinds of reasons why the latency of their service might vary.  It’s not a perfect world.  And, even though we probably should not FIRST suspect malicious intent, since it’s so much more likely that OTHER things are driving actions, there ARE indeed very malevolent actors out there – not just hackers who want to take down a service like Github for their own idiotic purposes, but maybe’s it WORSE … like some EVIL national security agency of a totalitarian regime of thugs might be forcing Github to supply data or obstruct free speech.  We have reasons for why we should LOVE Github, but … even if their intentions are better, purer, smarter than anyone else’s … you simply are NOT &lt;strong&gt;entitled&lt;/strong&gt; to expect IMMEDIATE help from anyone else … including GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIRST thing to look at is your own [lack of CURRENT] knowledge about your own set-up … for example … recently, I was working on a blog with the same Atom Editor and GitHub Desktop tools I’ve come to know and love … and use somewhat successfully [for my modest purposes] … using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as a SIMPLE blog-aware static &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/github-pages/&quot;&gt;GH pages&lt;/a&gt; site generator on my laptop … good ol’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000&quot;&gt;127.0.0.1:4000&lt;/a&gt; looked as current and good [ie what I expected to see] as ever … there had been no error messages from the editor or desktop app … I had up to date version of each … the updated pages were in Github’s repo and I could see them on Github’s website … but Github was not loading my updated pages for some reason!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO IT WAS TIME FOR ME TO RELAX and spend a couple minutes RELEARNING SOME STUFF … I had used the Github pages MAGIC and &lt;em&gt;it just worked&lt;/em&gt; … like MAGIC … I didn’t need to know AND I didn’t know some key portions of the magic … I had trusted Github TOO MUCH … I know better … you cannot trust ANYONE, even people who are on your side and do not want to deliberate screw up your workflow … that includes even Github … most importantly YOU CANNOT PLACE ALL OF YOUR FAITH MAGIC YOU DON’T UNDERSTAND … if you’re going to rely on magic, at least build in some redundancies, just in case, things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/configuring-a-publishing-source-for-github-pages/&quot;&gt;how GitHub serve pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2228-simpler-github-pages-publishing&quot;&gt;how they have recently updated it do it NOW&lt;/a&gt; don’t perform as you think they will, when you need a service to perform for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I didn’t need to change or fix anything … it was JUST an issue of LATENCY … for some reason, GitHub was not IMMEDIATELY updating the blogs it hosts as rapidly as it usually does. So … yeah … I did not learn as much about Git and GitHub behind-the-scenes internal magic as I &lt;em&gt;should have&lt;/em&gt; learned … but the search and the serendipitous things that I did learn made it ALL WORTHWHILE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that if you rely upon Github … and you probably should rely on GitHub … and the larger GitHub community … at least, you should &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; rely on them and even if you are a competitor of them, you should pay attention because Github is pretty good at what they do, especially the &lt;em&gt;network effects&lt;/em&gt; stuff … even for things that are not mission-critical for &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; mission, but if your mission involves developing software, content, data science or building any form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/awesome&quot;&gt;AWESOME&lt;/a&gt; knowledge, the fully network-effected social distributed version control that Github does is critical for your level of situational awareness … you really NEED to be reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog&quot;&gt;GitHub blog&lt;/a&gt;, following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/github&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/GitHubGuides&quot;&gt;Github Guides&lt;/a&gt; channels on YouTube and maybe even attending and definitely paying attention to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://githubuniverse.com/program/&quot;&gt;program&lt;/a&gt; of topics and speakers &lt;a href=&quot;http://githubuniverse.com/&quot;&gt;at GitHub conferences&lt;/a&gt; … you really should have an awareness of &lt;a href=&quot;https://octoverse.github.com/&quot;&gt;what is going on at GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and in the companies involved in providing distributed version control like [Git] … after all, the whole toolchain and different services that you rely on for source control are kind of a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/relearning,/trust/2016/09/21/The-Tao-of-Github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/relearning,/trust/2016/09/21/The-Tao-of-Github.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>relearning,</category>
        
        <category>trust</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prove your words by your deeds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are nothing more than imperfectly expressed desires. For thousands of years, humans have known action speak louder. Many people use words in order to enlist others, makes sales, get opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want opportunities … then USE the mountain of opportunities you already have.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of options and opportunities is always going to be pretty damned limited for people who think first in getting help from others and do not develop their abilities to think in terms of what they can work on, what they can make better, what they can use in order to &lt;em&gt;advance the ball.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look ONLY at what you can do without begging for help from others and then narrow your focus to what is the very highest and very best use of your time among those options … it will tend to exceptionally true that the very best opportunities one has just do not look especially inviting or compelling.  Opportunity is usually about the thing that eliminates a constraint for a lot of people or really helps the most people in the biggest way, especially when they do not understand that YOU are the one helping them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still highly advantageous to seek anonymity rather than get taken in by fame or adoration, power or wealth … fame, adoration, power or wealth ALWAYS attract the cocksuckers, ie the people who want to perform small services in order to “pick up the crumbs” and hopefully get opportunity &lt;em&gt;on the cheap&lt;/em&gt;.  There are plenty of people who enjoy having their cock sucked and relentlessly pursue fame, adoration, power and wealth … there are others, who enjoy getting into dick-measuring contests to compare stories or resumes or combat medals.  That is unfortunate – but it is a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the FEW who are not just expedient whores, it is possible to see the emptiness of those pursuits or how desire for fame, adoration, power and wealth leads to a state of permanent neediness and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/culture,/history,/seneca/2016/09/20/The-Tao-of-Desire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/culture,/history,/seneca/2016/09/20/The-Tao-of-Desire.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Culture,</category>
        
        <category>History,</category>
        
        <category>Seneca</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tolerance for slavery is an indicator of cultural weakness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If people want their culture to be STRONGER (ie, respect for rights, prosperity and distribution of wealth, creative people in vibrant yet stable communities, diverse choices in a variety of things), they must renounce the types of things that make a culture WEAK, like all forms slavery. The mainstream in Saudi Arabia refuses to do this; accordingly, a nation like Saudi Arabia has a weak culture. People will go there because they HAVE to [for work]; they will not go there to enjoy the culture. This sort of renunciation of repugnant cultural practices like slavey might seem obvious, but it is perhaps not so obvious that islamophilic multiculuralists are doing no favors for the people who must live in a sub-standard culture by refusing to be critical of bad practices, bad religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most [if not all] islamophiles tend to be deliberately, aggressively, WILLFULLY naive about how something like the &lt;em&gt;religion of submission&lt;/em&gt; but they cannot ignore how a culture that drives and thrives upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YnJfR70n6k0&quot;&gt;slavery&lt;/a&gt;.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Wln6lNTxVpY?t=37m40s&quot;&gt;entitled morons out there who will unabashedly and gladly enslave others&lt;/a&gt; in order to subsidize the grossly inefficient academic industry in America in order to provide higher education for everyone because they claim that higher education is the key to opportunity. They completely fail to realize that a nation FREE of slavery in all its forms, including the tax and regulatory burdens of grossly inefficient state and federal bureaucracies, is THE key to opportunity. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Wln6lNTxVpY?t=38m1s&quot;&gt;Thomas Sowell is absolutely right about &lt;strong&gt;opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; … all of us in America have had ample &lt;em&gt;opportunities&lt;/em&gt; to become the next &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LAr6oAKieHk&quot;&gt;Michael Jordan&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/dou3aSZmEg0?list=PLElrASo3VHBxt9zg3oRoKSqmyiCHct4Ai&quot;&gt;Miles Davis&lt;/a&gt; … but ONLY Michael Jordan and Miles Davis WORKED and PERSEVERED &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michaeldpollock.com/michael-jordan-on-failure-and-perseverance/&quot;&gt;to overcome their own fears, doubts and failures&lt;/a&gt; or when success looked especially FAR from being certain (eg being and then WORKED and PERSEVERED even more after it appeared that success was possible … even if we want to IMAGINE that our talent constrains us … even though we more than enough examples to PROVE that talent, aptitude or any physical attribute [including appearance] is NOT the barrier that most humans want to believe … we must know that we have had more than sufficient opportunities to WORK and PRACTICE and hone what skills we do have to be able to reach what most regard as impossible goals … ALL people in America HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY to play on a level where we can interact with supremely-talented masters who have ALSO worked hard in order to take advantage of the opportunities offered to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;higher-education-is-not-the-key-to-opportunity&quot;&gt;Higher education IS NOT the key to opportunity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KEY to opportunity is using what opportunities you have to the very fullest as you await being showered with the opportunities that surreptitiously always accrue to those who have a proven history of using the opportunities that they have had.  &lt;em&gt;If you want opportunities … then USE the mountain of opportunities you already have.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/culture,/history,/slavery/2016/09/15/Cultural-Weakness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/culture,/history,/slavery/2016/09/15/Cultural-Weakness.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Culture,</category>
        
        <category>History,</category>
        
        <category>Slavery</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
