<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns Tech Blawg</title>
    <description>This is my blog about version-controlled social production of open source technologies, cultures and revolutions ... and my interconnections to larger, more awesome interconnections in the universe ... https://xkcd.com/1579/</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 16:27:06 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 16:27:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fasting In Practice, Fasting As A Metaphor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For complicated reasons, we have allowed ourselves to be lied to about fasting … it’s not [entirely or exactly pure] malevolence or any sort of conspiracy to keep information from us – but it doesn’t really matter – we have chosen to imagine that fasting is more incredibly dangerous than it can possibly be.  We basically wanted to believe the myth that fasting or any form of self-induced beneficial stress or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eustress&quot;&gt;eustress&lt;/a&gt; to bring on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hormesis&quot;&gt;hormesis&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yerkes%E2%80%93Dodson_law&quot;&gt;improved performance&lt;/a&gt; was too harmful to comtemplate.  Getting, living and staying LEAN is not easy … it never was, but now we have the luxury of choosing how we go about improving our performance, ie it’s no longer an the IMMEDIATE threat of “improve or be consumed” – it’s now the less immediate choice of “improve or eventually wish for death.”  Lack of an immediate threat allows us to fantasize that lack of improvement is an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distinguishing feature of the truth about fasting is that fasting is extremely simple purification process, but simple does not mean “easy” particularly when we are addicted to wheat, processed foods and sugar. In our culture, it is not easy managing nutrition using an objective, evidence-based approach for peak cognitive fitness. It is not easy getting the right kinds of exercise, building agility or useful balanced, efficient movement. It’s not easy managing your time optimally so that you get things done and can get plenty of sleep. It’s not easy to attack the world’s problems and remove the ultimate root causes of the stressors out of your life. But it actually is really SIMPLE. In fact, if it isn’t simple … you’re doing it wrong. There are good mnemonics like using D.O.W.N.T.I.M.E. to use to recognize the CAUSES of waste (eg not listening, movement for the sake of movement, transporting, waiting) and fat (eg too much inventory, overproduction, defective output, extras for ego) in all of the realms of your existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting LEAN is NOT easy, because people are addicted to fat and people are addicts of wasteful thinking … it’s bad enough, but there are also “dope pushers” out there feeding on serving the bad habits of addicts … it doesn’t matter if we are talking about Lean Enterprise, Lean Startups, Lean Production, Lean Manufacturing or just being LEAN individuals … getting LEAN is a matter of managing habits, it is stressful to change approaches to thinking but it is ultimately less stressful when the change you are bringing to your thinking is about removing the ultimate root cause behind the stressors in your existence … and accomplishing that change in thinking is about institutionalizing habits and there’s no substitute for perfect repetition of good movement, better posture with poise and reinforcement of correct habits in order to change [subconscious, involuntary, habitual] thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is way too easy to criticize all of the different diet and weight loss programs out there … they are ALL miserable failures and do not work SUSTAINABLY … some do work temporarily [with sufficient commitment to drive applied diligence] for a period of six-months to a year or two, but most of the time the body returns to an undesired FAT homeostatic set point.  When it comes to getting lean, there is ONE success out there – it’s in YOU already, it’s what gave you your life, your existence and the body that has been passed to you as a result multiple millennia of intermittent fasting that hundreds of generations of YOUR ancestors.  Your ancestors may not have been perfect, but whether they wanted to or not, they had to use fasting in order to survive to give YOU life. Fasting, like exercise, is a GOOD stress to the body – fasting is a stress that your body might not like all that much, but a stress that your body, mind and soul NEED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody can lose weight with almost any diet, if they stick with the plan to achieve caloric restriction … the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Biggest-Loser-Bootcamp-Get-Real-Get-Results/dp/084874554X&quot;&gt;Biggest Loser Diet&lt;/a&gt; is the quintessential example of UNSUSTAINABLE temporary success, i.e. the diet certainly works and achieves impressive results for 6 months, but when the “thrill of the attack” is over and the body’s homeostatic set point drops the basal metabolic rate to survive, THEN weight reduction is unsustainable, the person is miserable AND even though there is no pleasure of consuming food, weight is regained.  The main problem with every unsustainable diet is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/v9Aw0P7GjHE?t=43m16s&quot;&gt;basal metabolic rate decrease&lt;/a&gt; that happens as a result of mere caloric restriction – this means that after six months or so, the weight losses from caloric restriction get a LOT tougher because the basal metabolic rate has been decreased so much that weight gains happen with very low amounts of food consumption while at the same time, the lower metabolism causes the person to feel cold, stressed, uncomfortable, depressed and anxious to try anything but sustaining the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fasting, on the other hands, is a sustainable approach to life because fasting is NOT about caloric restriction – it is a stark extremely that actually drives a change in hormones, reducing the bodies production of insulin and cortisol, the two hormones driving the homeostatic FAT set point. Fasting is also about cleansing, changing the epigentics of the gut bacteria, purging the system of everything that craves sugar … but fasting also has cognitive and spiritual impacts – fasting is about getting rid of a lack of mindfulness, getting rid of bad habits, snacking, eating in the car, eating while doing something else. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/v9Aw0P7GjHE?t=50m19s&quot;&gt;Eliminating all forms of mindless eating&lt;/a&gt; seems SIMPLE enough – there are no recipes or complex restrictions or meal plans to develop or remember – the difficulty is there is time available to THINK, to mindfully contemplate, meditate and for many people this kind of simplicity [when one is fasting] is next to impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physiological hardware in your body was [effectively] not just designed to intermittently fast, your would ancestors [like other species on the planet] would never have survived moving more than a tens or hundreds miles from where their ancestors were born if they could not hormenetic THRIVE after periods of prolonged fasting  … THRIVING after periods of prolonged fasting is the enabling technology for migratory superiority, ie the ability to explore, survive and then DOMINATE brand new environments … it’s only RECENTLY that we have undermined our bodies by allowing ourselves to become habitually addicted to bad habits, engaged in mindless eating, eating while driving, eating at our desks, eating while watching television or surfing the net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fasting is painful, it’s unrelenting pain and therefore fasting is STRESSFUL … but it is STRESS that you need … fasting is like an exercise program that pushes you beyond the point that you thought you signed up for. Nobody should underestimate how difficult fasting is – people do need to understand that, as with exercise and exercise past the point of comfort, there will be benefits … but that doesn’t mean the benefits will immediately be massive; the results will be HUMBLING.  Think of the results as you would body building. Nobody is going to win a Mr. Universe contest after five or six workouts or two weeks of extreme, grueling workouts in the gym … most body builders quit because the results are humbling and they think that “the view is not worth the climb”. Fasting will burn off fat for energy, it will allow you to think with greater clarity, it will allow you to have more creative insights, it will allow you to have brilliant spiritual visions … but FIRST fasting will be stressful and painful and intolerable.  You will NEVER get addicted to fasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fasting is not particularly dangerous for most people if only it is a habit that is far too easy to walk away from or abandon … affluent humans do not choose to fast because fasting is just not that much fun, it’s not that soothing or it is definitely not an intoxicating enabler of escapism … for affluent human beings, fasting is MINDFUL DISCIPLINE and doing it responsibly means paying a lot more attention to your body, health and fitness.  However, fasting is essential.  Without fasting, you and your species would not have made it this far … fasting is tough, but it is like an abrasive honing tool that sharpens the spear for physical, cognitive, spiritual optimization … but fasting is far from popular. Fasting, particularly at first, really sucks. Fasting has enemies. Fasting is aggressively criticized by many experts BECAUSE fasting does not help any expert’s business model, selling fasting products will not make companies money or reward investors hoping to profit from the next Viagra … in spite of what people might want to imagine, no professional is going to get fabulously rich being the “guru of fasting” because the only way to make fasting work, is to do it right … and fasting right is HARD, and most of the work has to be done by the person fasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The healthcare industry is driven by simple, easy solutions like prescribed medications and NEVER EVER asking people to do anything HARD [except pay the bill and deal with side effects.]  The problem with this approach is that simple, easy, quick solutions do not begin to address the ultimate root cause … instead they addict lazy people to believing in the lies that sell simple, easy, quick solutions.  This is especially true in topics like diabetes or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metabolic_syndrome&quot;&gt;metabolic syndrome&lt;/a&gt; – medications do not [and probably cannot] even attempt to begin to &lt;a href=&quot;https://intensivedietarymanagement.com/two-big-lies-type-2-diabetes-video-lecture/&quot;&gt;reverse insulin resistance&lt;/a&gt; or any of the issues in the underlying &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endocrinology&quot;&gt;endocrinology&lt;/a&gt; driving the problem. Medications only address symptoms and give superficial relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-started-acquiring-expertise-understand-ultimate-root-cause&quot;&gt;Getting Started, Acquiring Expertise, Understand Ultimate Root Cause&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEFORE you start fasting, you really have to LEARN a lot about fasting and nutrition … you have to LEARN … for yourself … about the ultimate root cause of your health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start with armfuls of books if you want … work by Dr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dr.-Jason-Fung/e/B01BT8K6FK/ref=ntt_aut_sim_3_1&quot;&gt;Jason Fung&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/David-Perlmutter/e/B001JSAC00/ref=ntt_aut_sim_3_1&quot;&gt;David Perlmutter&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Thomas-N.-Seyfried/e/B006M7MT86&quot;&gt;Thomas N. Seyfried&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Gary-Taubes/e/B0034P66MY/ref=ntt_aut_sim_1_1&quot;&gt;Gary Taubes&lt;/a&gt;… but you will also need to spend time at PubMed and looking at LOTS of articles about fasting, nutrition and topics that are specific to your health concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fasting-risk-management&quot;&gt;Fasting Risk Management&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, fasting is dangerous … so is crossing a street, so is driving a car, so is eating anything especially if you haven’t prepared it from scratch.  Fasting is dangerous … but it’s probably not as dangerous as having sex or routinely drinking diet soda. Fasting is nowhere near as dangerous as alcohol consumption.  Fasting is far less dangerous than buying or using any kind of illicit drugs.  Don’t listen to people who tell you that fasting is perfectly safe; you should know what you are doing when you fast OR otherwise, it’s as bad as routinely eating processed sugar or carelessly trusting that artificial sweeteners are safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;become-more-body-aware&quot;&gt;Become More Body Aware&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learn-by-experimenting-in-a-knowledgable-manner&quot;&gt;LEARN by experimenting in a knowledgable manner&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hormesis&quot;&gt;Hormesis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;master-intermittent-fasting-first&quot;&gt;Master Intermittent Fasting FIRST&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;introductory-prolonged-fasting&quot;&gt;5 + 2 Introductory Prolonged Fasting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;master-prolonged-fasting&quot;&gt;Master Prolonged Fasting&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/nutrition,/movement,/sleep,/stress,/lean,/d.o.w.n.t.i.m.e.,/mindful/discipline,/intermittent/fasting,/prolonged/hormesis/2017/04/02/Intermittent-Fasting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nutrition,/movement,/sleep,/stress,/lean,/d.o.w.n.t.i.m.e.,/mindful/discipline,/intermittent/fasting,/prolonged/hormesis/2017/04/02/Intermittent-Fasting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Nutrition,</category>
        
        <category>Movement,</category>
        
        <category>Sleep,</category>
        
        <category>Stress,</category>
        
        <category>LEAN,</category>
        
        <category>D.O.W.N.T.I.M.E.,</category>
        
        <category>Mindful</category>
        
        <category>DISCIPLINE,</category>
        
        <category>Intermittent</category>
        
        <category>Fasting,</category>
        
        <category>Prolonged</category>
        
        <category>Hormesis</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TRIZ</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been reconsidering how I should develop or recast my skillsets in order to not only emigrate to life in the virtual realm but to be a more valuable and active citizen in the virtual realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Golden-rule … I treat others as I would want to be treated; most of all, this requires that I am FRANK, BLUNT and BRUTALLY HONEST with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Assertiveness for everyone is a matter of pragmatic Stoicism. It is not that “might makes right” or authoritarianism … in this existence, Reality rules – that means understanding Reality and making the best of what options we have. There is nothing to be gained by imagining we are entitled to better options … we must understand Reality as Reality really is, not as someone wants to imagine, hope or fear Reality might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Communication, especially listening to others, is my obligation. I need to be proficient in the predominant languages of my trades – most of the time, someone else has already solved the problem before, so it is up to me to UNDERSTAND the root cause of problems and to apply existing solutions before re-inventing the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond these basic , there are still fundamental principles of inventiveness … principles that that I need to refine, extend, think more deeply about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;segmentation&quot;&gt;1. Segmentation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Deconstruct, refactor and simplify complexity into separate, independent “chewable” pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide-and-conquer workflows, understand value-addition, D.O.W.N.T.I.M.E eliminates waste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design ventures to be autonomous profit centers; eliminate cost / complexity / overhead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop understandable work breakdown structures for large project to tap remote talent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distribute power/control to franchised outlets to serve customers more directly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image/Value/Satisfaction segmentation of customer purchase-related preferences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kano Diagram – Excitement, Performance, and Threshold product attribute parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Micro-niche segmentation by demographics, sociographics, psychographics, lifestyles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Segmentation of ‘idea management’ process into Fertilization, Seeding, and Incubation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strength/Weakness/Opportunity/Threat (SWOT) analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplifying complexity without losing value with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.basadur.com/howwedoit/TheSimplexityThinkingSystem/tabid/72/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;simplexity thinking&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.basadur.com/howwedoit/An8StepProcess/tabid/82/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;Basadur process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B. Design objects to be easy to disassemble/assemble/reconfigure.&lt;br /&gt;
  * Flexible pensions
  * Eliminate headcount, use temporary workers, contractors, short-term project
  * Flexible Manufacturing Systems
  * Modular furniture/offices
  * Container shipment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C. Increase the degree of fragmentation or segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality Circles or LEAN workshops for empowerment – segmentation of decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distance learning (also ‘Taking Out’)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Virtual office/remote working (also ‘Taking Out’)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Creative Segmentation’ – ‘high performance small car’, ‘easy to use SLR’, ‘cordless power tool’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;taking-out&quot;&gt;2. Taking Out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate an interfering part or property from an object, or single out the only necessary part (or property) of an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakdown barriers between departments (Point No.9 of Deming’s Fourteen Points (5)).
Eliminate exhortations (Point No.10 of Deming’s Fourteen Points (5))
Eliminate targets (Point No.11 of Deming’s Fourteen Points (5)).
Drive Out Fear (Point No.8 of Deming’s Fourteen Points (5))
‘Separate the PEOPLE from the PROBLEM’ (‘Getting To Yes’ (6)).
‘Lean Manufacture’ (7)
USP advertising
Just-In-Time inventory management
Activity-Based Costing instead of allocation cost accounting.
Separate development and production activities – skunkworks, tiger-teams, etc.
‘The optimum committee has no members’ (Augustine’s Law #31 (Reference 8))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;local-quality&quot;&gt;3. Local Quality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Change an object’s structure from uniform to non-uniform, change an external environment (or external influence) from uniform to non-uniform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moves away from rigid salary structures/job grading.
Flexible working hours.
Franchise fast food outlets have local dishes in addition to normal product range.
Casual (‘dress-down’) days.
Introduce ‘Corporate Jester’ (e.g. British Airways) as a method of encouraging ‘out of the box’ thinking.
Red team/Blue team proposal preparation structures
‘Quiet’ work areas.
B. Make each part of an object function in conditions most suitable forits operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Empowerment’ of individuals
Have each employee’s workplace customized to his/her ergonomic and psychological needs.
Working hours phased to accommodate people working on international, shifted time-zone projects
Customizable software
C. Make each part of an object fulfill a different and useful function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;organizational division by function rather than product.
Staff specialists in centers of excellence
Position factory or distribution center near to customers
Hire local people to acquire cultural knowledge of local customers
‘Kids areas’ in restaurants, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;asymmetry&quot;&gt;4. Asymmetry&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Change the shape of an object from symmetrical to asymmetrical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Proportionately) more ‘P’ or more ‘S’ in the Deming PDSA cycle
Skewed normal distributions.
Use a different marketing approach for each class of clients. (Combine with Segmentation and Local Quality–make each class smaller to be sure the approach is exactly tailored to it.)
Budget for different departments individually rather than using a constant percentage increase or reduction for all departments
B. If an object is asymmetrical, change itsdegree of asymmetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;360º appraisals
More equitable 2-way dialogue between management and workers
Shift away from calendar-influenced sales bias (e.g. shift from annual to bi-annual car registration dates (to reduce August sales peak), greetings card companies, etc.)
‘The Peter Pyramid’ (9)
Honda’s 4M – ‘man maximum, machine minimum’ product design philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;merging&quot;&gt;5. Merging&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Bring closer together (or merge) identical or similar objects, assemble identical or similar parts to perform parallel operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal computers in a network
Cell-based Manufacture
Toyota JIT
Merge companies with related products
Internet Cafe
The ‘Joiner Triangle’ – Quality/Scientific Approach/All-One-Team (10)
‘Young engineers have ideas, old engineers have bad experiences’ Japanese saying
B. Make operations contiguous or parallel; bring them together in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theory of Constraints (11)
Enlisting customer help in designing the product (Boeing 777 ‘Working Together Teams)
Multi-media presentations
‘Aligned, Creative and Exploring’ Teams (12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;universality&quot;&gt;6. Universality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Make an object or structure performmultiple functions; eliminate the need for other parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-skilling of work-force
Team leader acts as recorder and timekeeper.
‘One-stop shopping’ – supermarkets sell insurance, banking services, fuel, newspapers, etc.
Rapid Reaction Forces in the military – cross-trained, equipment versatility, etc)
Semco – managerial staff set their own salaries, shopfloor workers set their own productivity targets, part of change agent’s job is to eliminate need for his/her job (13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;nested-doll&quot;&gt;7. “Nested Doll”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Place one object inside another; place each object, in turn, inside theother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Store-in-store
Mapping priority innovation areas (Reference 3, pp136-7)
Four levels of knowledge – 1) Basic Skills, 2) Know How, 3) Process Management, 4) Strategic Vision – contained in effective company (e.g. Sony) training schemes – (Reference 3, pp292-4)
Hierarchy of employee needs – Basic, Environment, Simple Individual, Complex Individual, Transcendent (Reference 14, Chapter 3)
B. Make one part pass through a cavity in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plug holes in organization structure
Use ‘Why, What’s Stopping?’ question sequence to break through layers of problems to get to root cause (4)
Expose traditionally inward facing job-holders to external events/customers (e.g. engineers shadow marketing people during customer visits)
Door sensors count customers into and out of a store/office, etc (use data for market profiling, etc)
Casino hotel architecture (Las Vegas style): The guest must pass through the gaming area to get to the restaurant, the hotel registration, even the lavatories!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;anti-weight&quot;&gt;8. Anti-Weight&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. To compensate for the weight (downward tendency)of an object, merge it with other objects that provide lift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a merger of two companies, one ‘lifts’ the other with whatever its stronger features are (distribution system, marketing, methods, capital, etc)
Companies increase flagging sales by making connections with other rising products (e.g. movie tie-ins)
‘This is my depressed stance. When you’re depressed, it makes a lot of difference how you stand. The worst thing you can do is straighten up and hold your head high because then you’ll start to feel better. If you’re going to get any joy out of being depressed, you’ve got to stand like this.’ Charlie Brown
“Whenever I feel afraid, I hold my head erect, and whistle a happy tune, and no one will suspect I’m afraid.”–Anna in “The King and I” by Rogers and Hammerstein
B. To compensate for the weight (downward tendency)of an object, make it interact with the environment (e.g. use globallift forces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small company is ‘lifted’ by a resource – use of a transportation network, etc – to the level of the larger companies
Political parties boost poll ratings by attaching themselves to popular causes
Attach product/service marketing to customer and business driving forces (Megatrends – aging population, desire for flexibility, simplicity, etc)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;preliminary-anti-action&quot;&gt;9. Preliminary Anti-Action&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. If it will be necessary to do an action with both harmful and usefuleffects, this action should be replaced with anti-actions to control harmfuleffects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making a public announcement, include all the information, not just the harmful parts (e.g. Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson’s handling of the Tylenol tampering case)
Use formal risk assessment methods to quantify risk and identify mitigation actions before (and during) a project
Customer trials/segmented launch of (high risk) new products (e.g. film companies film several endings to a movie and trial with different audiences before finalising selection)
Use of voluntary redundancy/pay-cuts/short-time working/job-sharing as alternatives to down-sizing
B. Create beforehand stresses in an object that will oppose knownundesirable working stresses later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epson product development engineers spend time as sales and then service staff before they are allowed to work on product development activities (Reference 3, p101)
Prior to a lay-off, prepare compensation, outplacement, and communication packages for all affected employees
‘In me the tiger sniffs the rose.’ Siegfried Sassoon
Principle 10. Preliminary Action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Perform, before it is needed, the required change of an object (eitherfully or partially).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project pre-planning
Perform non-critical path tasks early (where circumstances permit)
Dialogue with employees before embarking on BPR/change management activities.
Use of ‘story-boarding’ to facilitate creative problem solving (i.e. gathering the data before the “creativity” session)
B. Pre-arrange objects such that they can come into action from the mostconvenient place and without losing time for their delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanban arrangements in a Just-In-Time factory
Cell-based manufacture
Publish an agenda before meetings
‘If I had 8 hours to chop down a tree, I’d spend 6 hours sharpening my axe’ Abraham Lincoln.
Benetton ‘retarded differentiation’ – clothing is knitted before it is dyed; colour only applied when the season’s popular colours emerge.
Dealer-fit car accessories – CD player, alloy wheels, air-con, etc.
Principle 11. Beforehand Cushioning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Prepare emergency means beforehand to compensate for the relatively lowreliability of an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contingency planning
Establish a worst-case, fall-back position prior to negotiation – ‘Best Alternative to a Negotiated Agreement’ (6)
Back up computer data
Run anti-virus software frequently (and update it frequently)
Encourage short, effective meetings by removing the chairs
Put clauses in contracts requiring arbitration/mediation to avoid litigation
Begin with ‘S’ in the PDSA cycle (10)
‘80% of a successful production is in the casting’ Lindsay Anderson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;principle-12-equipotentiality&quot;&gt;Principle 12. Equipotentiality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. In a potential field, limit position changes (e.g. change operatingconditions to eliminate the need to raise or lower objects in a gravity field).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make ‘horizontal’ career changes to broaden skills
Team members distribute their own merit award money (rather than often divisive management dictate)
Force-Field Analysis – group discussion of the phrase ‘forces push in various directions’ – teambuilding/problem-solving technique discussed in Reference 3.
Beware of the Peter Principle – ‘Every employee tends to rise to his/her level of incompetence (15)
Principle 13. ‘The Other Way Round’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Invert the action(s) used to solve the problem (e.g. instead of coolingan object, heat it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring the mountain to Mohammed, instead of bringing Mohammed to the mountain.
Expansion instead of contraction during recession.
Benchmark against the worst instead of the best (16).
Blame the process not the person
‘I used to think that anyone doing anything weird was weird. I suddenly realised that anyone doing anything weird wasn’t weird at all, and it was the people saying they were weird that were weird’ Paul McCartney.
B. Make movable parts (or the external environment) fixed, and fixed partsmovable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home-shopping
Home banking
Park-and-ride schemes in busy cities
Don’t make changes just because they are fashionable management fads
‘If you obey all the rules, you miss all the fun’ Katherine Hepburn (17)
C. Turn the object (or process) ‘upside down‘.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cash-till assistant is the most important part of a retail organization
Computer help lines were often originally set up with relatively no-technical staff at the front-end, directing calls to progressively more technically able staff the more complicated the problem is. Latest logic suggests reversing this trend – i.e. place the most qualified staff as first point of contact (e.g. IBM)
Product- rather than function- based organization structure
‘Ready, Fire, Aim’ – Tom Peters (18)
Mercedes Benz vision changed from ‘the best or nothing’ to ‘the best for our customers’ – i.e. shift from internal to externally focused vision statement.
The Peter Pyramid (9)
Corporate ‘unlearning’ – acquiring the ability to forget about the past where appropriate
‘Ours is the age that is proud of machines that think and suspicious of men who try to’ H Mumford-Jones (16)
Russian government pays inventors for patent applications/West makes the inventor pay to apply.
Chairman of company spends time in the complaints department answering customer complaints
‘Nothing fails like success’ (19)
‘We don’t stop playing because we grow old, we grow old because we stop playing’ (12)
‘When you reach the top, that’s when the climb begins’ Michael Caine
Principle 14. Spheroidality – Curvature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Instead of using rectilinear parts, surfaces, or forms, use curvilinearones; move from flat surfaces to spherical ones; from parts shaped as a cube(parallelepiped) to ball-shaped structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ergonomic desk/work-station designs.
Take the shortest path to the customer – around the organization rather than point-to-point through the bureaucracy
‘Form the wagons into a circle’ John Wayne
B. Use rollers, balls, spirals, domes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile factory
Mobile car service – mechanic comes to you rather than you going to garage
Mobile library
‘Meals on wheels’/home-delivery pizza
C. Go from linear to rotary motion, use centrifugal forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotate leadership of a team
Establish a sphere of influence, then market to that sphere
Quality Circles
Circular work cells
Levi Strauss’ IS Department’s organizational chart resembles a solar system, with the names of 20 managers appearing once on a large circle-and in many cases, also on one of four smaller circles intersecting the large one. The small circles represent action groups focusing on specific tasks, including customer service and business systems (20).
Principle 15. Dynamics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Allow (or design) the characteristics of an object, externalenvironment, or process to change to be optimal or to find an optimal operatingcondition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empowerment
‘Customer Response Teams’
Continuous Process Improvement
Rapid Reaction Force
Swatch design proliferation – design for specific market niches
‘Cafeteria’ benefits – where employees pick which types of insurance, health system, etc. they want
‘In today’s turbulent business environment, there are no hard fast conclusions – only transitions’ (14)
B. Divide an object into parts capable of movement relative to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work teams oriented to achieve same goal, but work at different rates on different objectives
Geographically or functionally independent business units
Conglomerate structures
C. If an object (or process) is rigid or inflexible, make it movable oradaptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gallery Furniture on-line shopping – customer is able to control and move cameras to point to different products in different parts of the store from his/her home computer (www.galleryfurniture.com)
Changing the supervisor’s role; avoid ‘whack-a-mole’ firefighting (Reference 10, p20)
Flexible organization structure (chaocracy)
Principle 16. Partial or Excessive Actions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. If 100 percent of an objective is hard toachieve using a given solution method then, by using ‘slightly less’ or’slightly more’ of the same method, the problem may be considerably easier tosolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into a new market, do “saturation” advertising by all media–mail, newspapers, local magazines, local radio, local TV, billboards, etc.
Communicate more often and with more information than you think necessary
‘If it ain’t broke, improve it anyway’ – Japanese process management philosophy.
‘The most important numbers are the ones you’ll never know’ – W.E. Deming (i.e. is it possible to ever know what ‘100%’ means)
‘Communication is and should be hellfire and sparks, as well as sweetness and light’ Aman Vivian Rakoff
Principle 17. Another Dimension&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. To move an object in two- or three-dimensional space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;360º appraisals.
Multi-dimensional organization hierarchy charts – 3D (e.g. to show ‘hard’ and ‘soft’ relationships), or 4D – to include an element of time or movement (‘Buckyball Management’ – Reference 20)
Distributed responsibility and authority – e.g. Quality department advises on technical details and conducts audits, but everyone is responsible for quality. Ditto Safety Office.
B. Use a multi-story arrangement of objects instead of a single-storyarrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;organizational hierarchy
Multi-stack storage systems use the height of a building, and save floorspace
Employees “disappear” from the customers in a theme park, descend into a tunnel, and walk to their next assignment, where they return to the surface and magically reappear.
‘Pile ‘em high, sell ‘em cheap’
‘Standing on the shoulders of giants…’
‘When two people meet, there are really six people present. There is each man as he sees himself, each man as he wants to be seen, and each man as he really is.’ Michael De Saintamo
C. Tilt or re-orient the object, lay it on its side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horizontal (peer) communication
Horizontally integrated manufacture
Switch from vertical to horizontal (lateral) thinking – and vice-versa (21)
Shift from ‘line’ to ‘project’ management dominance in matrix organization (and vice-versa – depending on prevailing market conditions)
Shift from portrait to landscape report format
D. Use ‘another side’ of a given area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View your organization from the outside – either directly or using consultants, ‘mystery shoppers’, etc.
New ways of looking at the selling process – instead of selling carpets to its commercial and industrial customers, Interface now offers what it calls the “Evergreen Lease.” Its customers no longer buy carpets or pay an installation fee – they just pay a monthly service fee that guarantees they will always have clean, attractive carpets (22)
‘The seeing of objects involves many sources of information beyond those meeting the eye when we look at an object. It generally involves knowledge of the object derived from previous experience, and this experience is not limited to vision but may include the other senses: touch, taste, smell, hearing, and perhaps also temperature or pain.’ R.L.Gregory
‘You can’t teach an old dogma new tricks’ Dorothy Parker
Principle 18. Mechanical vibration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Cause an object to oscillate or vibrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the catchball process of hoshin planning to get the whole organization ‘vibrating’
‘A good manager doesn’t try to eliminate conflict; he tries to keep it from wasting the energies of his people. If you’re the boss and your people fight you openly when they think that you are wrong — that’s healthy’ Robert Townsend
‘The things we fear most in organizations — fluctuations, disturbances, imbalances — are the primary sources of creativity’ Margaret J Wheatley.
B. Increase its frequency (even up to the ultrasonic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communicate frequently, in multiple modes (newsletter, Intranet, staff meetings, etc).
‘I don’t think that you should ever manage anything that you don’t care passionately about’ D Coleman, VP &amp;amp; CFO Apple (12)
‘He inspired in us the belief that we were working in a medium that was powerful enough to influence the world’ Lillian Gish on D.W.Griffiths (12)
C. Use an object’s resonant frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use strategic planning (policy deployment, hoshin Kanri) to select the right frequency and get the organization resonating at that frequency to accomplish a breakthrough strategy
Creating extra-ordinary unity of purpose in a work-team (e.g. Don Petersen’s story of the Ford versus Mazda ‘competition to win the transmission job for the FWD Taurus (23))
‘Kansei’ – Japanese term for resonance/one-ness between product and user (Reference 23, pp 139-45)
D. Use piezoelectric vibrators instead of mechanical ones, E. Usecombined ultrasonic and electromagnetic field oscillations. (Useexternal elements to create oscillation/vibration)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring new blood into team
Hire consultant
Principle 19. Periodic Action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Instead of continuous action, use periodic or pulsating actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Batch manufacture.
Tidal traffic flow schemes ease transport into and out of busy areas
Change team leadership periodically (e.g. countries take it in turns to ‘lead’ the EU)
Introduce sabbaticals to refresh people’s points of view
B. If an action is already periodic, change the periodic magnitude orfrequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audit at irregular intervals
Use monthly or weekly feedback instead of annual reviews
Flexible savings schemes which pay higher interest rates the fewer the number of withdrawals made
C. Use pauses between impulses to perform a different action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get work done between meetings
Perform maintenance work during vacations
24-hour car service operation – evening pick-up, return of serviced car by breakfast the following morning (customer perspective).
Principle 20. Continuity of Useful Action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Carry on work continuously; make all parts of an object work at fullload, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the bottleneck operations in a factory continuously, to reach the optimum pace. (From theory of constraints)
Institute Constant Improvement (Point No.5 of Deming’s Fourteen Points (5))
Continuous on-line monitoring of elevators by Otis – total maintenance responsibility (Reference 3, pp54-5)
24 hour car service operation – evening pick-up, return of serviced car by breakfast the following morning (garage perspective)
‘The power of a waterfall is nothing but a lot of drips working together’ (12)
B. Eliminate all idle or intermittent actions or work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-skilling to enable working in bottleneck functions to improve workflow
Conduct training during pauses in work
‘Hot-till’ing in supermarkets – staff do other tasks during quiet periods; move to tills when they see queues developing
‘Life-long learning’
‘The more I practice, the luckier I get’ Gary Player
Principle 21. Skipping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Conduct a process , or certain stages (e.g. destructive, harmful orhazardous operations) at high speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Incrementalism is innovation’s worst enemy’ Nicholas Negreponte, MIT Media Lab (18)
‘Don’t be afraid to take a big step if one is indicated. You can’t cross a chasm in two small jumps’ David Lloyd George
‘Fail Fast; Learn Fast’
‘Fast Cycle – Full Participation’ – method of involving the whole organization simultaneously and rapidly in a major change, such as a re-organization
Get through painful processes quickly (e.g. firing someone)
Rapid prototyping
‘If you want to succeed, double your failure rate’ JR Watson, IBM founder
Principle 22. “Blessing in Disguise” or “Turn Lemons intoLemonade”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Use harmful factors (particularly, harmful effects of the environmentor surroundings) to achieve a positive effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recast an attack on you as an attack on the problem (6).
Making a fuss over customers who have experienced a problem with your goods/services/etc, tends to re-enforce their overall positive feel about you – to a level greater than that where no problem had occurred
Collect information to understand the harm, then formulate a positive action to remove it
‘Provocations’ method of encouraging new ideas (24)
‘The Extra Mile will have no traffic jams.’ Unknown.
B. Eliminate the primary harmful action by adding it to another harmfulaction to resolve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliminate fear of change by introducing fear of competition
Put a ‘problem’ person on an assignment in another area where he/she can do well and not be a problem to the original group
Loss-leader strategy for increasing sales
Keep traffic out of cities by introducing cheap ‘park and ride’ and expensive downtown parking charges.
Make potentially polluting industries place flow intakes downstream of flow outlets on a river
C. Amplify a harmful factor to such a degree that it is no longer harmful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The famous software solution ‘that’s not a bug, it’s a feature’
Benevolent dictatorship (25)
Reduce resourcing levels to such an extent that new ways of doing the job have to be discovered
Restrict supply of goods to create scarcity value (e.g. some sports car manufacturers seek to maintain a multiple year waiting list on vehicles)
Principle 23. Feedback&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Introduce feedback (referring back, cross-checking) to improve aprocess or action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistical Process Control (SPC) — Measurements are used to decide when to modify a process.
Budgets –Measurements are used to decide when to modify a process.
Enlist customers in the design process.
‘Extranets’ (22)
Customer surveys/customer seminars, etc
‘Active Transition Management’ as a way of controlling product development process between research, development and production phases.
Electronic bulletin boards
(Supermarket) loyalty cards – provide customer shopping profile information
‘What you measure is what you get’ Joe Juran
B. If feedback is already used, change its magnitude or influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change a management measure from budget variance to customer satisfaction.
Expose designers as well as marketers to customers
Multi-Criteria Decision Analysis (valid ‘apples and oranges’ comparisons).
Toshiba medical systems division split into R&amp;amp;D, Engineering and Manufacture sectors. As a product is being developed, key personnel and leadership physically move from one sector to another to actively manage transitions between product development stages.
‘Open the kimono’ – everything out in the open communication (Reference 14, Chapter 9)
‘Supravision’ rather than ‘supervision’
‘Co-evolutionary marketing’ – e.g. Amazon.com invites readers to write on-line book reviews; other readers often prefer these views to professional reviewer evaluations, therefore people visit the site more often (26)
Motorola ‘open dissent’ policy – employees fill in a minority report to senior management when ideas they consider valuable are unsupported by colleagues and immediate superiors (Reference 27, pp164-6)
Use of ‘half-life’ as a measure of improvement (e.g. time taken to half product development time) to encourage large-scale thinking
Principle 24. ‘Intermediary’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Use an intermediary carrier article or intermediary process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use of impartial body during difficult negotiation (e.g. ACAS)
‘Po’ (provocative operator) – a place between ‘yes’ and ‘no’, construct devised by Edward DeBono to help avoid premature discarding of ideas (28)
Sub-contract non-core business (e.g. cleaning services, transport)
Franchisee acts as intermediary between corporate vision and customer
Travel agent (NB can also mean removal of intermediary – e.g. direct selling).
UPS distribution system using core sorting center.
KLM ‘feeder’ airline concept – short flights from Germany, England pull passengers away from national airlines in order that they fly long distances using Holland as a hub
‘Video Plus’ – programme video using simple codes to represent channels, dates and times
‘Cuckoo Investments’ (24)
B. Merge one object temporarily with another (which can be easilyremoved).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction of specialist trouble-shooting or fire-fighting teams
Hire consultant.
Use bridging loan arrangements to help cashflow
Subcontract occasional services – accounts, cleaning, transport, etc.
Principle 25. Self-service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Make an object serve itself by performing auxiliary helpful functions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality Circles
Self-help groups
Brand image circularity – Harvard Business School produces bright people; these people enhance the School’s reputation; hence lots of people apply; hence they only take on very bright people; bright people in equals bright people out; and so the circle re-enforces itself.
‘Cookies’ on the Internet gather data useful for future marketing activities, while performing a useful service for the ‘surfer’
Bar-codes in supermarkets provide instant pricing information, but the system also gathers information to assist future marketing decisions
Edward DeBono’s suggestion to Ford UK that they buy National Car Parks and then only let Ford cars into the parking lots – i.e. motorists buying a Ford are also buying a parking place in every city (24)
B. Use waste (or lost) resources, energy, orsubstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-hire retired workers for jobs where their experience is needed
Loan out temporarily under-utilised workers to other organizations (load-capacity balancing across companies – e.g. footballers – win-win situation; the player stays match fit, the loaner saves wages, the loanee fills skill shortage)
‘Industrial eco-systems’ (22, 29) – e.g. plan factories so that waste heat from one operation provides power for another operation, install co-generation equipment so that waste heat can generate electricity–use it for your own operations or sell it to the electric power utility.
‘Brown-field’ developments
Body Shop re-cycles used containers brought back by customers – helps promote corporate green image
Re-cycle all packaging material
Scan mail into data systems and recycle the paper
Principle 26. Copying&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Instead of an unavailable, expensive, fragile object, use simpler andinexpensive copies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual reality via computer instead of an expensive vacation
Listen to an audiotape instead of attending a seminar.
Rapid prototyping (e.g. stereo-lithography)
Scan rare, historic books, documents, etc so they are accessible to all and the original remains protected
Lascaux II – reproduction of Lascaux cave paintings which is open to visitors
. Replace an object, or process with optical copies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual product service manuals.
Video-conferencing instead of physical travel
Use a central electronic database instead of paper records in cases where multiple users would benefit from simultaneous access to data – e.g. medical records, customer data, engineering drawings, etc
Keep your personal calendar on a web-site so you (and others?) can access it from any computer, and it can’t get lost
C If optical copies are used, move to IR or UV (Usean appropriate out of the ordinary illumination and viewing situation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluate employee morale using multiple methods such as interviews and questionnaires (2 different ‘wavelengths’)
Evaluate customer satisfaction using multiple techniques
Have your customers benchmark you/have your suppliers benchmark you
Principle 27. Cheap Short-Living Objects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Replace an expensive object with a multiple of inexpensive objects,compromising certain qualities (such as service life, for instance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use disposable paper objects to avoid the cost of cleaning and storing durable objects. Plastic cups in motels, disposable diapers, many kinds of medical supplies.
Numerical simulation – operational analysis (virtual war-gaming, virtual business development, strategic planning modeling).
Flight simulator reduces pilot training costs.
Swatch ‘renewed impulse’ buying ‘ – ‘Change clothes? Change Swatch’.
Principle 28 Mechanics Substitution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Replace a mechanical means with a sensory (optical, acoustic, taste orsmell) means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEO of budget motel chain; ‘our goal is that when you turn out the lights and climb into bed, you think you are at the Hilton’ (16)
Have retail customers enter data by means of a touch screen, instead of filling out a form that must be keyed in by employees. (Wedding registries, etc. use this)
Electronic voting
Supermarkets pump bakery odours around the store to help advertise bread products
B. Use electric, magnetic and electromagnetic fields to interact with theobject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mrs Fields Cookies has a morning video/internet conference with all franchisees – electronic communication replaces memos, etc.
Automatic GPS sensors inform central control point where (e.g. delivery trucks or taxis) are
Electronic tagging
Pagers
C. Change from static to movable fields, from unstructured fields to thosehaving structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind-maps (30)
Tidal traffic flow schemes /HOV lanes
‘Hot-desking’
MBWA – Management By Walking Around
D. Use fields in conjunction with field-activated (e.g. ferromagnetic)particles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind-mapping software tools
Intelligent tidal traffic flow control (e.g. using roadside sensors)
Use a radio transponder payment system for traffic control (Highway 91 in California). The fee ranges from $0.50 to $3.50 depending on how heavy the traffic is on the free part of the highway. Radio signals deduct the payment from the users’ account when the car enters the special traffic lane.
Principle 29. Pneumatics and Hydraulics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Use gas and liquid parts of an object instead of solid parts (e.g.inflatable, filled with liquids, air cushion, hydrostatic, hydro-reactive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Water logic’ versus ‘rock logic’ – fluid, flowing, gradually building up logic versus permanent, hard-edged, rock-like alternatives (31)
Flexible (fluid) organization structure versus old fixed hierarchical structures
Liquidation of assets
Introduction of ‘breathing spaces’ into contracts
Principle 30. Flexible Shells and Thin Films&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Use flexible shells and thin films instead of three-dimensionalstructures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thinnest film is a single molecule thick. Likewise, the thinnest organization structure is one employee thick. Get faster customer service by having the single employee customer service agent have all the necessary data easily available, so the customer only deals with the single, flexible ‘shell’ of the organization not the whole bulky volume.
Card transactions instead of money – e.g. vending machines in companies use employee ID card and charges are debited direct from salary
‘Cardboard police’ – 2D policemen or police cars over freeway bridges used as a means of slowing down traffic
Inflatable ‘passenger’ for lone drivers out late at night
B. Isolate the object from the external environment using flexible shellsand thin films.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Office workers in open areas can use flexible curtains to shut themselves off from the visual chaos of the open area when they need to concentrate rather than communicate
Use ‘trade secret’ methods to separate company proprietary knowledge from general knowledge
‘Umbrella’ organizations
‘We like to delegate and leave people as free as possible, so we try to push management decisions down the line. We run Rolls-Royce with a very thin corporate structure’, Lord Tombs of Brailes, ex-Chairman of Rolls-Royce (32)
Principle 31. Porous Materials&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Make an object porous or add porous elements (inserts, coatings, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the customer-facing layers of a company as a porous membrane which filters information flow both into and out of the organization
Improve internal communications by creating Intranet accessible by all hierarchical layers; giving workers access to CEO and vice-versa.
‘Trickle-down’ economics
Government ‘leaks’ – used as a way of gauging public reaction to (usually) controversial issues
B. If an object is already porous, use the pores to introduce a usefulsubstance or function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empower the customer facing layer (information is the thing that fills the pores – see 30A).
Use mind-maps (30), self-patterning capabilities (21), etc to improve the information/knowledge intake and filtering abilities of the brain
Media relations department turns spin-doctor and/or marketing feedback gatherer
Principle 32. Color Changes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Change the color of an object or its external environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red/Blue proposal preparation teams
Use of lighting effects to change mood in a room or office
Six Thinking Hats (33)
Creation of ‘corporate colours’ – creating a strong brand image through use of bespoke colours – ‘BP green’, ‘British Telecom red’ phone boxes, ‘Ford blue’, etc
Use colours to communicate state of alert (green, black, amber, red, etc)
Highlighter pens
B. Change the transparency of an object or its external environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Transparent’ organizations
Transparent communications
Importance of creating clear, concise mission statement (34)
Smoke-screen/mis-information to disguise confidential R&amp;amp;D etc activities
Principle 33. Homogeneity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Make objects interact with a given object of the same material (ormaterial with identical properties).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-located project teams
Internal customers
Product branding/product families
Boeing ‘Working Together Teams’ – bring customers and suppliers into design loop.
‘Constancy of Purpose’ (Point No. 1 of Deming’s Fourteen Points (5))
‘Singing from the same hymn sheet’
Common data transfer protocols between different organizations
‘The best way to make a silk purse from a sow’s ear is to begin with a silk sow. The same is true of money’ (Augustine’s Law #1 (Reference 8))
Principle 34. Discarding and Recovering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Make portions of an object that have fulfilled their functions go away(discard by dissolving, evaporating, etc.) or modify them directly duringoperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flexible, variable-sized project teams
Load/capacity balance using contract labour
Consultants
Contract hire of specialised equipment/facilities, etc
B. Conversely, restore consumable parts of an object directly in operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to periodically re-energise continuous improvement initiatives (‘enthusiasm injections’)
Life-long learning (where individuals are given responsibility for managing their own personal continuing education, ensuring skills remain up to date)
‘In a start-up company, you basically throw out all assumptions every three weeks.’ Scott McNealy
Principle 35. Parameter Changes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Change an object’s physical state (e.g. to a gas, liquid, or solid).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual prototyping
Numerical simulation
Virtual shopping – e.g. Amazon.com
Telephone banking
Electronic voting in elections
B. Change the concentration or consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Six Thinking Hats’ (33)
‘Six Action Shoes’ (35)
Change the team structure (e.g. football teams use substitutes)
Stores introduce ‘special offers’ and other promotions
C. Change the degree of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduce intelligence into on-line catalogues (e.g. first generation catalogues were replicas of previous paper versions, latest generation incorporate search engines, expert systems, etc)
Software with options for ‘beginner’ through to ‘expert’ usage
Moves away from fixed clothing size partitions – e.g. ‘Personal Pairs’ – a customer at a participating store chooses which fabric he/she wants, then is measured. Those measurements are transmitted instantly to a Levi’s plant in Tennessee where the data controls a laser cutter. The bar-coded pieces are stitched on the regular assembly line, and mailed directly to the customer. (The custom Levi’s, which customers love, run about $15 more than off-the-rack ones) (22)
D. Change the temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get customers excited (‘hot’) about the product by giving them ownership of the change
Get employees excited about the future of the company by using full involvement strategic planning, or stock options, or… etc.
‘A fired-up team wins games even if it’s not the best team. A fired-up company can achieve the same result’ (34)
Principle 36. Phase Transitions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Use phenomena occurring during phase transitions. (Awarenessof macro-scale business phenomena)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awareness of the requirements of different stages – conception, birth, development, maturity, retirement – of a project (e.g. shifting manpower requirements, shifting budget requirements).
Transition from a ‘bull’ to a ‘bear’ market.
Tendency to relax after receiving a Quality Award, Innovation Award, etc.
Forming/storming/norming/performing phases of team development – e.g. take advantage of enthusiasm dip during storming-norming (3)
Principle 37. Thermal Expansion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Use thermal expansion (or contraction) of materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If employees are excited (‘hot’) each can do more in the space that expands to exist between them.
‘A fired-up, empowered, appreciated individual will do the work of three who aren’t’ Anon.
‘It seems safe to say that significant discovery, really creative thinking, does not occur with regard to problems about which the thinker is lukewarm’. Mary Henle
B. If thermal expansion is being used, use multiple materials withdifferent coefficients of thermal expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expand or contract marketing efforts depending on the product’s ‘hotness’ – rate of sales and profitability
Personality matching on work-teams
Principle 38. Strong Oxidants (‘Boosted Interactions’)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Replace common air with oxygen-enriched air (enrichedatmosphere)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk and Revenue Sharing Partnerships
Guest speakers at a seminar
Use internal subject matter experts
Use simulations/games instead of lecture-style training
Use case-studies in training
Injection of new-blood/new challenge into a team
B. Replace enriched air with pure oxygen (highlyenriched atmosphere).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider personal chemistry issues when assembling a project team – find people who will spark-off interesting reactions with each other.
Deming’s 4 stages of learning – unconscious incompetence, conscious incompetence, conscious competence, unconscious competence
Focus teams on a single project only (give them an enriched environment full of success factors
‘Leadership is a potent combination of strategy and character. But if you must be without one, be without strategy.’ General H. Norman, Schwartzkopff (17)
Expose air or oxygen to ionizing radiation, D. Use ionized oxygen, E.Replace ozonized (or ionized) oxygen with ozone (atmosphereenriched by ‘unstable’ elements) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corporate Jester
‘Devil’s Advocate’
‘I like Bartok and Stravinsky. It’s a discordant sound and there are discordant sounds inside a company. As president you must orchestrate the discordant sounds into a kind of harmony. But you never want too much harmony. One must cultivate a taste for finding harmony within discord or you will drift away from the forces that keep a company alive’ Takeo Fujisawa, Honda co-founder.
Principle 39. Inert Atmosphere&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Replace a normal environment with an inert one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moves away from the (normal) disruptive performance appraisal, merit award, and reward environment to an (emotionally neutral) more fair system of working practice (36, 37).
‘TRIZ and People’ (38)
Hare Brain, Tortoise Mind (39)
Time-out during negotiation
‘Away-day’s/ team-building days
Corporate Retreats
Operations Room – e.g. for planning organizational change, proposal submissions, contract tendering, etc.
B. Add neutral parts, or inert additives to an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use of neutral third parties during difficult negotiations (e.g. Senator George Mitchell in Northern Ireland, ACAS, etc.)
Introduction of ‘quiet areas’ into the workplace.
Rest breaks/’pause for reflection’ breaks in meetings.
Principle 40. Composite Structures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Change from uniform to composite (multiple) structures.(Awareness and utilisation of combinations of different skills andcapabilities.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-disciplinary project teams.
Do training with a combination of lecture, simulations, on-line learning, video, etc.
Employ different personality types (e.g. Myers-Briggs) on a team
Hard person/soft person negotiating team.
‘Post-capitalist Society’ (40)
‘Small is beautiful’ – appreciation for diverse, interconnected systems (41)
Mix of thinking skills in a project team (e.g. Basadur (4), De Bono’s ‘Six Thinking Hats‘ (33) and ‘Six Action Shoes’ (35))
Positional players in a football team
Combined high risk/low risk investment strategy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/triz,/problem-solving,/40/principles/2017/02/02/TRIZ.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/triz,/problem-solving,/40/principles/2017/02/02/TRIZ.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>TRIZ,</category>
        
        <category>problem-solving,</category>
        
        <category>40</category>
        
        <category>Principles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design For Immunity</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the GOAL of the Design for Immunity project? We might not think about it as much as we should, but ALL of us basically want to boost our immune system.  We all want to be healthier tomorrow than we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is serious about health [and strengthening immunity against all kinds of attacks] knows that there’s a LOT to think about … almost TOO MUCH … so should think about the scope of the project or about what we might focus on FIRST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a SPECIFIC example … to prove the concept in a practical manner that demonstrates how one might incorporate particular interests, I will be look in at how I can learn about designing, building and continuously improving an edible foodscape on small amount of land that house sits on.  This foodscape will need to provides me with all kinds of antioxidants and phytochemicals and raw foods that I not only LIKE, but also are especially conductive to rebuilding my immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a starting point, for getting a general idea of the “lay of the land” for this project, I will attempt curate an AWESOME annotated reading list that looks at things like the types of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cancertutor.com/mirror_lymphoma/&quot;&gt;nutritional programs recommended for those undergoing radiation or chemotherapy or other particular toxic treatments for cancer&lt;/a&gt; … but the background research, derived from curating and annotating a reading list is ONLY for making informed choices about this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MOST important informed choice that I can make about the SCOPE of this particular immunity project is deciding the general strategy that I will use for attacking the opportunity … I will refer to my Design For Immunity approach as a meta-immunity approach … it will be about building the informational infrastructure for continually advancing the PRACTICAL, PERSONAL goal of improving my level of immunity.  To accomplish this, &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; … I recognize the NEED to reach out, build upon what others have done … &lt;em&gt;WE&lt;/em&gt; will be designing a set of cloneable, forkable, open source repositories to construct a dynamic, continuously updatable system that helps people get information and data, learn on their own, build a lifestyle that takes responsibility for caring for ones environment in a way that strengthens immune systems and generally builds health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really about open-sourcing education and aggressively developing ways to tap the power of community knowledge in learn how to live better and healthier, to replace bad habits with healthier ones and steadily build the foundations of things that build immunity to get stronger and stronger, little by little … data APIs, repositories, MOOCs, JUPYTER notebooks, Electron driven messaging like Slack, online conferences [with LIVEstreamed video and more-or-less immediate interaction]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;analytics&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, people will stop playing defense and just being spooked by the #JustWorryAboutIt passive strategies used by conventional healthcare systems … when get serious about [re]building immunity / fitness / productivity, we will recursively develop metrics by measuring, comparing, quantitatively optimizing and then analyzing or tracking improvements in performance. To be sure, healthcare options are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercatus.org/hoap&quot;&gt;tracked and analyzed at the state level&lt;/a&gt;, but where the analytics are really necessary is at the individual level. #DontGetSick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;improvement&quot;&gt;Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improvement is driven by nothing other than disciplined, intelligently-applied, focused EFFORT … analytics can give you idea of where you should focus or how effective parts of your effort has been, eg consider reps, weight, distance, time in an exercise regimen, but they cannot replace EFFORT. There are ways to improve more effectively, but there are no shortcuts, no way around putting in the EFFORT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to be able to envision an explosion of data-driven immunity / fitness / productivity social communities, but it will take real work and sustained effort to build this kind of community … at least as first; one hopes it would be self-sustaining after people realized the benefits of a crowd-driven “buddy system”… somebody needs to LEAD efforts in things like the democratization of genome wide association studies and things made possible by affordable, portable nanopore DNA sequencer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/immunity,/against/disease,/evidence/based/health,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/11/19/Design-Against-Disease.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/immunity,/against/disease,/evidence/based/health,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/11/19/Design-Against-Disease.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>evergreen,</category>
        
        <category>DMAIC,</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>For</category>
        
        <category>Immunity,</category>
        
        <category>Against</category>
        
        <category>Disease,</category>
        
        <category>evidence</category>
        
        <category>based</category>
        
        <category>health,</category>
        
        <category>Arm</category>
        
        <category>Thy</category>
        
        <category>Neighbor</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Against Crime</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the entrant’s into &lt;a href=&quot;http://NIJ.gov/MappingChallenge&quot;&gt;mapping challenge&lt;/a&gt; sponsored by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://NIJ.gov&quot;&gt;Natl Institute of Justice&lt;/a&gt; will probably aim their approach to data science prediction and forecasting at mapping BAD OUTCOMES … and there is a lot to be said for place-based crime forecasting algorithms that look at neighborhoods at [future] risk. Okay, crime is interesting enough … and it is certainly very necessary to get serious about law enforcement and neighborhood watch programs and others ways to deal better with crime, BUT …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… what if instead of playing defense [against something negative like crime], we went on offense and started trying to put POSITIVE points on the board for the GOOD changes that we might be able to effect.  What if we looked instead at the predictors that lead to neighborhoods that DO NOT MAKE the news … is it possible for to change our our thinking to AVOID focusing on the sensationalism and crisis that usually follows things like crime?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it isn’t as simple as just applying a 180 degree reverse policy … we cannot really do the same data analytics on good behaviors as we do on reported data for criminal convictions.  Happiness analytics are much more suspect than crime analytics … since we don’t have numbers on people or communities &lt;em&gt;convicted&lt;/em&gt; of being happy, normal, successful or different things that are the opposite of crime, those who want to engage in happiness analytics must &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; more with the use of imperfect inferential statistical methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONE way of looking at good behavior is how productive [and generally higher-earning] behavior gets monetized into something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/c/house-prices-advanced-regression-techniques&quot;&gt;strong housing prices&lt;/a&gt;. We all know some things about housing already – for example, we know that the age of the something like carpet or even a furnace is going to be orders of magnitude less important than location or proximity to a good school or other community amenities.  AFTER we have prepared our data set [by eliminating obvious outliers in the data], we could BEGIN our exploratory analysis by looking at the different housing districts by using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_forest&quot;&gt;random forest model&lt;/a&gt; in order to assure that we are comparing basically similar neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;analytics&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why just look at Ames … let’s look at ALL real estate in Iowa.  Or the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;improvement&quot;&gt;Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design your COMMUNITY for Maintainability … and the maintainability of better neighbors, better neighborhoods, better public utilities, better civic projects … is important as a [derived] value because maintainability means thinking about other people. That includes the differing valid motives, aptitudes, stage of education and levels of capabilities of OTHER developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about building an social architecture or &lt;em&gt;culturescape&lt;/em&gt; that engenders people in the future [after you are gone] to go about maintaining their ability to be creative, productive, independent and free to protect themselves and advance their just causes [without hurting other people]. Of course, it is NECESSARY that choices about maintainability are voluntary – a good argument with a useful tool should be sufficient to convince most people to go along with a policy – coercion, force and mandates are unnecessary. Controlling others or taking away the independence of others is one of the very most immoral things that anyone can do. Open source code and data are part of this – so are distributed information, defense and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/maintainability,/against/crime,/happiness/analytics,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/10/24/Design-Against-Crime.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/evergreen,/dmaic,/design/for/maintainability,/against/crime,/happiness/analytics,/arm/thy/neighbor/2016/10/24/Design-Against-Crime.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>evergreen,</category>
        
        <category>DMAIC,</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>For</category>
        
        <category>Maintainability,</category>
        
        <category>Against</category>
        
        <category>Crime,</category>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        <category>analytics,</category>
        
        <category>Arm</category>
        
        <category>Thy</category>
        
        <category>Neighbor</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design for Maintainability</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE reason that I am interested in open source is flexibility and extensibility [to a degree] but mostly my interest is about MAINTAINABILITY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintainability does not just spontaneously happen.  Not all that long ago, &lt;strong&gt;it used to be&lt;/strong&gt; [and in some cases still is] true that much, if not most, of the Javascript code hacked together by &lt;em&gt;developers&lt;/em&gt; worldwide is pretty much unmaintainable &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;junk.js&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; … this is not a critique of Javascript or ECMAscript language itself; it is a critique of the sloppy practices that are possible.  Javascript [and simply trusting the Javascript of others or enabling Javascript in the &lt;em&gt;sandbox&lt;/em&gt; represented the web browser] makes lots of crappy, error-prone, spammy and even downright malevolent code possible … but the &lt;em&gt;beauty&lt;/em&gt; [and its potential for sheer evil] of Javascript lies in the combination of ubiquity and expedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it might &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt; but maintenance of the code tends to be a matter of the original developer(s) &lt;em&gt;keeping their heads in the game&lt;/em&gt; and staying engaged to remember how the thing was supposed to work and where the technical debt &lt;em&gt;anti-treasure&lt;/em&gt; or where the treasure troves of dangerous anti-patterns and [intentionally-bad] virus-enabling &lt;em&gt;easter eggs&lt;/em&gt; are buried … in other words, unmaintainable code might expediently &lt;em&gt;get the job done&lt;/em&gt;, but it cannot serve as a foundation.  It definitely should not be something that is built upon, replicated, cloned, widely-distributed … ESPECIALLY when the code includes &lt;em&gt;easter eggs&lt;/em&gt; exploitable weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately the strength of the open source ecosystem is that community includes plenty of really solid computer scientist who understand the reason for producing automate-able tools that serve as antidotes to the creation of new bad Javascript … these professionals in the open source community have recognized that Javascript’s weaknesses are not just a matter of style [as is the case with written documents] but the pervasiveness of bad code replicates even sloppier code – so better practices must be STRONGLY encouraged with tools that do the heavy lifting.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sorrycc/awesome-javascript&quot;&gt;AWESOME transpilers, linters, build tools, pattern repositories for Javascript&lt;/a&gt; and more are constantly being developed, improved and enhanced in the [not always so informal] competition to improve the code of developers around you … but there’s still no substitute for humans who constantly think about maintainability and OTHER USERS … just as there is no substitute for being skeptical of the &lt;em&gt;MAGIC&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;candy&lt;/em&gt; that is distributed based on an intensely widely-used language like Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Guidelines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Placeholder for additional DFM material – tbd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Epilogue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintainability is important as a [derived] value because maintainability means thinking about other people. That includes the differing valid motives, aptitudes, stage of education and levels of capabilities of OTHER developers. It is all about maintaining their ability to be creative, productive, independent and free to protect themselves and advance their just causes [without hurting other people]. Of course, it is NECESSARY that choices about maintainability are voluntary – a good argument with a useful tool should be sufficient to convince most people to go along with a policy – coercion, force and mandates are unnecessary. Controlling others or taking away the independence of others is one of the very most immoral things that anyone can do. Open source code and data are part of this – so are distributed information, defense and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/evergreen,/dfx,/design/for/maintainability/2016/10/18/Design-For-Maintainability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/evergreen,/dfx,/design/for/maintainability/2016/10/18/Design-For-Maintainability.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>evergreen,</category>
        
        <category>Dfx,</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>for</category>
        
        <category>Maintainability</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrity Is Impossible To Achieve Through Imitation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Journalists might &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2015-paul-ford-what-is-code/&quot;&gt;think they know what code is&lt;/a&gt;, but I do not know if journalists are capable of really understanding what code is … or what makes serious software developers or data scientists tick … journalists necessarily reduce the world to what they can understand well enough to write about and that is a very serious limitation on what Reality really is. If you want to understand what code is, you need to emigrate to the world of code and live in it, you cannot understand code by reading what journalists write about it … at best, you can only understand what journalists think about something … the function of media and journalism is not so much to inform as it is to condition the herd of pliant bovines who look to others for their opinions and their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do know is that that if you are going to follow the herd, you’re going to eat a lot of dust and feel terrified a lot of time for no good reason whatsoever … because terrorizing or titillating an audience sells [electronic] papers and there’s an enormous amount of competition in this world to stand out in terrorism or titillation, so the herd gets conditioned. There are herds of people intent on following Trump, following the #NeverTrump movement, following Hillary … all move in lock step with one another and have a variety of ways of whipping other members of the herd into delusional frenzies.  Human beings are much more stupid when they are in herds … if you believe that there is even a RISK of your being in a herd, you really need to change and be your own person. If YOU don’t look out for your integrity, no one else will … there is nothing wrong with being gregarious, outgoing and friendly … there are many benefits to things like voluntary standards and respecting the beliefs, customs, conventions and social norms others … we can certainly learn from others, but &lt;strong&gt;integrity is impossible to achieve through imitation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot fathom why the herd imagines that Presidential elections matter … the population of people that vote for a President matters [because we all must conduct our lives and businesses with those people], but the actual election does not matter.  With the exception of Ronald Reagan [but only, because he was my Commander-In-Chief in 1981-1983, when I was a Federal agent, still deluded by the prospects of a career in public service and his policies thus inordinately, pathologically affected me] no President has actually mattered in terms of how I conduct my life.  I don’t expect that the next one will matter either; I almost want to be proven wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The herd definitely WANTS Presidential elections to matter … because the herd WANTS to be led … the herd desperately needs to find a leader it can believe it, a leader with integrity … because no one in the herd can lead or think for themselves, no one in the herd has a shred of integrity – they have demonstrated time and again that they do not know integrity when integrity slaps them in the face. The want their integrity to go after someone else … they want a “leader” who will blame &lt;em&gt;the other&lt;/em&gt;, the immigrant, the jew, the nigger, the irredeemable, deplorable misogynist. The herd cannot and does not want to know.  The herd cannot and does not want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why the herd imagines that Presidential elections matter … the herd cannot adapt, the herd NEEDS a President who will restrict the ability of citizens to be informed, the herd NEEDS a President who will restrict the ability of citizens to defend themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be part of the herd; you can choose to be part of the minority of people who can think for themselves and defend themselves and therefore are not afraid those who share information … including information on how to produce weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is much more to be hoped for in an excess of information or of weapons than in the restriction of information or arms control.”&lt;/em&gt; — Jean Baudrillard … from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;epigraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Cody Wilson’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Come-Take-Printers-Guide-Thinking-ebook/dp/B01CO34MBI/&quot;&gt;Come and Take It: The Gun Printer’s Guide to Thinking Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/integrity/2016/10/12/Priorities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/integrity/2016/10/12/Priorities.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>integrity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Knowledge Prospecting and Data-Intensive Economies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is said that travel helps one to find new perspectives, prospect for new interests, meet new friends … and although I believe that could not be more true, I also believe that traveling for the sake of traveling, or crossing places visited off some sort of bucket list, is mostly a non-value-added activity that involves shipping a live body around the planet. Of course, we all know that there ARE interactions and experiences that you simply cannot have in a virtual realm, but the fact of the matter is that information, communication and VR technologies are raising the level of what can be experienced virtually, while the expenses, difficulties and uncertainties of travel are basically unchanged. When the relative costs change, it is necessary to reallocate resources … and this applies just as much to the area of knowledge prospecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For SOME, this means that they can accomplish more in less time … affording MORE time for travel – but for people like me, it means that I can accomplish more [knowledge prospecting] in less time AND because of that I can engage in more pure knowledge prospecting, [scientific] content consumption, data analysis AND I can &lt;strong&gt;do more walking, biking, and GARDENING outdoors&lt;/strong&gt; rather than being cooped up in car, plane or hotel room. In essence, writing code, analyzing data and working remotely, as well as being more engaged in more relationships FROM A DISTANCE allows me to spend more time time getting dirt under my fingernails as I have more time for serious investigation of soil ecosystems and using/developing laboratory tools things like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nanoporetech.com/applications/metagenomics&quot;&gt;GWAS metagenomics and nanopore DNA sequencing technology&lt;/a&gt; in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for me to do this, it is still very much necessary for me to travel in a virtual sense … to learn new skills for communication with others … and, beyond that, to extend and develop new tools for traveling even further … because the revolution in the ability to prospect for knowledge in a virtual fashion is only just beginning … it will change as more and more people adapt and the network effects create new opportunities … in the same way, that personal computers … then client-server networked computers … and the internet and world wide web … and social media, mobile and wireless technologies have changed how people prospect for information and begin to travel virtually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no different than cooking or firing a kiln with fire … or floating or rolling a log then building boats and things that use wheels … or finding that keeping an edge on sharp tools improves with hard metals … or domesticating and breeding plants and animals …  it will be always be necessary for humans to pick up knowledge in realms where they have none … developing and extending new tools makes it possible to explore new realms of knowledge which require the development and extension of new tools … chickens » eggs  »  omelettes and other recipes  »  nutrition and health  »  scientific methods and innovation  » data-intensive economies and extensible open source DevOps … the source of code/technology has to be written for OTHER developers who ultimately will extend the paradigm AND also to accomplish the [OBVIOUS] immediate specific goal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/problem/solving,/extensibility/2016/10/08/Prospecting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/problem/solving,/extensibility/2016/10/08/Prospecting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>problem</category>
        
        <category>solving,</category>
        
        <category>extensibility</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fighting Fires</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You will see all kinds of articles that … instead of inspiring people to work with their communities, neighbors and friends to solve problems … call for people to look to a bigger role for government (e.g. “There oughta be a law to …”).  For example, you might see headlines that say something like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/murders-rose-at-their-fastest-pace-in-a-quarter-century-last-year/&quot;&gt;Murders Rose At Their Fastest Pace In A Quarter Century Last Year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s PARTIALLY true, but it is grossly misleading … murders did NOT increase EVERYWHERE; murders did not increase in MOST jurisdictions where MOST Americans live.  The AVERAGE murder rate for America increased because it increased DRAMATICALLY in SOME jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at the data, we can test certain hypotheses and the data do provide answers … but those answers raise new questions.  That is exactly what getting to root cause is all about.  When the data furnishes an answer, we ordinarily have to ask, &lt;em&gt;“But, WHY did that happen?”&lt;/em&gt;  In fact, the need to asks several levels of WHY is not the exception, it is THE RULE. Experience teaches us that for any particular problem, it is necessary to use data AND to ask &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys&quot;&gt;five levels of WHY&lt;/a&gt; … beyond just drilling down to get simplistic answers, it is necessary to understand the complex cause-and-effect nature of the problem, i.e. we cannot quit solving the problem until we have populated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ishikawa_diagram&quot;&gt;full Ishikawa fishbone diagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In jurisdictions with smaller governments, murders and crimes have decreased … murders and all other crimes have certainly decreased in rather dramatic fashion in those towns/cities/rural areas that have VOLUNTEER fire departments. Crime increases [in some jurisdictions] where people trust and depend upon their governments more and instead of being involved, just feel entitled to government providing for them. It’s NOT a Democratic or Republican thing; it’s NOT an income or poverty thing, even though we ALL know that the ultra-rich always have hired thugs to take care of their things in their sterile, locked-down, &lt;em&gt;lifeless&lt;/em&gt; RICH &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;compounds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – driving down crime for REAL living human beings is primarily about how INVOLVED or ENGAGED people are in their communities, ie do citizens tolerate the &lt;strong&gt;persistence&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;em&gt;broken windows&lt;/em&gt; in their community [because &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; windows get broken everywhere that windows are] OR do they tend to do something about solving community problems together?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to drill down, to REALLY look at the data to see EXACTLY where the breakdown is happening – things are NOT breaking down everywhere. According to NYU Law School’s Brennan Center for Justice, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brennancenter.org/publication/crime-2016-preliminary-analysis&quot;&gt;murder rate in cities is up 13% in 2016&lt;/a&gt; … which is an alarming start of [what hopefully is NOT] a pattern of a double-digit increase on top of another double-digit increase … since murders in the U.S. jumped by 10.8% in 2015, according to FBI data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, there is a LOT of good news in crime data – GENERALLY speaking, in most jurisdictions, crime has been really low and been falling even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t live in an area where crime is falling … well … you and your community are doing it wrong … and the data prove that you are doing it wrong.  If you don’t like the conclusion, go argue with the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the FBI recorded violent crime narrowly falling, by 0.2%. In 2015, the number of violent crimes rose 3.9% and the number of property crimes dropped 2.6% … while crime is dropping in much of the country, and even in some urban environments … but in 44 of the 65 largest police agencies in 2015, the murder rate increased. There are some cities, like Baltimore, DC, Louisville, Chicago, St. Louis, Omaha, Houston and LA where things are seriously screwed-up … compared to the rest of the country, those 44 urban police jurisdictions are bad enough by themselves to significantly raise the murder rates on average for the ENTIRE country … in spite of decreases in MOST of the nation.  It is interesting that the very worst, i.e. Chicago [labeled by some as an “outlier”] are enough to counter the trend of the rest of the nation … and it will get worse before it gets better because there are some “community organizers” out there who are NOT really providing any leadership, but instead are blaming the police and failing to look at the root cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to find the ROOT CAUSE for what is driving the crime increase in some urban hell-holes, here’s a HINT … it AIN’T the police doing the killing … or looting the Walmarts after a riot … or exploiting the unrest and riots for political gain by calling for more protests and riots, ie protests and riots are NOT going to help with what is primarily a self-inflicted problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guess is that it’s like fighting fire … which is MOSTLY about recognizing fire hazards, doing things to DE-ESCALATE the hazard level and making sure that the people you hang around with are also not idiots when it comes to escalation of risk … idiots who play with fire must not be defended and certainly should not be celebrated [or even mourned] when the idiots die in a fire they started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fighting fire is MOSTLY about behaviors … but fire does happen, so fire extinguishers matter … the problem with fires is much less where fire extinguishers are ubiquitous and EVERYONE takes ownership when it comes to preventing fires and calling out idiotic behavior that might lead to fire.  Sometimes things do happen – that’s why EVERYONE has know exactly where several different fire extinguishing devices, water, blankets are and EVERYONE knows how to help put out a fire because they had hands-on training using one within the last year … in other words, if you live in a city with lots of immature, irresponsible, unsupervised uber-entitled children [regardless of what age they are] are running around with gas cans and fire-starting kits expecting the adults in fire departments to put out the fires, your city is going to BURN DOWN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to situations where things are engulfed in flame and BURNING DOWN … even in relatively small fires … another part of fighting fire is about EXIT.  That means there is no good that comes from be being the stupid amateur hero, puts on his superhero cape and CONFRONTS the fire that is already out-of-control.  In other words, back away from the blaze, call in the professionals and do NOT complicate the problem the professionals have to solve by becoming part of the situation.  Do NOT be a hero unless you are a TRAINED PROFESSIONAL who is PAID to develop all of the skills necessary to be a hero, ie support your Fire Dept folks, support your police.  The thing to do with an out-of-control fire is to GET AWAY and let the professionals decide what to do … don’t be too surprised if they decide to let the fire burn what it’s going to burn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/crime,/root/cause/analysis/2016/09/28/Fighting-Fires.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/crime,/root/cause/analysis/2016/09/28/Fighting-Fires.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>crime,</category>
        
        <category>root</category>
        
        <category>cause</category>
        
        <category>analysis</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are the most important technologies for accelerated learning?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe the most important thing is encouragement and nudging people to be TOUGH enough to fit in, to naturalize, assimilate, adapt enough to thrive and not only become native but to produce something of importance or beauty for others in the ecosystem, like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/y/2rpqQTs&quot;&gt;muscari armeniacum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to &lt;em&gt;become native&lt;/em&gt; and then transcend that by producing things of real value?  It is probably a matter of LOVE, commitment and extreme ownership – that means really &lt;em&gt;OWNING&lt;/em&gt; every problem (ie opportunity) that other people run away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;at your own pace&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;on your own&lt;/em&gt; is NEVER really a matter of &lt;em&gt;going it entirely alone&lt;/em&gt; … the best way to really learn or even master something is to teach it to someone else … there are ways to apply the benefits of exposure and network effects, to encourage meaningful social interaction, to elicit others to be involved in progress, to participate in the code code graph, to not just participate but to take on the effort as their own, to hack it, to extend it for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me think about applying the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FreeCodeCamp/FreeCodeCamp&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; method to the natural HARD sciences … it goes beyond mere coding, but coding is extremely important for building tools that explore relationships … like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neo4j.com/use-cases/real-time-recommendation-engine/&quot;&gt;graph databases&lt;/a&gt; and building a tool to find shared knowledge connections or what might be described as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ILjTikVhT9k&quot;&gt;topical interest recommendation engine&lt;/a&gt; … for example, what kinds of understanding can we bring together to give us new frontiers to explore in understanding an aspect of soil ecosystem health and nutritional pathways … of course, understanding informs the approach we use in looking for data … sometimes we simply need to gather a lot more data now, perhaps we can get lots of macro photos (although macro photos are important and there are better technologies for micro and even nano level photography), but also we also think about things like sequential or time-lapse longitudinal panel data gathering, but we can also explore other tools like DNA chips for nutritional genomics of different species in different ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should think about how superheros like us build and use tools … and then use those tools to build and use better tools … and how the incremental daily improvement might not seem all that significant, but when we look back we see how incredibly much things have CHANGED in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lyDLAutA88s&quot;&gt;the last 20 years of building tools to munge data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning,/acceleration/2016/09/24/Evolutionary-Advance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning,/acceleration/2016/09/24/Evolutionary-Advance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning,</category>
        
        <category>acceleration</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WHY won&#39;t updates to GitHub pages load immediately [or with the same latency]?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of LITTLE … and some times, not so little … things that impact your workflow on GitHub … and it’s up to YOU to stay engaged, to have a degree of situational awareness … perhaps patiences … perhaps an understanding of what you need to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgot about what you might believe … you simply are NOT &lt;strong&gt;entitled&lt;/strong&gt; to help from anyone else … including even GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now … the folks at GitHub probably want to help you, but there might be impediments to IMMEDIATELY serving you … maybe you haven’t phrased your question intelligently or in a manner that fits their jargon and linguistic realm … maybe there are problems with people who supply services to them; maybe they have their own glitches or bugs or issues … there are all kinds of reasons why the latency of their service might vary.  It’s not a perfect world.  And, even though we probably should not FIRST suspect malicious intent, since it’s so much more likely that OTHER things are driving actions, there ARE indeed very malevolent actors out there – not just hackers who want to take down a service like Github for their own idiotic purposes, but maybe’s it WORSE … like some EVIL national security agency of a totalitarian regime of thugs might be forcing Github to supply data or obstruct free speech.  We have reasons for why we should LOVE Github, but … even if their intentions are better, purer, smarter than anyone else’s … you simply are NOT &lt;strong&gt;entitled&lt;/strong&gt; to expect IMMEDIATE help from anyone else … including GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIRST thing to look at is your own [lack of CURRENT] knowledge about your own set-up … for example … recently, I was working on a blog with the same Atom Editor and GitHub Desktop tools I’ve come to know and love … and use somewhat successfully [for my modest purposes] … using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as a SIMPLE blog-aware static &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/github-pages/&quot;&gt;GH pages&lt;/a&gt; site generator on my laptop … good ol’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000&quot;&gt;127.0.0.1:4000&lt;/a&gt; looked as current and good [ie what I expected to see] as ever … there had been no error messages from the editor or desktop app … I had up to date version of each … the updated pages were in Github’s repo and I could see them on Github’s website … but Github was not loading my updated pages for some reason!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO IT WAS TIME FOR ME TO RELAX and spend a couple minutes RELEARNING SOME STUFF … I had used the Github pages MAGIC and &lt;em&gt;it just worked&lt;/em&gt; … like MAGIC … I didn’t need to know AND I didn’t know some key portions of the magic … I had trusted Github TOO MUCH … I know better … you cannot trust ANYONE, even people who are on your side and do not want to deliberate screw up your workflow … that includes even Github … most importantly YOU CANNOT PLACE ALL OF YOUR FAITH MAGIC YOU DON’T UNDERSTAND … if you’re going to rely on magic, at least build in some redundancies, just in case, things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/configuring-a-publishing-source-for-github-pages/&quot;&gt;how GitHub serve pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2228-simpler-github-pages-publishing&quot;&gt;how they have recently updated it do it NOW&lt;/a&gt; don’t perform as you think they will, when you need a service to perform for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I didn’t need to change or fix anything … it was JUST an issue of LATENCY … for some reason, GitHub was not IMMEDIATELY updating the blogs it hosts as rapidly as it usually does. So … yeah … I did not learn as much about Git and GitHub behind-the-scenes internal magic as I &lt;em&gt;should have&lt;/em&gt; learned … but the search and the serendipitous things that I did learn made it ALL WORTHWHILE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that if you rely upon Github … and you probably should rely on GitHub … and the larger GitHub community … at least, you should &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; rely on them and even if you are a competitor of them, you should pay attention because Github is pretty good at what they do, especially the &lt;em&gt;network effects&lt;/em&gt; stuff … even for things that are not mission-critical for &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; mission, but if your mission involves developing software, content, data science or building any form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/awesome&quot;&gt;AWESOME&lt;/a&gt; knowledge, the fully network-effected social distributed version control that Github does is critical for your level of situational awareness … you really NEED to be reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog&quot;&gt;GitHub blog&lt;/a&gt;, following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/github&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/GitHubGuides&quot;&gt;Github Guides&lt;/a&gt; channels on YouTube and maybe even attending and definitely paying attention to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://githubuniverse.com/program/&quot;&gt;program&lt;/a&gt; of topics and speakers &lt;a href=&quot;http://githubuniverse.com/&quot;&gt;at GitHub conferences&lt;/a&gt; … you really should have an awareness of &lt;a href=&quot;https://octoverse.github.com/&quot;&gt;what is going on at GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and in the companies involved in providing distributed version control like [Git] … after all, the whole toolchain and different services that you rely on for source control are kind of a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/relearning,/trust/2016/09/21/The-Tao-of-Github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/relearning,/trust/2016/09/21/The-Tao-of-Github.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>relearning,</category>
        
        <category>trust</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
