<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns Tech Blog</title>
    <description>This is my blog about version-controlled social production of open source technology ... feel free to reach out to me and tell me how I can be of service to you!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 13:14:26 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 13:14:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why go to Mars when there are fungi here we haven&#39;t met yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding herbicide transformation is necessary for pesticide development for their safe and efficient use, as well as for developing pesticide bioremediation strategies for contaminated soil and water. Recent studies persuasively demonstrated the key role of soil white-rot fungi in biotransformation of various anthropogenic environmental contaminants. However, often this common knowledge is not associated with specific metabolic processes of fungi and therefore cannot be transformed into specific recommendations for agricultural practice.  Beyond just bioremediation of pollutants, think about how much more we don’t know about building and conditioning of soils for optimal productivity?  If we are so smart about soils, what stops us from making it possible for everyone to be surrounded by a luxurious garden and living foodscape?  The answer is that we are most decidedly NOT THAT SMART when it comes to soils and everything that soils could offer us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course oceans are very important, but since most humans live on land, human life is almost entirely based on what soil ecosystems – I have no problem whatsoever with people disagreeing with me on the importance of soils, as long as they back up their argument with actions and agree to move PERMANENTLY offshore.  Soil should be the most important topic for humans to be knowledgable about.  Many people [erroneously] believe that the largest problem facing humanity involves carbon in the atmosphere … whether this is a concern or not, these people seem to completely ignore that 2,700 Gt of C stored in soils worldwide.  As almost all knowledgable gardeners or farmers would tell you, they would like to have more … MUCH more … organic material in their soil.  As anyone who loves growing things, anyone who loves having dirt under their fingernails, knows and there is a capacity to double, triple or quadruple the soil organic carbon in most soils under cultivation or in human use.  This is significant because there is only 780 Gt of C is in the atmosphere and a small percentage of humans believe that it should be three-quarters of that amount … 200 Gt of C is less than one-tenth of C stored in C-deficient soils worldwide. Even if we assume that world’s oceans cannot be managed as a carbon sink [which is slightly debatable, but perhaps true because of property rights issues] it becomes clear that carbon “problem” should be thought of as a soil issue. We can do a much better job of utilizing our soils for a variety of different issues – better knowledge of soils not only solves the carbon  issue, adding soil organic carbon will improve soil quality and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTHER issue with soil ecosystems involves essential compounds like antibiotics that originated from studies of soils.  People fail to realize how fundamentally these discoveries have transformed human existence … the real problem with this fundamental ignorance is the lack of understanding that we have only just scratched the surface.  We do not understand a tenth or even one-percent of what soil ecosystems have to offer … we do not even understand enough to know how small the fraction of that one-percent is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of how incomplete our knowledge is, consider how soil has, for millions of years, provides the environment for many different fungal species. These different species play an absolutely role in recycling nutrients through decay and breaking down of materials. Of course, these fungi produce different compounds [many essential for other species] in their digestive process but they do not just recycle nutrients by digest decaying plant matter. Fungi are attacked by bacteria which favor the same growing conditions and food stocks, but molds have defense mechanisms such as antimicrobial agents that prevent of the bacteria from making new cell walls and reproducing … as Penicillium chrysogenum … the ability of P. chrysogenum to produce antimicrobial agent penicillin appears to have evolved over hundreds of thousands or millions of years in soils in damp, consistent temperature environments in temperate and subtropical regions [which also favor bacterial growth]. Even though most humans now take penicillin for granted … few know that the sexual stage of P. chrysogenum was discovered only a few years ago, in 2013, by mating cultures in the dark on oatmeal agar supplemented with biotin, after the mating types (MAT1-1 or MAT1-2) of the strains had been determined using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction&quot;&gt;PCR&lt;/a&gt; amplification … the tools and technologies to do meaningful things are still being invented, as we stumble into things that we can’t “see” yet …  so we really don’t even know that much at all yet about how we would begin to set up practical methods to select and breed what has been one of the most important fungi to human beings … but others species, with uses we haven’t really discovered or conceived of yet, are almost necessarily more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When one considers that approximately 70,000 fungal species have been described, but the total number of fungal species is estimated to be well over 1.5 million and then one begins to understand that human beings have only begun to select and breed a very limited number of these fungal species for specific compounds and uses … when we factor in the chemical, bacterial, plant and animal interactions inside our soil ecosystems … it becomes almost painfully clear that our knowledge of soil ecosystems is teensy, especially in comparison to the human-scale crops and livestock that humans developed and perfected for over ten thousand years before even understanding that things like bacteria and fungi existed. Part of the lack of understanding is scale – in order to really understand micro interactions, it’s necessary to be able to observe at the nano scale. But it’s also matter of understanding ecosystem complexities, co-evolution and inventing new approaches, eg, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction&quot;&gt;PCR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metagenomics&quot;&gt;metagenomics&lt;/a&gt;, to explore how and why the microbial world of soil ecosystems works the way it does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bioremediation,</category>
        
        <category>antibiotics,</category>
        
        <category>enzymes,</category>
        
        <category>metagenomics,</category>
        
        <category>soil</category>
        
        <category>ecosystems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Antifragile Government</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been watching and re-watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civilization:_Is_the_West_History%3F&quot;&gt;Niall Ferguson’s series on the six killer apps of Western Civilization&lt;/a&gt;. As I have been watching this program, I have also been thinking and reading supporting historical materials with an eye to understanding the demise of different empires and I am almost dumbfounded by the degree to which most people in great empires have always tended to forget the importance of their empire’s foundations, what made them great in the first place.  Thus, I completely agree with the whole premise of the show and highly recommend that others watch and re-watch the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot know if the number of “killer apps” is exactly six or the degree to which these “apps” are interrelated and basically share other deeper dependencies, but six killer apps is probably a good way for framing the discussion.  I believe that we should emphasize some things about those apps differently – the show [like any show broadcast for popular consumption] was constructed [or watered down] TO BE POPULAR and thus avoid any controversy or appearance of toughness or antifragility that would cause people to dismiss the entire show or even question the BBC, Ferguson and those funding the production of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I don’t face the same “lowest-common-denominator” constraint that Ferguson and the BBC did in 2011, so I can state that the six killer apps that made western civilization more antifragile, thus likely to gain from the disorder of history are: 1) intense competition [as a substitute for war], 2) the scientific method and widespread practical discovery, research and debugging, especially outside of academia or domains coercively dominated by the church, governments or similar political/religious institutions, 3) property rights and the Constitutional rule of law [providing the foundation for economic/cultural mobility within the republic and the world], 4) evidence-based environmental health and safety, awareness of fitness [for greater productivity and discipline by key individuals] and some key medical technologies, 5) free markets providing creative destruction of less efficient businesses and diverse alternatives for consumers and employees, 6) freedom of religious or philosophical thought [which underpins the motivation for things like a strong work ethic].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I DISAGREE rather strongly with Ferguson on his conclusion, that we simply need to believe in ourselves … we do need understand our history; that need is what drives Ferguson’s conclusion, as well as his occupational choice … so it’s rather obvious that Ferguson’s conclusion is a HISTORIAN’s conclusion.  That would be fine, but to simply believe in ourselves, to revel in our own greatness … or, what is now, PAST greatness, PAST conquests, PAST victories … might work for a popular show on television, but as a practical operational code, it will create a bunch of backward-looking pride-filled entitled, but impotent little monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom of religion and the philosophical quest still matters … not for experts, academics, high-priests – but for EVERY SINGLE PERSON. It is necessary to understand that the important part of “freedom of religion” is the FREEDOM part … freedom of inquiry, freedom to doubt, freedom to question … but we should acknowledge the practical necessity of having some sort of a belief system. Demanding that everyone must give up their religion is nothing more than demanding conformance to a belief in giving up religion.  One form of zealotry is as EVIL as another. History is replete with examples of the oppression and then stagnation that comes from conformity or uniformity in adherence to any religion or absence or religion (eg, Atheism or ~absence of religion~ and unquestioning faith in authoritarian communist State was the state religion of the USSR).  Freedom of religion serves the purpose of looking forward, for the quest for appropriate vision. As a practical matter all humans must heuristically believe in some higher power, a greater good, a larger agenda or philosophical objective to aspire to and motivate practical plans and SMART goals for conquering the next frontier … it is entirely illogical, meaningless, circular happy talk to tell people we must aspire to believe in ourselves or our pasts … we must look forward.  That means believing in Reality as it really is, not as we hope it might be, fear it might be or as others want us to believe it might be.  We must OPTIMISTICALLY see Reality as our friend; Reality is the ONLY reason we are here. Reality is the ONLY way forward. Instead of boastfully believing in ourselves, I believe that we should humbly seek to understand Reality as it really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our future Reality involves crisis, probably greater crisis than we have experienced at any time in the last two-thirds of a century. It is becoming increasingly apparent some sort of really serious breakdown in the American government is almost certain, perhaps sooner rather than later.  If it is sooner, then something like even civil war [or at least a declaration of martial law, suspension of Constitutional rights] will be likely within the next decade. I am optimistic because I believe that disruption and chaos can be extremely transformative opportunities for human growth. That absolutely does NOT mean that they are easy; it means than disruption and growth is far, far better than stagnation and drudgery. We are heading into very interesting times; these times will not be one bit easy at all; people will suffer and die and wish for less interesting times BUT tough times are necessary to shed weakness, lay the foundation for future post-traumatic growth. There are those who will believe with their full hearts and souls that these times are “end times” but WE humans do not get to decide when THE END is … it is far more likely that these are simply extremely difficult times that will push us and everything about our human institutions harder than we can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to understanding the way forward lies in understanding the essential nature of antifragility and things that gain from disorder and chaos. Small things, like cockroaches, fungus or bacteria, gain from chaos and that applies to our institutions. It is the increasingly centralized nature of our institutions that makes them and the populations that depend upon them weak. The problems of centralization cannot be solved through the same modes of command-and-control thinking that created them. Instead, antifragile solutions will require distributed innovation from decentralized, diverse populations of freethinking innovators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human species can endure far more than any human would ever want to because although herds of dependent humans who look to experts are weak, independent humans who look to their direct experience and Reality-driven knowledge are antifragile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/government/2016/08/17/Antifragile-Government.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/government/2016/08/17/Antifragile-Government.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Government</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pine64</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My Pine64 boards showed up last week … actually before I expected to receive them … I have come to expect people who organize and run crowdfunding campaigns for hardware underestimate how difficult it will be to meet any significant project deadline … hardware is HARD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/kickstarter/2016/06/05/Pine64.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kickstarter/2016/06/05/Pine64.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>KickStarter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lean Government</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people believe in government in the same way that four-year-olds believe in Santa Claus.  They believe because the rest of the human species has lied to them and it has never occurred to them that they had a choice in questioning their belief in government.  So governments persist … for the same reason that any group of four-year-olds will persist in their belief in Santa Claus – nothing will derail that that belief, because the four-year-olds WANT to believe in Santa … governments persist because people DESPERATELY, HOPELESSLY, UNFAILINGLY need to believe in governments [because deep down, they’re all little kids who still really WANT to believe in Santa].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments have ALWAYS existed to protect the interests of already powerful, wealthy and general affluence who want to preserve their power and wealth … there’s nothing especially dark or conspiratorial going here – government is MOSTLY just a matter of preserving the rules of the game, eg the currency in your wallet can be spent; if you buy a car, you get title to the car to prove you own it … but we should remember that the already powerful have the inside track on preserving and EXPANDING their power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does technology have to do with it?  Technology is inherently DISRUPTIVE of power … even though powerful and wealthy citizens are good at investing in [and sometimes subverting] technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But technology can also disrupt the inefficiencies that the powerful exploit to control government. Government does not have to be inefficient … even if the gross inefficiency of government will probably be what ultimately brings about the mass annihilation of all humans and other lifeforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government does not have to be coercive … believe it or not, instead of broadcasting propaganda to the masses, a government could actually LISTEN to what individual human beings want in order to boost the efficiency of government.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/government/2016/03/24/Lean-Government.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/government/2016/03/24/Lean-Government.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Government</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prediction Markets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe much in polls anymore … it’s not just that the polling data is limited to the people who are in the phone database of the pollsters; most people really HATE to be polled and accordingly have all kinds of incentives for telling pollsters everything other than the truth just so that the pollster will leave them alone.  The big reason that I detest polls is the euphoric over-reaction that people have following media hype and mainstream media news coverage – TEMPORARILY hot candidates do much better in polls than prediction markets.  Prediction market traders see past the hype and discount for future success and/or failure, not just current standing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in prediction markets because prediction markets are driven by knowledgable people who want to trade or bet real hard-earned cash on their insights.  As we might expect prediction markets are extremely accurate indication of where the electorate is at a given time – the prediction markets result from election day almost always matches up exactly with the final result before the networks have called the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s look at prediction markets … first look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/politics/2016RepNomination&quot;&gt;current GOP Presidential nomination race&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4174&quot;&gt;September 8 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Bush appears to be weak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4184&quot;&gt;September 16 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Trump, Rubio … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4187&quot;&gt;September 17 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4212&quot;&gt;September 27 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4222&quot;&gt;October 4 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Rubio is sliding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4234&quot;&gt;October 11 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Bush, Rubio, Trump … the Establishment front-runner Bush has been almost overtaken by Rubio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4247&quot;&gt;October 18 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Bush, Trump  … the Establishment front-runner is now Rubio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4263&quot;&gt;October 25 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Bush, Trump … Bush continues to slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4277&quot;&gt;November 1 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Bush … Bush is overtaken by Trump&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4290&quot;&gt;November 8 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Cruz … Bush is overtaken by Cruz who has 12%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4305&quot;&gt;November 15 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Cruz … Rubio climbs to 48%, Trump 19%, Cruz 13%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4314&quot;&gt;November 22 2105&lt;/a&gt; …  Rubio, Trump, Cruz … Rubio still at 48%, Trump 22% (which may be Trump’s peak), Cruz 13%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4325&quot;&gt;November 29 2105&lt;/a&gt; … Rubio, Trump, Cruz … the Establishment front-runner Rubio appears to have peaked at 48%, Trump 24%, Cruz 14%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.predictwise.com/node/4340&quot;&gt;December 6 2105&lt;/a&gt; …  Rubio, Trump, Cruz … the Establishment front-runner Rubio at 40% is sliding, Trump at 27% (which also may be Trump’s peak), Cruz at 15%&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/markets/2015/12/24/Prediction-Markets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/markets/2015/12/24/Prediction-Markets.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Markets</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to Reinvent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a starter list … read it over, agree/disagree, change it, improve it, reinvent your own list for reinventing yourself.  This one is mine [in its current revision]; I &lt;em&gt;plageurized, cheated, stole&lt;/em&gt; and reinvented it after reading and re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2013/12/the-ultimate-cheat-sheet-for-reinventing-yourself-2/&quot;&gt;James Altucher’s THE ULTIMATE CHEAT SHEET FOR REINVENTING YOURSELF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A) Learn to &lt;em&gt;plageurize, cheat, steal&lt;/em&gt; but make the REINVENTION your OWN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OWN your life. Put that life together with the free stuff that you find laying around, but do not just accumulate a pile of junk.  Shaping the stuff that you have laying around into your reinvented future takes ingenuity, vision and EFFORT.  Fixing and polishing your reinvented life is not easy before it is a success; get used to being second-guessed and disrepected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B) Worry about NOW. 5S your life. Focus on your health, your breathing, your diet, the small details.  Fall in love with the person you are becoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by moving the needle on your level of fitness and productivity, so that you have more time and energy to tackle other areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take baby steps, but program yourself each day to have better habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C) Reinvention never stops … start today, but realize that you cannot reinvent yourself in a month or a year, you need to work a five-year plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’a all about the Plan-Do-Check-Act cycle. Every day, every week, every month, every year you need to invest a small amount of time in checking your progress doing what you’ve planned, taking action to bring your performance in line with the plan, then re-calibrating the plan and doing it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a description of what you might expect in the five year plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year One: you are flailing, drinking from the firehose, reading and absorbing everything, you are learning fast, but you’re a like baby … life is tough.
Year Two: you are still “selling snake oil” but know who you need to talk to and network with, i.e. you understand the movers, dice, cards and board layout of your new game.
Year Three: your plan is good enough to start making some money, but it isn’t anything to brag about and probably is not a living yet.
Year Four: your plan is providing an okayish living
Year Five: your plan is starting to compound and give you indications that it might generate real wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it works better, faster than that, great … but don’t expect and prepare yourself mentally for it to be worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D) Give everything away; ditch your baggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanna be more effing tough, you need to develop the SKILLS to be able to continually start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screw pride! Waste your time in dick measuring contests and your core competency is LOSING dick measuring contests. #TheresAlwaysABiggerDick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E) You need a mentor of some sort another.  You also need to mentor others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of mentors; here are three archetypes … there are more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Respected master. Be EXTREMELY CAREFUL. Do NOT join a cult. Certainly do no seek to be a cult leader … be careful when others follow you.
2) Indirect. Books, podcasts, vlogs, blogs, social media
3) Ordinary “average joe.””  Everyone has unique skill, knowledge about something. Every person could be your mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F) Program yourself to not be passive and programmed, be more skeptical, ask more questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THINK! Become a listening leader – seek out people who are DIFFERENT than you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G) Be more humble. You are not humble enough right now, you will be humiliated. Get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think you can reinvent yourself easier, faster, better or without giving up everything – then you too damned arrogant, too full of pride, not really ready, willing or able to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do NOT succumb to your own PR and start imagining that you walk on water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H) It’s not about the money … well, okay to some degree it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people say “it’s not about the money” they should make sure they have a different measuring stick; money is not a bad measuring stick to start with, but you need a better WHY than just money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about just doing what you love?” There will be many days when you don’t love what you are doing. If you are doing it just for love then it will take much much longer than five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is just a positive perception from our brain. Some days you will be unhappy. Our brain is a tool we use. It’s not who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I) When can you say, “I do X!” where X is your new career or your new enterprise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J) When can I start doing X?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read … listen to mentors, but don’t waste all day reading.
Write … dream, but don’t spend all day dreaming … write down your dreams and start sketching out a plan.
Plan-Do-Check-Act … start spec-ing out the idea for your business/life. Get going today. Get up tomorrow and do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K) How will this business or new life of mine ever make money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, it won’t you will have to scramble for a couple years, working at other jobs or somehow scraping together the money to live on and begin starting your business.  Starting a business necessarily involves doing OTHER things … full-time … stop believing that you are entitled to be carried while you start your business … you don’t get to watch televison or relax anymore if you want to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first “alpha” year, you must reconceive your customer – to do this you have to work doing the research to develop a competitive situational awareness in your niche to understand what you will need to do to be one of the best 200-300 people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second “beta” year, you will work hard at doing what you need to do to launch your prototype product or service and then correcting the flaws so that you move beyond the “beta” level to begin getting solid paying customers and building your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By year three you’ve put in 5,000-7,000 hours and you launch the real deal … something that is good enough to be in the top 200-300 in the world in anything. The top 200 in almost any field makes a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By year four you will scale that up and polish to take out the non-value-added distractions to allow you to make a decent, comfortable living. Some people stop at year four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By year five you’re in the top 30-50 so you can actually invest in compounding your succcess to make genuine wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M) What is “it”? How do I know what I should do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever area you feel like reading 500 books about. Go to the bookstore and find it. If you get bored three months later go back to the bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to get disillusioned. That’s what failure is about. Success is better than failure but the biggest lessons are found in failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very important: There’s no rush. You will reinvent yourself many times in an interesting life. You will fail to reinvent many times. That’s fun also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many reinventions make your life a book of stories instead of a textbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people want the story of their life to be a textbook. For better or worse, mine is a book of stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why reinvention happens every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;N) The choices you make today will be in your biography tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make interesting choices and you will have an interesting biography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;N1) The choices you make today will be in your biology tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O) What if I like something obscure? Like biblical archaeology or 11th-century warfare?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat all of the steps above, and then in year five you will make wealth. We have no idea how. Don’t look to find the end of the road when you are still at the very first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P) What if my family wants me to be an accountant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many years of your life did you promise your family? Ten years? Your whole life? Then wait until the next life. The good thing is: you get to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose freedom over family. Freedom over preconceptions. Freedom over government. Freedom over people-pleasing. Then you will be pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q) My mentor wants me to do it HIS way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s fine. Learn HIS way. Then do it YOUR way. With respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully nobody has a gun to your head. Then you have to do it their way until the gun is put down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R) My spouse is worried about who will support/take care of kids?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then after you work 16 hours a day, seven days a week being a janitor, use your spare time to reinvent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who is reinventing ALWAYS has spare time. Part of reinvention is collecting little bits and pieces of time and re-carving them the way you want them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;S) What if my friends think I’m crazy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What friends?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T) What if I want to be an astronaut?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a reinvention. That’s a specific job. If you like “outer space” there are many careers. Richard Branson wanted to be an astronaut and started Virgin Galactic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U) What if I like to go out drinking and partying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this post again in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V) What if I’m busy cheating on my husband or wife or betraying a partner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this post again in two or three years when you are broke and jobless and nobody likes you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W) What if I have no skills at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read “B” again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X) What if I have no degree or I have a useless degree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read “B” again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y) What if I have to focus on paying down my debt and mortgage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read “R” again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Z) How come I always feel like I’m on the outside looking in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein was on the outside looking in. Nobody in the establishment would even hire him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone feels like a fraud at some point. The highest form of creativity is born out of skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AA) I can’t read 500 books. What one book should I read for inspiration?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BB) What if I’m too sick to reinvent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reinvention will boost every healthy chemical in your body: serotonin, dopamine, oxytocin. Keep moving forward and you might not get healthy but you will get healthier. Don’t use health as an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, reinvent your health first. Sleep more hours. Eat better. Exercise. These are key steps to reinvention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CC) What if my last partner screwed me and I’m still suing him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop litigating and never think about him again. Half the problem was you, not him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DD) What if I’m going to jail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect. Reread “B.” Read a lot of books in jail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EE) What if I’m shy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your weaknesses your strengths. Introverts listen better, focus better, and have ways of being more endearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FF) What if I can’t wait five years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on being alive in five years then you might as well start today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GG) How should I network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make concentric circles. You’re at the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next circle is friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next circle is online communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is meetups and coffees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is conferences and thought leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle after that is customers and wealth-creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start making your way through the circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HH) What happens when I have ego about what I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 6-12 months you’ll be back at “B”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II) What if I’m passionate about two things? What if I can’t decide?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine them and you’ll be the best in the world at the combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JJ) What if I’m so excited I want to teach what I’m learning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start teaching on YouTube. Start with an audience of one and see if it builds up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KK) What if I want to make money while I sleep?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In year four, start outsourcing what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LL) How do I meet mentors and thought leaders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have enough knowledge (after 100-200 books), write down 10 ideas for 20 different potential mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of them will respond. Write down 10 more ideas for 20 new mentors. Repeat every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put together a newsletter for everyone who doesn’t respond. Keep repeating until someone responds. Blog about your learning efforts. Build community around you being an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MM) What if I can’t come up with ideas?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then keep practicing coming up with ideas. The idea muscle atrophies. You have to build it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for me to touch my toes if I haven’t been doing it every day. I have to do it every day for a while before I can easily touch my toes. Don’t expect to come up with good ideas on day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NN) What else should I read?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFTER books, read websites, forums, magazines. But most of that is garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OO) What if I do everything you say but it still doesn’t seem like it’s working?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will work. Just wait. Keep reinventing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try and find the end of the road. You can’t see it in the fog. But you can see the next step and you do know that if you take that next step eventually you get to the end of the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PP) What if I get depressed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sit in silence for one hour a day. You need to get back to your core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this sounds stupid then don’t do it. Stay depressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QQ) What if I don’t have time to sit in silence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then sit in silence for two hours a day. This is not meditation. This is just sitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RR) What if I get scared?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep 8-9 hours a day and never gossip. Sleep is the No. 1 key to successful health. It’s not the only key. It’s just No. 1. Some people write to me and say, “I only need four hours of sleep” or “in my country sleeping means laziness.” Well, those people will fail and die young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about gossip? The brain biologically wants to have 150 friends. Then when you are with one of your friends you can gossip about any of the other 150. If you don’t have 150 friends then the brain wants to read gossip magazines until it thinks it has 150 friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be as stupid as your brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SS) What if I keep feeling like nothing ever works out for me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend 10 minutes a day practicing gratitude. Don’t suppress the fear. Notice the anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also allow yourself to be grateful for the things you do have. Anger is never inspirational but gratitude is. Gratitude is the bridge between your world and the parallel universe where all creative ideas live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TT) What if I have to deal with personal bullshit all the time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find new people to be around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who is reinventing herself will constantly find people to try and bring her down. The brain is scared of reinvention because it might not be safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biologically, the brain wants you to be safe and reinvention is a risk. So it will throw people in your path who will try to stop you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to say “no.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UU) What if I’m happy at my 9-t0-5 job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine. Good luck. You are not one of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VV) Why should I trust you – you look like a failure to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do NOT trust me.  But be VERY VERY cynical of someone who portrays himself as a master with all of the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WW) Will you be my mentor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have just read this entire post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/11/30/Reinvention.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/11/30/Reinvention.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Monk Thing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am just an OLD MONK, but after seeing friends and family again over Thanksgiving, I have been thinking a LOT about how I should TRAIN now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that my training not at all about me anymore, it’s mostly about what I should do so that I can more effectively work with others or assist others in THEIR training.  When an old monk survives long enough, he becomes more interested in next generation training (i.e. I want to train for the FUTURE threat, not my survival or the threat of yesterday or today). Some time ago, I started looking into training SYSTEMS … there are old school martial arts traditions, but there are plenty of worthy modern examples also such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.combatical.com/&quot;&gt;Marine Corps Martial Arts close combat training&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kravmaga-ikmf.com/krav-maga/train-in-israel/warriors-quest/&quot;&gt;Israeli Krav Maga training&lt;/a&gt;.  Since I respect traditions, I realize that I am not really any different from those who have come before me.  I am just an OLD MONK … but I am obligated to train others because I survived to be an old monk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some fairly simple and timeless rules that emerge …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-daily-practice-that-supports-and-sustains-you-and-advances-your-art&quot;&gt;Create a daily practice that supports and sustains you and advances your art.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Get up and get moving, move throughout the day. Try to eat better each day than you did the day before
2) Do the HARD THING that you fear most first so that your mind is clear to write, code, implement, debug
3) Play with principles and your original extension of principles rather than memorizing specific techniques, quotes, phrases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rest-and-relax-without-engaging-in-bad-unmindful-habits&quot;&gt;Rest and relax without engaging in bad unmindful habits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) If you need a distraction from your pathetic life, you’re doing it wrong.
2) Use or don’t use sex or stimulants or drugs or asceticism, but do not allow addiction to rule you.
3) Practice the habits of mindfulness, especially in your rest and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-essence-of-being-a-warrior-is-never-quitting-on-yourself&quot;&gt;The essence of being a warrior is never quitting on yourself.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Relapse is a necessary part of recovery, recovery is necessary to beat addiction. Don’t let relapse lead you back to addiction.
2) Celebrate your victories by working on your humility; never be satisfied – always think about the ways that you could have done something better or helped others more.
3) Be more anonymous, but rule by example. Avoid dick measuring competitions. Work harder at channeling desire for wealth, power, fame, sex, comfort into helping others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-can-be-dead-serious-without-losing-your-sense-of-humor&quot;&gt;You can be dead serious without losing your sense of humor.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Practice giving humor speeches or being a standup comic.
2) Have a point, but illustrate your point with humor, koans, riddles.
3) Shut up and listen.  Work on being a better listener.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/to/learn/2015/11/30/The-Monk-Thing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/to/learn/2015/11/30/The-Monk-Thing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        <category>to</category>
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Disrupting Education</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am still digesting the depth of what I learned at a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://chirontraining.com/Site/VioDy_MN_November.html&quot;&gt;Violence Dynamics seminar held in Mounds View, MN&lt;/a&gt; … the timetable of the material covered in this seminar is given at the bottom of this posting … but that doesn’t really describe the impact that the seminar had on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Marc MacYoung is responsible for pointing out that violence is a taboo topic nowadays in the same way that sex was a taboo topic in the 1950s.  You cannot talk about violence in polite company any more.  SEX is a completely different matter. Whether it’s stretched, holey spandex on an older overweight woman in Walmart OR the latest overexposure of something that one of the Kardashians should keep private OR a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2015/11/23/blogger-bread-vagina-yeast/#L4U6QKDgpaq3&quot;&gt;feminist using her own vaginal yeast for her sourdough bread&lt;/a&gt;, [whether you want to think about it or not] SEX is something that cannot and will not be underexpressed any more.  The sexual revolution is over and we all have lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Violence training can disrupt education in the same way that SEX has totally disrupted commerce.  When it comes to team building, trust networks and practical bonds between professionals NOTHING can match hands on training in violence.  When you put others into serious choke holds and, in turn, you are put into serious choke holds by every other person in class, you learn something about others that you cannot learn from a face-to-face conversation.  Serious means that a person has to tap out or loses consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Play and humor matter in anything – they are especially important in training and teambuilding. We need more class clowns; but those class clowns also need to handle being slapped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Training should not end when the sessions wrap up.  Most of the commentary should occur AFTER the training session rather than during it.  By the same token there is something to be said for training prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) How should I train?  How should I work with others or lead others in training?  Since I am most interested in next generation training (i.e. I want to train for the FUTURE threat, not the threat of yesterday or today) I started looking into things like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kravmaga-ikmf.com/krav-maga/train-in-israel/warriors-quest/&quot;&gt;Israeli Krav Maga training&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THURSDAY NOVEMBER 19
8:00-8:45	Introduce Instructors/ Introductory Paper Work	Keckeisen
9:00-9:45	Introduction to Basic Drills/Pre-test	Keckeisen
10:00-10:45	Social Violence A	MacYoung &amp;amp; King
11:00-11:45	Social Violence B	MacYoung &amp;amp; King
12:00-12:45	Break
1:00-1:45	Striking Power Generation	Beyer
2:00-2:45	Striking Targeting	Beyer
3:00-3:45	Asocial Violence A	MacYoung &amp;amp; King
4:00-4:45	Asocial Violence B	MacYoung &amp;amp; King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FRIDAY NOVEMBER 20
8:00-8:45	Counter Assault A (Discussion and Principles)	King
9:00-9:45	Counter Assault B (Application and Drills)	King
10:00-10:45	Logic of Violence A	Miller
11:00-11:45	Logic of Violence B	Miller
12:00-12:45	Break
1:00-1:45	Mechanics of Throwing A	Keckeisen
2:00-2:45	Mechanics of Throwing B	Keckeisen
3:00-3:45	Force Law (Pre-arrest)	Keckeisen
4:00-4:45	Force Law (Post-arrest)	Keckeisen
5:00-6:00	Principle Based Movement	Q Fitness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SATURDAY NOVEMBER 21
8:00-8:45	Con Com A	Beyer
9:00-9:45	Con Com B	Beyer
10:00-10:45	High End Use of Force A	Keckeisen
11:00-11:45	High End Use of Force B	Keckeisen
12:00-12:45	Break
1:00-1:45	Con Com C	Beyer
2:00-2:45	Con Com D	Beyer
3:00-3:45	Ground Skills A	Miller
4:00-4:45	Ground Skills B	Miller
5:00-6:00	Principle Based Movement	Q Fitness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SUNDAY NOVEMBER 22
8:00-8:45	Basic Drills Post Test	Keckeisen
8:45-9:00	Conclusion Paper Work (Course Reviews)
9:00-9:45	Mall Training Brief	Miller
9:45-10:00	Drive to MOA
10:00-10:45	Topic 1 of 4
10:45-11:00	Debrief 1
11:00-11:45	Topic 2 of 4
11:45-12:00	Debrief 2
12:00-1:00	Break
1:00-1:45	Topic 3 of 4
1:45-2:00	Debrief 3
2:00-2:45	Topic 4 of 4
2:45-3:00	Final Debrief&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 02:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/11/24/Disrupting-Education.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/11/24/Disrupting-Education.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Go language and learning Russian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a lot about the old story or parable of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tower_of_Babel&quot;&gt;Tower of Babel&lt;/a&gt; lately … parables embed wisdom in cultures.  The lesson from Tower of Babel is we should be nervous about imagining that we can work well in different languages on difficult safety-critical projects of any scale.  It is probably not humanly impossible for someone to become a proficiently-wise polyglot in just one lifetime; it is impossible to have a competent multi-lingual team.  There has to be a common language that glues the conversation and collaboration together.  Yes, it is possible to become fluent enough in multiple languages to become dangerous, but being proficient to be wise and think with clear judgement is a lot tougher … this is not exactly the same as saying that most authors will never develop the proficiency to be Shakespeare – that’s already obvious enough.  It’s sort of like saying that most authors will probably never develop the multi-lingual proficiency to become remotely as competent [in different languages/cultures] as Kurt Vonnegut or Norman Mailer or John le Carré were in English … and certainly no multi-lingual author will be as proficient in multiple languages as the Steinbecks, Hemingways, Faulkners or Clarkes, Asimovs, Heinleins and other proficient users of the English language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This posting is about computer languages, specifically the Go programming language.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/trends/explore#q=golang&amp;amp;date=3%2F2012%2073m&amp;amp;cmpt=q&amp;amp;tz=Etc%2FGMT%2B5&quot;&gt;rate of adoption of Go language&lt;/a&gt; is just flat out impressive by almost any measure.  Go became a public open source project on November 10, 2009. After a couple of years of very active design and development, stability was called for and Go 1 was released on March 28, 2012.  There are, of course, other languages that one might want to be proficient or fluent in … languages that you cannot really ignore, even if you want to … C, Java, Python, Javascript, Erlang, Ruby, Haskell, Scala … but there are very good reasons to learn something about Go that are not just about why Go adoption is exploding, particularly in very interesting projects like Docker or CockroachDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to be VERY, VERY CAREFUL before you invest any effort learning in a new programming language … most programmers are not remotely careful enough about bumbling into a new language … if we want to understand why, let’s think about what we know about spoken languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-ways-to-learn-a-language-as-an-adult&quot;&gt;Learning any new language as an adult&lt;/a&gt; can be a rather daunting and unrewarding task AT FIRST.  4% of students embarking on &lt;em&gt;language courses in schools&lt;/em&gt; achieve a BASIC level of fluency after three years; 96% of the student invest time and money learning a language might start the best intentions and the kids are certainly smart enough and most of them are motivated enough to achieve other things in life, but they fail to learn new languages because they start out with completely wrong expectations. It takes 600+ hours of study and practice to reach BASIC fluency in a typical new language, unless you already speak a language that is linguistic similar, eg French-Spanish-Portuguese-Italian or English-German-Dutch are examples of linguistic similar languages … let that sink in for a second, 600+ is 2 hrs/day – ideally with most of that time spent practicing with fluent speaker, EVERY day for a full year to get a BASIC, three-year-old’s level of fluency!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fluency is not proficiency or mastery, mind you … effectively, fluency is not that much more than being able to follow a conversation translating what the speaker says and to ask VERY, VERY BASIC questions – fluency means that you can interact, but it does not mean that you can interact natively, without thinking… fluency is like hacking code, copy-and-pasting algorithmic snippets and taking 5X or 10X as long to debug code as someoe who is good enough to be proficient … at some point, you need to move beyond simple hacking and translating and you need to form new thoughts and actually THINK in a language.  REALLY learning a lanaguage to be able to think in that language will take you a LOT MORE than just 600+ hours; probably at least one order if not almost two orders of magnitude longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the ENTIRE reason to go to the effort of really learning a language well enough to THINK in that language is that, as Ludwig Wittgenstein famously said long ago [Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus (1922)], &lt;em&gt;a new language will expand the limits of your world dramatically&lt;/em&gt; but only if you USE it* … you need to understand and live the idioms and patterns, the best practices and the stories and parables that go with them, the algorithms and ways of thinking. Learning new ways to think is the big reason to learn a new language and USE IT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will admit that these are not very robust metaphors but they do sort of illustrate the way that I see the language thing.  Being fluent in Javascript, Python, Ruby and various scripting languages is [for a native English speaker] a lot like learning German or learning to use English at a higher, more abstract level … everytime I turn around, I find myself thinking I should be better at these.  If I did not already have a bit of a background in it, C [and to some degree C++ and Java] would probably be like learning Chinese … almost painful, but I do not have a choice … the number of applications for it is in the billions and neither C nor Chinese are going to go away.  Learning other languages like Erlang, Haskell or Go are probably a lot like learning Russian – people are doing some really interesting, really complex things in those languages and the mental world inhabited by those people is obviously far different than the middle-class American mental realm … so why not explore it?  But there are limits to what I can do, so when it comes to other languages like Cobol, Pascal, Fortran or &lt;em&gt;even a scientific computing language like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JuliaLang/julia&quot;&gt;Julia&lt;/a&gt; that I probably SHOULD dig into&lt;/em&gt; … those languages are like French or Spanish or Portuguese or Italian … yes, I know that a lot of great people use them and maybe they really turned my head at one at one time, but I don’t see them impacting my future that directly so I think I will just rely on friends or robo translators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I will look at some Go idioms … or maybe some Russian proverbs&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning/2015/09/23/Learning-Russian.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning/2015/09/23/Learning-Russian.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It looks like we might have CONSENSUS!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy and am frustrated by the topic of CONSENSUS enough that I once started writing a book once about consensus and distributed leadership … &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.platosrepublicans.com/&quot;&gt;Plato’s Republicans&lt;/a&gt; … my interest in political economics and social choice theory gradually was overcome by the more concrete and practical world of consensus algorithms for distributed databases … although I continue to see BOTH topics as very closely related, but I now see that the implementations of the distributed database algorithms offers much more promise than the theoretic navel-gazing of political economics and the even more abstract topic of how leaders form, seize, shape, manipulate, define consensus … &lt;em&gt;if you thought consensus algorithms were difficult.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a techblog so my focus in this post is upon an exploration of consensus algorithms in distributed databases.  In these RT/FT algorithms as in life with humans, it is easy to recognize what consensus is after you are there … everyone loves it and we almost declare some sort of moral triumph when we exclaim, “So we have consensus!” … but the pain of converging on the final solution can be a bugger … especially if speed of convergence matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paxos_(computer_science)&quot;&gt;Paxos&lt;/a&gt; … first published in 1989, named after a fictional legislative consensus system used on the Paxos island in Greece. The Paxos family of protocols includes a spectrum of trade-offs between the number of processors, number of message delays before learning the agreed value, the activity level of individual participants, number of messages sent, and types of failures. Although no deterministic fault-tolerant consensus protocol can guarantee progress in an asynchronous network, Paxos guarantees safety (consistency), and the conditions that could prevent it from making progress are difficult to provoke. Paxos is usually used where durability is required (for example, to replicate a file or a database), in which the amount of durable state could be large. The protocol attempts to make progress even during periods when some bounded number of replicas are unresponsive. There is also a mechanism to drop a permanently failed replica or to add a new replica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chandra%E2%80%93Toueg_consensus_algorithm&quot;&gt;Chandra-Toueg&lt;/a&gt; … published by Tushar Deepak Chandra and Sam Toueg in 1996, is an algorithm for solving consensus in a network of unreliable processes equipped with an eventually strong failure detector. The failure detector is an abstract version of timeouts; it signals to each process when other processes may have crashed. An eventually strong failure detector is one that never identifies some specific good process as having failed after some initial period of confusion, and at the same time eventually identifies all bad processes as failed. The algorithm itself is similar to the Paxos algorithm, which also relies on failure detectors. Both algorithms assume the number of faulty processes is less than n/2, where n is the total number of processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raft.github.io/&quot;&gt;Raft&lt;/a&gt; … first published in 2013 by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ongardie.net/&quot;&gt;Diego Ongaro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.stanford.edu/~ouster/cgi-bin/home.php&quot;&gt;John Osterhout&lt;/a&gt; is a understandable, more readily-implementable consensus algorithm designed as a more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~ms705/pub/papers/2015-osr-raft.pdf&quot;&gt;practical alternative to famously difficult Paxos algorithm&lt;/a&gt;. It’s no accident – according to Ongaro, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6bBggO6KN_k&quot;&gt;the idea for Raft was CONCIEVED and then DESIGNED AT EVERY STEP TO BE MORE UNDERSTANDABLE&lt;/a&gt; than Paxos or Chandra-Toueg algorithms by means of separation of logic, but it is also formally proven safe and offers some new features. Raft offers a generic way to distribute a state machine across a cluster of computing systems, ensuring that each node in the cluster agrees upon the same series of state transitions.  Although Raft is a recent development, it already has a number of open-source reference implementations, with full-spec implementations in Go, C++, Java, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/heidi-ann/ocaml-raft&quot;&gt;OCaml&lt;/a&gt; and Scala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/1407.4765.pdf&quot;&gt;Ark&lt;/a&gt; … first published in 2014 by Zardosht Kashef and Leif Walsh It ultimately has many similarities with Raft, but diverges in a few ways, mainly to support other features like chained replication and unacknowledged writes (ie prevention from rolled back writes by elections). Ark elections have been used in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tokutek/mongo&quot;&gt;TokuMX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading list …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;TBD accelerated social consensus research … &lt;em&gt;like the rest of this reading list, this is glaringly incomplete&lt;/em&gt; especially given the material that should be out there on NEW forms of social leadership … what does social graph research tell us about the emergence of leader candidates; can the heuristic selection of leaders be applied to algorithms?  One would think that surely the voluminous research afforded by all of the social graph data from &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1509.04227&quot;&gt;Twitter latent communities&lt;/a&gt; or others like FB or LinkedIn have taught us at least as much about nuances in the selection of Leaders and how followers aggregate as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byzantine_fault_tolerance&quot;&gt;Byzantine Generals&lt;/a&gt; ever taught us about fault-tolerance, right… consider also Bitcoin and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bandwagon_effect&quot;&gt;other cultural phenomena, such as the bandwagon effect&lt;/a&gt; … as one might expect in industries where social interaction threatens the dominant regime, there are some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC411092/&quot;&gt;really thorough, CRITICAL systematic reviews of the effects of online peer to peer interactions in healthcare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;TBD consensus algorithm dissertations and peer-reviewed papers … another glaringly incomplete bullet point … &lt;a href=&quot;http://lampwww.epfl.ch/~blackbal/Thesis/thesis.pdf&quot;&gt;A Formal Approach to Fault Tolerant Distributed Consensus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://research.google.com/archive/spanner.html&quot;&gt;Google’s Spanner&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.googleusercontent.com/media/research.google.com/en//archive/spanner-osdi2012.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://research.google.com/archive/spanner-osdi2012.pptx&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://livestream.com/accounts/1545775/osdi12/videos/4646642&quot;&gt;2012 talk at OSDI&lt;/a&gt; Spanner is Google’s scalable, multi-version, globally-distributed, and synchronously-replicated database. It is the first system to distribute data at global scale and support externally-consistent distributed transactions. This paper describes how Spanner is structured, its feature set, the rationale underlying various design decisions, and a novel time API that exposes clock uncertainty. This API and its implementation are critical to supporting external consistency and a variety of powerful features: non-blocking reads in the past, lock-free read-only transactions, and atomic schema changes, across all of Spanner.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/datastore/docs/articles/balancing-strong-and-eventual-consistency-with-google-cloud-datastore/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Datastore balances strong and eventual consistency&lt;/a&gt; … achieving strong consistency for a positive user experience while leveraging the eventual consistency model to scale to large datasets. Eventual consistency is a theoretical guarantee that, provided no new updates to an entity are made, all reads of the entity will eventually return the last updated value. The Internet Domain Name System (DNS) is a well-known example of a system with an eventual consistency model. DNS servers do not necessarily reflect the latest values but, rather, the values are cached and replicated across many directories over the Internet. It takes a certain amount of time to replicate modified values to all DNS clients and servers. However, the DNS system is a very successful system that has become one of the foundations of the Internet. It is highly available and has proven to be extremely scalable, enabling name lookups to over a hundred million devices across the entire Internet.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eventual_consistency&quot;&gt;Eventually consistent&lt;/a&gt; services are often classified as providing BASE (Basically Available, Soft state, Eventual consistency) semantics, in contrast to traditional ACID (Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability) guarantees. Eventual consistency is sometimes criticized as increasing the complexity of distributed software applications. This is partly because eventual consistency is purely a liveness guarantee (reads eventually return the same value) and does not make safety guarantees: an eventually consistent system can return any value before it converges.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoq.com/articles/cap-twelve-years-later-how-the-rules-have-changed&quot;&gt;The CAP theorem&lt;/a&gt; asserts that any net­worked shared-data system can have only two of three desirable properties. How­ever, by explicitly handling partitions, designers can optimize consistency and availability, thereby achieving some trade-off of all three.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;TBD … video playlists&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/rocksdb&quot;&gt;RocksDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FoundationDB&quot;&gt;FoundationDB&lt;/a&gt; … the &lt;em&gt;consensus&lt;/em&gt; is that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/benkepes/2015/03/25/a-cautionary-open-source-tale-apple-buys-and-shutters-foundationdb/&quot;&gt;Apple is not about to become an open source company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Extended blogosphere and twittersphere TBD&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;MORE repository TBD&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/algorithms/social/leadership/2015/09/23/Consensus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/algorithms/social/leadership/2015/09/23/Consensus.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>algorithms</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
