<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns Tech Blawg</title>
    <description>This is my blog about version-controlled social production of open source technologies, cultures and revolutions ... and my interconnections to larger, more awesome interconnections in the universe ... https://xkcd.com/1579/</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 11:21:58 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 11:21:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fighting crime, fighting fires</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to NYU Law School’s Brennan Center for Justice, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brennancenter.org/publication/crime-2016-preliminary-analysis&quot;&gt;murder rate in cities is up 13% in 2016&lt;/a&gt; … which is an alarming start of [what hopefully is NOT] a pattern of a double-digit increase on top of another double-digit increase … since murders in the U.S. jumped by 10.8% in 2015, according to FBI data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, there is a LOT of good news in crime data – GENERALLY speaking, in most jurisdictions, crime has been really low and been falling even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t live in an area where crime is falling … well … you and your community are doing it wrong … and the data prove that you are doing it wrong.  If you don’t like the conclusion, go argue with the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the FBI recorded violent crime narrowly falling, by 0.2%. In 2015, the number of violent crimes rose 3.9% and the number of property crimes dropped 2.6% … while crime is dropping in much of the country, and even in some urban environments … but in 44 of the 65 largest police agencies in 2015, the murder rate increased. There are some cities, like Baltimore, DC, Chicago, St. Louis, Houston and LA where things are seriously screwed-up … compared to the rest of the country, those 44 urban police jurisdictions are bad enough to significantly raise the murder rates on average for the whole country, with the worst, i.e. Chicago [labeled by some as an “outlier”] being enough to counter the trend of the rest of the nation … and it will get worse before it gets better because there are some “community organizers” out there who are NOT really providing any leadership, but instead are blaming the police and failing to look at the root cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to find the ROOT CAUSE for what is driving the crime increase in some urban hell-holes, here’s a HINT … it AIN’T the police doing the killing … or looting the Walmarts after a riot … or exploiting the unrest and riots for political gain by calling for more protests and riots, ie protests and riots are NOT going to help with what is primarily a self-inflicted problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guess is that it’s like fighting fire … which is MOSTLY about recognizing fire hazards, doing things to DE-ESCALATE the hazard level and making sure that the people you hang around with are also not idiots when it comes to escalation of risk … idiots who play with fire must not be defended and certainly should not be celebrated [or even mourned] when the idiots die in a fire they started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fighting fire is MOSTLY about behaviors … but fire does happen, so fire extinguishers matter … the problem with fires is much less where fire extinguishers are ubiquitous and EVERYONE takes ownership when it comes to preventing fires and calling out idiotic behavior that might lead to fire.  Sometimes things do happen – that’s why EVERYONE has know exactly where several different fire extinguishing devices, water, blankets are and EVERYONE knows how to help put out a fire because they had hands-on training using one within the last year … in other words, if you live in a city with lots of immature, irresponsible, unsupervised uber-entitled children [regardless of what age they are] are running around with gas cans and fire-starting kits expecting the adults in fire departments to put out the fires, your city is going to BURN DOWN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to situations where things are engulfed in flame and BURNING DOWN … even in relatively small fires … another part of fighting fire is about EXIT.  That means there is no good that comes from be being the stupid amateur hero, puts on his superhero cape and CONFRONTS the fire that is already out-of-control.  In other words, back away from the blaze, call in the professionals and do NOT complicate the problem the professionals have to solve by becoming part of the situation.  Do NOT be a hero unless you are a TRAINED PROFESSIONAL who is PAID to develop all of the skills necessary to be a hero, ie support your Fire Dept folks, support your police.  The thing to do with an out-of-control fire is to GET AWAY and let the professionals decide what to do … don’t be too surprised if they decide to let the fire burn what it’s going to burn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/crime,/root/cause/2016/09/28/Fighting-Fires.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/crime,/root/cause/2016/09/28/Fighting-Fires.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>crime,</category>
        
        <category>root</category>
        
        <category>cause</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are the most important technologies for accelerated learning?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe the most important thing is encouragement and nudging people to be TOUGH enough to fit in, to naturalize, assimilate, adapt enough to thrive and not only become native but to produce something of importance or beauty for others in the ecosystem, like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/y/2rpqQTs&quot;&gt;muscari armeniacum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to &lt;em&gt;become native&lt;/em&gt; and then transcend that by producing things of real value?  It is probably a matter of LOVE, commitment and extreme ownership – that means really &lt;em&gt;OWNING&lt;/em&gt; every problem (ie opportunity) that other people run away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;at your own pace&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;on your own&lt;/em&gt; is NEVER really a matter of &lt;em&gt;going it entirely alone&lt;/em&gt; … the best way to really learn or even master something is to teach it to someone else … there are ways to apply the benefits of exposure and network effects, to encourage meaningful social interaction, to elicit others to be involved in progress, to participate in the code code graph, to not just participate but to take on the effort as their own, to hack it, to extend it for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me think about applying the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FreeCodeCamp/FreeCodeCamp&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; method to the natural HARD sciences … it goes beyond mere coding, but coding is extremely important for building tools that explore relationships … like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neo4j.com/use-cases/real-time-recommendation-engine/&quot;&gt;graph databases&lt;/a&gt; and building a tool to find shared knowledge connections or what might be described as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ILjTikVhT9k&quot;&gt;topical interest recommendation engine&lt;/a&gt; … for example, what kinds of understanding can we bring together to give us new frontiers to explore in understanding an aspect of soil ecosystem health and nutritional pathways … of course, understanding informs the approach we use in looking for data … sometimes we simply need to gather a lot more data now, perhaps we can get lots of macro photos (although macro photos are important and there are better technologies for micro and even nano level photography), but also we also think about things like sequential or time-lapse longitudinal panel data gathering, but we can also explore other tools like DNA chips for nutritional genomics of different species in different ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should think about how superheros like us build and use tools … and then use those tools to build and use better tools … and how the incremental daily improvement might not seem all that significant, but when we look back we see how incredibly much things have CHANGED in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lyDLAutA88s&quot;&gt;the last 20 years of building tools to munge data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/learning,/acceleration/2016/09/24/Evolutionary-Advance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/learning,/acceleration/2016/09/24/Evolutionary-Advance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning,</category>
        
        <category>acceleration</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WHY won&#39;t updates to GitHub pages load immediately [or with the same latency]?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of LITTLE … and some times, not so little … things that impact your workflow on GitHub … and it’s up to YOU to stay engaged, to have a degree of situational awareness … perhaps patiences … perhaps an understanding of what you need to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgot about what you might believe … you simply are NOT &lt;strong&gt;entitled&lt;/strong&gt; to help from anyone else … including even GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now … the folks at GitHub probably want to help you, but there might be impediments to IMMEDIATELY serving you … maybe you haven’t phrased your question intelligently or in a manner that fits their jargon and linguistic realm … maybe there are problems with people who supply services to them; maybe they have their own glitches or bugs or issues … there are all kinds of reasons why the latency of their service might vary.  It’s not a perfect world.  And, even though we probably should not FIRST suspect malicious intent, since it’s so much more likely that OTHER things are driving actions, there ARE indeed very malevolent actors out there – not just hackers who want to take down a service like Github for their own idiotic purposes, but maybe’s it WORSE … like some EVIL national security agency of a totalitarian regime of thugs might be forcing Github to supply data or obstruct free speech.  We have reasons for why we should LOVE Github, but … even if their intentions are better, purer, smarter than anyone else’s … you simply are NOT &lt;strong&gt;entitled&lt;/strong&gt; to expect IMMEDIATE help from anyone else … including GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIRST thing to look at is your own [lack of CURRENT] knowledge about your own set-up … for example … recently, I was working on a blog with the same Atom Editor and GitHub Desktop tools I’ve come to know and love … and use somewhat successfully [for my modest purposes] … using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as a SIMPLE blog-aware static &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/github-pages/&quot;&gt;GH pages&lt;/a&gt; site generator on my laptop … good ol’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000&quot;&gt;127.0.0.1:4000&lt;/a&gt; looked as current and good [ie what I expected to see] as ever … there had been no error messages from the editor or desktop app … I had up to date version of each … the updated pages were in Github’s repo and I could see them on Github’s website … but Github was not loading my updated pages for some reason!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO IT WAS TIME FOR ME TO RELAX and spend a couple minutes RELEARNING SOME STUFF … I had used the Github pages MAGIC and &lt;em&gt;it just worked&lt;/em&gt; … like MAGIC … I didn’t need to know AND I didn’t know some key portions of the magic … I had trusted Github TOO MUCH … I know better … you cannot trust ANYONE, even people who are on your side and do not want to deliberate screw up your workflow … that includes even Github … most importantly YOU CANNOT PLACE ALL OF YOUR FAITH MAGIC YOU DON’T UNDERSTAND … if you’re going to rely on magic, at least build in some redundancies, just in case, things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/configuring-a-publishing-source-for-github-pages/&quot;&gt;how GitHub serve pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2228-simpler-github-pages-publishing&quot;&gt;how they have recently updated it do it NOW&lt;/a&gt; don’t perform as you think they will, when you need a service to perform for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I didn’t need to change or fix anything … it was JUST an issue of LATENCY … for some reason, GitHub was not IMMEDIATELY updating the blogs it hosts as rapidly as it usually does. So … yeah … I did not learn as much about Git and GitHub behind-the-scenes internal magic as I &lt;em&gt;should have&lt;/em&gt; learned … but the search and the serendipitous things that I did learn made it ALL WORTHWHILE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that if you rely upon Github … and you probably should rely on GitHub … and the larger GitHub community … at least, you should &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; rely on them and even if you are a competitor of them, you should pay attention because Github is pretty good at what they do, especially the &lt;em&gt;network effects&lt;/em&gt; stuff … even for things that are not mission-critical for &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; mission, but if your mission involves developing software, content, data science or building any form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/awesome&quot;&gt;AWESOME&lt;/a&gt; knowledge, the fully network-effected social distributed version control that Github does is critical for your level of situational awareness … you really NEED to be reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog&quot;&gt;GitHub blog&lt;/a&gt;, following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/github&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/GitHubGuides&quot;&gt;Github Guides&lt;/a&gt; channels on YouTube and maybe even attending and definitely paying attention to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://githubuniverse.com/program/&quot;&gt;program&lt;/a&gt; of topics and speakers &lt;a href=&quot;http://githubuniverse.com/&quot;&gt;at GitHub conferences&lt;/a&gt; … you really should have an awareness of &lt;a href=&quot;https://octoverse.github.com/&quot;&gt;what is going on at GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and in the companies involved in providing distributed version control like [Git] … after all, the whole toolchain and different services that you rely on for source control are kind of a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/relearning,/trust/2016/09/21/The-Tao-of-Github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/relearning,/trust/2016/09/21/The-Tao-of-Github.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>relearning,</category>
        
        <category>trust</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prove your words by your deeds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are nothing more than imperfectly expressed desires. For thousands of years, humans have known action speak louder. Many people use words in order to enlist others, makes sales, get opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want opportunities … then USE the mountain of opportunities you already have.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of options and opportunities is always going to be pretty damned limited for people who think first in getting help from others and do not develop their abilities to think in terms of what they can work on, what they can make better, what they can use in order to &lt;em&gt;advance the ball.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look ONLY at what you can do without begging for help from others and then narrow your focus to what is the very highest and very best use of your time among those options … it will tend to exceptionally true that the very best opportunities one has just do not look especially inviting or compelling.  Opportunity is usually about the thing that eliminates a constraint for a lot of people or really helps the most people in the biggest way, especially when they do not understand that YOU are the one helping them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still highly advantageous to seek anonymity rather than get taken in by fame or adoration, power or wealth … fame, adoration, power or wealth ALWAYS attract the cocksuckers, ie the people who want to perform small services in order to “pick up the crumbs” and hopefully get opportunity &lt;em&gt;on the cheap&lt;/em&gt;.  There are plenty of people who enjoy having their cock sucked and relentlessly pursue fame, adoration, power and wealth … there are others, who enjoy getting into dick-measuring contests to compare stories or resumes or combat medals.  That is unfortunate – but it is a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the FEW who are not just expedient whores, it is possible to see the emptiness of those pursuits or how desire for fame, adoration, power and wealth leads to a state of permanent neediness and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/culture,/history,/seneca/2016/09/20/The-Tao-of-Desire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/culture,/history,/seneca/2016/09/20/The-Tao-of-Desire.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Culture,</category>
        
        <category>History,</category>
        
        <category>Seneca</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tolerance for slavery is an indicator of cultural weakness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If people want their culture to be STRONGER (ie, respect for rights, prosperity and distribution of wealth, creative people in vibrant yet stable communities, diverse choices in a variety of things), they must renounce the types of things that make a culture WEAK, like all forms slavery. The mainstream in Saudi Arabia refuses to do this; accordingly, a nation like Saudi Arabia has a weak culture. People will go there because they HAVE to [for work]; they will not go there to enjoy the culture. This sort of renunciation of repugnant cultural practices like slavey might seem obvious, but it is perhaps not so obvious that islamophilic multiculuralists are doing no favors for the people who must live in a sub-standard culture by refusing to be critical of bad practices, bad religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most [if not all] islamophiles tend to be deliberately, aggressively, WILLFULLY naive about how something like the &lt;em&gt;religion of submission&lt;/em&gt; but they cannot ignore how a culture that drives and thrives upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YnJfR70n6k0&quot;&gt;slavery&lt;/a&gt;.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Wln6lNTxVpY?t=37m40s&quot;&gt;entitled morons out there who will unabashedly and gladly enslave others&lt;/a&gt; in order to subsidize the grossly inefficient academic industry in America in order to provide higher education for everyone because they claim that higher education is the key to opportunity. They completely fail to realize that a nation FREE of slavery in all its forms, including the tax and regulatory burdens of grossly inefficient state and federal bureaucracies, is THE key to opportunity. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Wln6lNTxVpY?t=38m1s&quot;&gt;Thomas Sowell is absolutely right about &lt;strong&gt;opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; … all of us in America have had ample &lt;em&gt;opportunities&lt;/em&gt; to become the next &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LAr6oAKieHk&quot;&gt;Michael Jordan&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/dou3aSZmEg0?list=PLElrASo3VHBxt9zg3oRoKSqmyiCHct4Ai&quot;&gt;Miles Davis&lt;/a&gt; … but ONLY Michael Jordan and Miles Davis WORKED and PERSEVERED &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michaeldpollock.com/michael-jordan-on-failure-and-perseverance/&quot;&gt;to overcome their own fears, doubts and failures&lt;/a&gt; or when success looked especially FAR from being certain (eg being and then WORKED and PERSEVERED even more after it appeared that success was possible … even if we want to IMAGINE that our talent constrains us … even though we more than enough examples to PROVE that talent, aptitude or any physical attribute [including appearance] is NOT the barrier that most humans want to believe … we must know that we have had more than sufficient opportunities to WORK and PRACTICE and hone what skills we do have to be able to reach what most regard as impossible goals … ALL people in America HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY to play on a level where we can interact with supremely-talented masters who have ALSO worked hard in order to take advantage of the opportunities offered to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;higher-education-is-not-the-key-to-opportunity&quot;&gt;Higher education IS NOT the key to opportunity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KEY to opportunity is using what opportunities you have to the very fullest as you await being showered with the opportunities that surreptitiously always accrue to those who have a proven history of using the opportunities that they have had.  &lt;em&gt;If you want opportunities … then USE the mountain of opportunities you already have.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/culture,/history,/slavery/2016/09/15/Cultural-Weakness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/culture,/history,/slavery/2016/09/15/Cultural-Weakness.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Culture,</category>
        
        <category>History,</category>
        
        <category>Slavery</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Most of what passes for science is NOT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of what passes for science these days involves a manufactured conclusion that artificially satisfies the expectations of funders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent JAMA article about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archinte.jamanetwork.com/article.aspx?articleid=2548255&quot;&gt;sugar industry lobby steering research for decades&lt;/a&gt; is far from news … no one is [or should be] really all that surprised by this.  Funding steering conclusion [more than results] is TYPICAL of the way that 99.999% of the research conducted in academia is done. What is amazing about this article is that one of the loyal subjects has actually FINALLY admitted in empire’s most venerable publication that the emperor is wearing absolutely no clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/junk/2016/09/12/Junk-Science.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/junk/2016/09/12/Junk-Science.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Junk</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It&#39;s not the politicians that are the problem; it&#39;s the slugs who rely upon politicians and governments.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First they came for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/video/politics/after-deplorables-comment-trump-claims-clinton-laughed-at-us-workers/2016/09/12/5f904da6-790b-11e6-8064-c1ddc8a724bb_video.html&quot;&gt;basket of irredeemable (i.e. unprogrammable) deplorable soldiers, cops, technicians, engineers and hard-working Americans&lt;/a&gt;, and I did not speak out — Because I didn’t think of myself as irredeemable or deplorable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then they came for the guys who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=11-EAzsGxgQ&quot;&gt;post YouTube videos&lt;/a&gt;, and I did not speak out — Because I don’t know how to shoot videos or post to YouTube.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then they came for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitchy.com/dougp-3137/2016/09/12/what-a-scream-howard-dean-has-had-it-with-anti-hillary-bias-from-npr/&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;, and I did not speak out — Because I don’t listen to ANY media; I just look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikileaks.org/&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then they came for me—and there was no one left to speak for me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we should just let things take their own course and ROT .. because rotting is part of the chemical, nutrient and life cycle of human existence … although there could be giant benefits to subtly manipulating, ie ACCELERATING, the rotting process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complexity of soil ecosystems has some important lessons for how we think about human interactions and optimizing those interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, human beings really know remarkably little about soil ecosystems … there are people who know a lot … but generally speaking, the population of farmers in the world knows a LOT more about government programs than they know about soil fungi, bacteria, earthworms and plant roots interactions … because IT PAYS to study farm programs – there’s not really any serious money in building soil … so when MOST farmers are bouncing around in their tractor seats, a lot of them might be worried about farm programs, revenue assurance policies, making sure that they’ve dotted the i’s and crossed the t’s so that they are still eligible for maximized federally-subsidized guaranteed income streams to finance the purchase of more equipment or farmland … but MOST of them are NOT thinking about optimizing the soil ecosystems under their control – some are, but MOST are thinking more about farm programs because farm programs drive incentives and influence the mindshare of what sharp, capable, hard-working people think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are one of those who still imagines that governments and bureaucratic silos are NOT the problem … please correct your thinking … when it comes to agriculture, food and soil science, government is most definitely THE PROBLEM … or, more correctly, it creates and feeds the problem of ultra-risk averse welfare maximization [rather than scarce amounts of ambition, creativity and investment devoted to new product creation and value addition in the economy] coupled with political rent-seeking by industry organizations paid for by dues / checkoffs / contributions from welfare recipients that defend and expand welfare payments and subsidies to people who are already quite wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a 3000-yr-old chinese proverb that applies to the the debacle created by the USDA and various farm programs … as well as the Affordable Care Act, or Dodd-Frank or any other monsterous debacle created by clueless morons trying to give the appearance that they want to help … &lt;strong&gt;A government has a strategy … as result of that, the people will need to find counter strategies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DON’T help!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, we should think about what is really valuable, about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLElrASo3VHBxt9zg3oRoKSqmyiCHct4Ai&quot;&gt;what really matters&lt;/a&gt;.  The purpose of everything we do … programming, writing, experimenting, trying things … is INSIGHT. It’s not getting a candidate elected OR convincing someone to believe a LIE OR jealously manipulating and obfuscating truth so that our dick looks bigger in the giant dick-measuring contest that we think everyone wants to be part of. The indisputable truth is still there …  &lt;strong&gt;Every politician, every government has a [worse than just WORTHLESS] strategy, which will create more problems that it fixes. The people have work harder at finding counter strategies that give them the insight to actually make their lives better.&lt;/strong&gt;  The world doesn’t really need calories or protein or energy or all kinds of free shit – people can and will figure that stuff out in the best manner on their own … the clarity of NO SOLUTION is actually helpful.  We should think a lot more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLElrASo3VHBxt9zg3oRoKSqmyiCHct4Ai&quot;&gt;what really matters&lt;/a&gt; in terms of helping people to find INSIGHT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insight is always in short supply.&lt;/em&gt;  Insight is impossible to find in a bureaucratic silo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to the world of agriculture and soil building. If you look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s1BpauXRp6U&quot;&gt;what is emerging down at the suburban street level in the world of permaculture&lt;/a&gt;, you have to be excited about the ‘counter strategies’ that PEOPLE are developing … without or in spite of government interference.  The largest danger that these independent efforts faces is the subtle subversion executed by government officials … as the officials attempt to co-opt and direct the movement by &lt;em&gt;teaching birds to fly&lt;/em&gt; with criticisms, i.e. “&lt;em&gt;You doing it wrong, haven’t you read paragraph 4(b) of chapter 357.19 in the code. Here’s a pamphlet on how gardeners can comply with the code.&lt;/em&gt;” or &lt;em&gt;offering&lt;/em&gt; their policies, programs and incentives to &lt;em&gt;participate&lt;/em&gt; in their government-controlled bureaucratic silo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government-controlled bureaucratic silos steadily atrophy skills and disenfranchise people by subtly inducing independent people believe they need to follow the MASTER, to not just accept assistance from the MASTER, but get comfortable with and begin to depend upon the subsidized revenue insurance, leadership and direction from the MASTER … while the MASTER places the radio-controlled shock collar and tracking device around your neck, and maybe embeds a carefully selected mix of stories in your social media feeds so that even the thoughts that are imagined to be spontaneous are actually the result of subconscious programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cocksuckers are incredibly seductive and powerful … so powerful that there is a COLD civil war that is now underway in which the cocksuckers are persecuting, taxing and regulating the inventors, creators, entrepreneurs and other productive people into oblivion … this COLD civil war will eventually become a HOT civil war … maybe not immediately, in the next year or decade, but eventually the COLD civil war will turn HOT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who imagine that overthrow of the government is impossible because the government holds all the resources do not understand the nature of fighting and using a stronger, but unjust opponent’s strengths and weapons against him. The bureaucratic centralizers of the Union are still in the process of devising and implementing the schlerotic regime that will choke initiative and diversity to product a demoralizing defeat and complete, incomprehensible capitulation for them. Shutting down NEW growth always preceded death and rot of living systems. Death is part of life; decay and rot pave the way for the next generation of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t rush the schlerosis … if it needs another century, fine … give it time, whether it was McClelland fighting Lee in the 19th century or folks like McNamara and Westmoreland fighting Giáp in the 20th, the game still works the same … ultimately, any insurgency with a just cause … even if it’s like Lee/Jackson v McClelland with a perceived just cause of the Union being in Virginia … the supposedly weaker opponent ALWAYS annihilates an enemy with more and better systems, resources, arms, personnel … if Lee hadn’t gone into Pennsylvania in 1863, the South could have lasted a very long time, someone would have stepped up to take Jackson’s place. The South was ultimately going to lose because its cause, ie perpetuation of slavery, was thoroughly and deeply unjust … the Union would have found ways to incompetently continue to provide the CSA with “free” resources and materials; the Union did not win as much as South LOST the First Civil War because its unjust cause eventually dried up its talent and any hope of foreign assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not really different now … it is only a matter of time before the power centralizers LOSE to those wishing for distributed and decentralized freedom and lose … the authoritarians will lose in a completely convincing and obvious fashion … the just cause can always tolerate incredibly high casualties because anything perceived as a just and righteous cause is ALWAYS going to be an unstoppable recruiting tool to bring in new allies. Consider the case of Al Qaeda and ISIS … the PERCEPTION of their cause being just [in certain populations] means that defeating them will be next to impossible, regardless of the resources deployed … the ONLY way to defeat them is by correcting the perception that their cause is just. Frankly, it will be IMPOSSIBLE to do that as long as we don’t do a better job of providing a better alternative, with an economy and culture that encourages a higher rate of new business formation and ventures that create new opportunities for billions of young people wanting to do something meaningful with their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the top-down centralizers and powerful cronies are in control and stifling bottom-up entrepreneurial freedom, the West’s cause will be equally as unjust as Al Qaeda’s or ISIS’s … it will only be a different flavor of injustice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/09/09/The-Tao-Of-Laziness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/09/09/The-Tao-Of-Laziness.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bioremediation,</category>
        
        <category>antibiotics,</category>
        
        <category>enzymes,</category>
        
        <category>metagenomics,</category>
        
        <category>soil</category>
        
        <category>ecosystems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anthropogenic soil building ecosystems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best way to criticize is to CREATE.  To create, observe and mimic nature.&lt;/strong&gt;  You cannot spend too much time outdoors, not just in the smoking area behind your building or an urban courtyard [which isn’t that different than huddling outside to take a drag off of a cigarette] … BE really outdoors, with your bare feet on the earth, observing nature, as part of nature, looking at how nature creates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativity is like soil building … not at all simple, even though people like to imagine that it is.  Creativity is a way of understanding cycles and rhythms, bot cut through noise. Understanding value and achieving a cleaner signal yields simplicity and sustainability.  If humans want to create, they should avoid their fixation on biased, complicated human policy models and instead imitate how [natural] creation achieves simplicity. This means shepherding reasonable complex interactions involving plants, fungi, bacteria, insects and animals … basically a matter of pulling the weeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entropy or noise of the universe is constantly increasingly in several different dimensions. If you want to defeat noise or minimize entropy, you must understand cycles and rhythms in order to work at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/awesome-electron&quot;&gt;creating a PRODUCTIVE community of tool developers building everything to make people independently creative … everything from email, chat, git repo apps, research notebooks, CAD tools, collaborative data analytics tools, torrent clients, gaming/simulation software and streaming robots for different ways to collaborate&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best way to fight or compete is to create and collaborate.  There are opportunities everywhere.  ATTACK the problems! ATTACK the opportunities! ATTACK things that are HARD to do! Help others ATTACK!  The best way to attack is to create!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/situational/intelligence,/electron,/jupyter/2016/09/06/MORE-Situational-Intelligence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/situational/intelligence,/electron,/jupyter/2016/09/06/MORE-Situational-Intelligence.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Situational</category>
        
        <category>Intelligence,</category>
        
        <category>Electron,</category>
        
        <category>Jupyter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WHY governments and bureaucratic silos MUST suck the life out of everything they touch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government always has a strategy … because of this, the people need to deploy counter strategies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you trust governments, you shouldn’t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; trust your basic motives for wanting to believe that governments are there for good purposes like liberty, justice and fighting for the little guy … BUT … you have to be very careful about naively failing to examine the REALITY that governments offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments SUFFER from the impossible problem that results from the centralization of resources in the hands of people who claim to be the “best and brightest.”  That might sound like an okay idea, but it NEVER works out well.  The best ideas come from the bottom up, through COMPETITION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in government might CLAIM to be as bright and capable as the folks at the Google, but the reality is that, on their very best day, the folks in government are not as close to be good as Google Buzz … remember Google Buzz?  Google Buzz was designed to be THE KILLER SOCIAL MEDIA APP that annihilated a Facebook or Twitter or LinkedIn [before Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn or anybody had critical mass for real network effects] … government’s Affordable Care Act ability to compete effectively with do-it-yourself veterinary care is more of a stretch than Google Buzz’s current ability to take down Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments are NEVER as good as something like Google Buzz, or Buzz’s successor Google+ or remotely close to what the politicians grandiosely promise to deliver. NEVER.  The best and brightest are NEVER that good or bright – it gets much worse when the best and brightest have the unfettered monopoly power of government to violently and completely coerce citizens into accepting “historic policy initiatives.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t really trust anyone or anything, but if you think you NEED to trust something, it’d be better if you trusted the type of people who are involved in a project that helps get past government, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/whispersystems/&quot;&gt;Open Whisper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDEALLY, governments are supposed to exist in order to protect rights. Governments only RARELY do this … they would NEVER EVER EVER do this if not for checks, balances and people holding governments accountable.  That means the goodness of government is entirely up to you … without YOU holding your government accountable, government is EVIL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, governments exist to protect the rights of powerful bureaucrats, politicians and tyrants. This is not to say that there are not plenty of plenty who really try hard to make government better, to make it serve the public interest.  NO politician, soldier or bureaucrat has EVER has &lt;em&gt;absolutely&lt;/em&gt; followed their oath to support and defend the Constitution … even the ones who actually try can’t – they do the best that they can within the constraints of how government actually operates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDEALLY, government leaders are democratically selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, MOST adults are so disgusted by government that they RATIONALLY choose not to wait effort voting. Majorities are TERRIBLE ways to make choices – if you believe otherwise, try being the guy that the majority of the lynch mob wants to hang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of what the leader of the lynch mob wants the crowd to do, there is almost NEVER an actual need for government to take action … if the lynch mob wants action and needs government to forcefully, coercively take action, we can say with near certainty that there is a BETTER voluntary solution that makes more sense BECAUSE it is VOLUNTARY and makes obvious sense without needing to HURT the minority that is opposed to the coercive action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democracy IS a great thing IF one realizes that there are severe limits on how large a democracy can be before it becomes a mechanism for corruption and tyranny.  A couple thousand years ago, Plato nailed it – Plato earnestly believed that the optimal size for a democracy was 5,300 people.  This is about right – maybe the optimal size human-scale democracy is closer 53,000 but it is definitely not human scale any more at 530,000 or 5.3M or larger.  In other words, if something is a GREAT IDEA … why isn’t it VOLUNTARY … if you imagine that &lt;em&gt;voluntary&lt;/em&gt; cannot possibly work for your great idea, WHY does it need the coercive force of MORE than a human-scale 5300-person true democracy.  WHY does your great idea require the corruption and tyrannical power of more than 5300 people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your idea isn’t voluntary or requires the industrial coercive strength of more than 5300 people for adoption, there’s a good likelihood that your idea is IDIOTIC and DANGEROUS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/game/theory,/political/theory/2016/09/04/Why-Government-Sucks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/game/theory,/political/theory/2016/09/04/Why-Government-Sucks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>game</category>
        
        <category>theory,</category>
        
        <category>political</category>
        
        <category>theory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jupyter Lab, PhosphorJS ... and Getting Used to Swimming in the Deep End</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A government has a strategy. The people have counter strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It USED to be that governments had the inside edge on gathering the data and formulating better strategies – but increasingly that is no longer true – governments have inept, inflexible, archaic sub-optimal strategies, whereas people have smarter, more sophisticated, more intensely-responsive strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; why I am so intensely intrigued by things like new computer languages … I almost worry about the fascination sometimes … but I am engrossed in things that enable collaborative workflows like the Julia Language, or tools for collaborative language polyglottery such as the Jupyter (Julia-Python-R) Project, including both Jupyter Notebook, Jupyter Lab and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/howitworks.html&quot;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt; … but it’s mostly about how language enables thinking – that includes the data analysis that provides the sophistication and accuracies in the strategies of people … I am not particularly interested in policy prescriptions for governments, although I get that people [especially investors and fund managers] can benefit from having &lt;a href=&quot;http://quantecon.org/notebooks.html&quot;&gt;quantitative economic&lt;/a&gt; models [including models of government policy] for their own information and use in their own industries and economic spheres.  I TOTALLY understand that shiny new tools are dangerous for their distractive power and their POWER in providing the WRONG answers. Nothing sends people to the ER like the exuberance of a new power tool. But &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; we figure out how to use the power tool for maximum productivity and, maybe even more importantly, TIMELINESS … and one farmer can PERFECTLY plant more acres of a crop at exactly the right right time with his giant tractor pulling a sophisticated planting implement than armies of planters could have ever planted with their hoes and bags of seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.hackpad.com/&quot;&gt;Jupyter Hackpad &lt;/a&gt; because I believe that &lt;a href=&quot;http://jupyterlab-tutorial.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html&quot;&gt;Jupyter Lab&lt;/a&gt; is really a big deal … sort of like Linux really looked spooky big 25 years ago, when a new riff on the Minix clone of Unix was small enough to be ignored because the gold standard was still a PCs running DOS or Windows NT … but some could generally see that it was a big enough of an idea that you knew it was somehow GOING TO amount to something in the fall of 1991.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think Jupyter is going to be an even bigger deal because of things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.hackpad.com/collection/zCqMrBELzrv&quot;&gt;Jupyter Hackpad Weekly Dev Meetings&lt;/a&gt; … although I still suspect that Jupyter, like Linux, will ultimately be driven by an individual leading a small core development group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter-notebook.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/a&gt; was already a big deal because of what it means for team workflows … sharing and and walking through code and data science …and since those workflows change, what is important is how the Notebook extends the basic console-based approach to interactive computing in a qualitatively new direction, providing a web-based application suitable for capturing the whole computation process: developing, documenting, and executing code, as well as communicating the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jupyter Notebook combines two components: 1) A web application and 2) notebook documents.  The web application is a browser-based tool for interactive authoring of documents which combine explanatory text, mathematics, computations and their rich media output.  The notebook documents provide a representation of all content visible in the web application, including inputs and outputs of the computations, explanatory text, mathematics, images, and rich media representations of objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jupyter.org/2016/07/14/jupyter-lab-alpha/&quot;&gt;Jupyter Lab&lt;/a&gt; puts extensibility on steroids by making it easy to extend the already venerable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.safaribooksonline.com/library/view/jupyter-notebook-for/9781771375030/&quot;&gt;Jupyter notebook for data science teams&lt;/a&gt; and provide a foundation for continued extensions of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jupyter.org/about.html&quot;&gt;Project Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://phosphorjs.github.io/about.html&quot;&gt;the PhosphorJS libraries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;swimming&quot;&gt;SWIMMING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My curation of content is not what it should be … maybe it is, but what I am referring to is the explosion of really important ideas in the realm of data science … and the need to amp up one’s situational awareness of development in this professional realm of knowledge … using the tools of data science, ie a Jupyter notebook of notebooks, data visualizations, webinars, code repos and Github codegraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently started thinking that I need to spend a fair amount of time … maybe as much as four hours a day (&lt;em&gt;Is that way too much?!  NOT ENOUGH??!!&lt;/em&gt;) engaged in skimming / sipping / “swimming in the deep end” from what I call the “Data Science Ecosystem Firehose”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub / Gitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Udacity / CodeSchool / Cloud Academy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetups / Confs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn / Twitter (Lists)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogs (FooledByRandomness)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/phosphorjs/2016/09/01/PhosphorJS-Jupyter-Lab.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/phosphorjs/2016/09/01/PhosphorJS-Jupyter-Lab.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>PhosphorJS</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
