<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarkBruns Tech Blag</title>
    <description>This is my blog about version-controlled social production of open source technology ... and the interconnections to interconnections ... https://xkcd.com/1579/</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 15:16:52 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 15:16:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anthropogenic soil building ecosystems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best way to criticize is to CREATE.  To create, observe and mimic nature.&lt;/strong&gt;  You cannot spend too much time outdoors, not just in the smoking area behind your building or an urban courtyard [which isn’t that different than huddling outside to take a drag off of a cigarette] … BE really outdoors, with your bare feet on the earth, observing nature, as part of nature, looking at how nature creates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativity is like soil building … not at all simple, even though people like to imagine that it is.  Creativity is a way of understanding cycles and rhythms, bot cut through noise. Understanding value and achieving a cleaner signal yields simplicity and sustainability.  If humans want to create, they should avoid their fixation on biased, complicated human policy models and instead imitate how [natural] creation achieves simplicity. This means shepherding reasonable complex interactions involving plants, fungi, bacteria, insects and animals … basically a matter of pulling the weeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entropy or noise of the universe is constantly increasingly in several different dimensions. If you want to defeat noise or minimize entropy, you must understand cycles and rhythms in order to work at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/awesome-electron&quot;&gt;creating a PRODUCTIVE community of tool developers building everything to make people independently creative … everything from email, chat, git repo apps, research notebooks, CAD tools, collaborative data analytics tools, torrent clients, gaming/simulation software and streaming robots for different ways to collaborate&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best way to fight or compete is to create and collaborate.  There are opportunities everywhere.  ATTACK the problems! ATTACK the opportunities! ATTACK things that are HARD to do! Help others ATTACK!  The best way to attack is to create!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/situational/intelligence,/electron,/jupyter/2016/09/16/MORE-Situational-Intelligence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/situational/intelligence,/electron,/jupyter/2016/09/16/MORE-Situational-Intelligence.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Situational</category>
        
        <category>Intelligence,</category>
        
        <category>Electron,</category>
        
        <category>Jupyter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It&#39;s not the politicians that are the problem; it&#39;s the slugs who rely upon politicians and governments.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First they came for the irredeemable, deplorable lunatics, and I did not speak out — Because I didn’t think I was a irredeemable, deplorable lunatic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then they came for the guys who post YouTube videos, and I did not speak out — Because I don’t know how to shoot videos or post to YouTube.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then they came for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitchy.com/dougp-3137/2016/09/12/what-a-scream-howard-dean-has-had-it-with-anti-hillary-bias-from-npr/&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;, and I did not speak out — Because I don’t listen to public radio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then they came for me—and there was no one left to speak for me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an explanation of why I think we should just let things rot .. because rotting is part of the chemical, nutrient and life cycle of human existence … although there could be giant benefits to subtly manipulating, ie ACCELERATING, the rotting process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complexity of soil ecosystems has some important lessons for how we think about human interactions and optimizing those interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, human beings really know remarkably little about soil ecosystems … there are people who know a lot … but generally speaking, the population of farmers in the world knows a LOT more about government programs than they know about soil fungi, bacteria, earthworms and plant roots interactions … because IT PAYS to study farm programs – there’s not really any serious money in building soil … so when MOST farmers are bouncing around in their tractor seats, a lot of them might be worried about farm programs, revenue assurance policies, making sure that they’ve dotted the i’s and crossed the t’s so that they are still eligible for maximized federally-subsidized guaranteed income streams to finance the purchase of more equipment or farmland … but MOST of them are NOT thinking about optimizing the soil ecosystems under their control – some are, but MOST are thinking more about farm programs because farm programs drive incentives and influence the mindshare of what sharp, capable, hard-working people think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are one of those who still imagines that governments and bureaucratic silos are NOT the problem … please correct your thinking … when it comes to agriculture, food and soil science, government is most definitely THE PROBLEM … or, more correctly, it creates and feeds the problem of ultra-risk averse welfare maximization [rather than scarce amounts of ambition, creativity and investment devoted to new product creation and value addition in the economy] coupled with political rent-seeking by industry organizations paid for by dues / checkoffs / contributions from welfare recipients that defend and expand welfare payments and subsidies to people who are already quite wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a 3000-yr-old chinese proverb that applies to the the debacle created by the USDA and various farm programs … as well as the Affordable Care Act, or Dodd-Frank or any other monsterous debacle created by clueless morons trying to give the appearance that they want to help … &lt;strong&gt;A government has a strategy … as result of that, the people will need to find counter strategies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DON’T help!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, we should think about what is really valuable, about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLElrASo3VHBxt9zg3oRoKSqmyiCHct4Ai&quot;&gt;what really matters&lt;/a&gt;.  The purpose of everything we do … programming, writing, experimenting, trying things … is INSIGHT. It’s not getting a candidate elected OR convincing someone to believe a LIE OR jealously manipulating and obfuscating truth so that our dick looks bigger in the giant dick-measuring contest that we think everyone wants to be part of. The indisputable truth is still there …  &lt;strong&gt;Every politician, every government has a [worse than just WORTHLESS] strategy, which will create more problems that it fixes. The people have work harder at finding counter strategies that give them the insight to actually make their lives better.&lt;/strong&gt;  The world doesn’t really need calories or protein or energy or all kinds of free shit – people can and will figure that stuff out in the best manner on their own … the clarity of NO SOLUTION is actually helpful.  We should think a lot more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLElrASo3VHBxt9zg3oRoKSqmyiCHct4Ai&quot;&gt;what really matters&lt;/a&gt; in terms of helping people to find INSIGHT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insight is always in short supply.&lt;/em&gt;  Insight is impossible to find in a bureaucratic silo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to the world of agriculture and soil building. If you look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s1BpauXRp6U&quot;&gt;what is emerging down at the suburban street level in the world of permaculture&lt;/a&gt;, you have to be excited about the ‘counter strategies’ that PEOPLE are developing … without or in spite of government interference.  The largest danger that these independent efforts faces is the subtle subversion executed by government officials … as the officials attempt to co-opt and direct the movement by &lt;em&gt;teaching birds to fly&lt;/em&gt; with criticisms, i.e. “&lt;em&gt;You doing it wrong, haven’t you read paragraph 4(b) of chapter 357.19 in the code. Here’s a pamphlet on how gardeners can comply with the code.&lt;/em&gt;” or &lt;em&gt;offering&lt;/em&gt; their policies, programs and incentives to &lt;em&gt;participate&lt;/em&gt; in their government-controlled bureaucratic silo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government-controlled bureaucratic silos steadily atrophy skills and disenfranchise people by subtly inducing independent people believe they need to follow the MASTER, to not just accept assistance from the MASTER, but get comfortable with and begin to depend upon the subsidized revenue insurance, leadership and direction from the MASTER … while the MASTER places the radio-controlled shock collar and tracking device around your neck, and maybe embeds a carefully selected mix of stories in your social media feeds so that even the thoughts that are imagined to be spontaneous are actually the result of subconscious programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cocksuckers are incredibly seductive and powerful … so powerful that there is a COLD civil war that is now underway in which the cocksuckers are persecuting, taxing and regulating the inventors, creators, entrepreneurs and other productive people into oblivion … this COLD civil war will eventually become a HOT civil war … maybe not immediately, in the next year or decade, but eventually the COLD civil war will turn HOT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who imagine that overthrow of the government is impossible because the government holds all the resources do not understand the nature of fighting and using a stronger, but unjust opponent’s strengths and weapons against him. The bureaucratic centralizers of the Union are still in the process of devising and implementing the schlerotic regime that will choke initiative and diversity to product a demoralizing defeat and complete, incomprehensible capitulation for them. Shutting down NEW growth always preceded death and rot of living systems. Death is part of life; decay and rot pave the way for the next generation of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t rush the schlerosis … if it needs another century, fine … give it time, whether it was McClelland fighting Lee in the 19th century or folks like McNamara and Westmoreland fighting Giáp in the 20th, the game still works the same … ultimately, any insurgency with a just cause … even if it’s like Lee/Jackson v McClelland with a perceived just cause of the Union being in Virginia … the supposedly weaker opponent ALWAYS annihilates an enemy with more and better systems, resources, arms, personnel … if Lee hadn’t gone into Pennsylvania in 1863, the South could have lasted a very long time, someone would have stepped up to take Jackson’s place. The South was ultimately going to lose because its cause, ie perpetuation of slavery, was thoroughly and deeply unjust … the Union would have found ways to incompetently continue to provide the CSA with “free” resources and materials; the Union did not win as much as South LOST the First Civil War because its unjust cause eventually dried up its talent and any hope of foreign assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not really different now … it is only a matter of time before the power centralizers LOSE to those wishing for distributed and decentralized freedom and lose … the authoritarians will lose in a completely convincing and obvious fashion … the just cause can always tolerate incredibly high casualties because anything perceived as a just and righteous cause is ALWAYS going to be an unstoppable recruiting tool to bring in new allies. Consider the case of Al Qaeda and ISIS … the PERCEPTION of their cause being just [in certain populations] means that defeating them will be next to impossible, regardless of the resources deployed … the ONLY way to defeat them is by correcting the perception that their cause is just. Frankly, it will be IMPOSSIBLE to do that as long as we don’t do a better job of providing a better alternative, with an economy and culture that encourages a higher rate of new business formation and ventures that create new opportunities for billions of young people wanting to do something meaningful with their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the top-down centralizers and powerful cronies are in control and stifling bottom-up entrepreneurial freedom, the West’s cause will be equally as unjust as Al Qaeda’s or ISIS’s … it will only be a different flavor of injustice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/09/09/The-Tao-Of-Laziness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/09/09/The-Tao-Of-Laziness.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bioremediation,</category>
        
        <category>antibiotics,</category>
        
        <category>enzymes,</category>
        
        <category>metagenomics,</category>
        
        <category>soil</category>
        
        <category>ecosystems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WHY governments and bureaucratic silos MUST suck the life out of everything they touch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government always has a strategy … because of this, the people need to deploy counter strategies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you trust governments, you shouldn’t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; trust your basic motives for wanting to believe that governments are there for good purposes like liberty, justice and fighting for the little guy … BUT … you have to be very careful about naively failing to examine the REALITY that governments offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments SUFFER from the impossible problem that results from the centralization of resources in the hands of people who claim to be the “best and brightest.”  That might sound like an okay idea, but it NEVER works out well.  The best ideas come from the bottom up, through COMPETITION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in government might CLAIM to be as bright and capable as the folks at the Google, but the reality is that, on their very best day, the folks in government are not as close to be good as Google Buzz … remember Google Buzz?  Google Buzz was designed to be THE KILLER SOCIAL MEDIA APP that annihilated a Facebook or Twitter or LinkedIn [before Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn or anybody had critical mass for real network effects] … government’s Affordable Care Act ability to compete effectively with do-it-yourself veterinary care is more of a stretch than Google Buzz’s current ability to take down Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments are NEVER as good as something like Google Buzz, or Buzz’s successor Google+ or remotely close to what the politicians grandiosely promise to deliver. NEVER.  The best and brightest are NEVER that good or bright – it gets much worse when the best and brightest have the unfettered monopoly power of government to violently and completely coerce citizens into accepting “historic policy initiatives.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t really trust anyone or anything, but if you think you NEED to trust something, it’d be better if you trusted the type of people who are involved in a project that helps get past government, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/whispersystems/&quot;&gt;Open Whisper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDEALLY, governments are supposed to exist in order to protect rights. Governments only RARELY do this … they would NEVER EVER EVER do this if not for checks, balances and people holding governments accountable.  That means the goodness of government is entirely up to you … without YOU holding your government accountable, government is EVIL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, governments exist to protect the rights of powerful bureaucrats, politicians and tyrants. This is not to say that there are not plenty of plenty who really try hard to make government better, to make it serve the public interest.  NO politician, soldier or bureaucrat has EVER has &lt;em&gt;absolutely&lt;/em&gt; followed their oath to support and defend the Constitution … even the ones who actually try can’t – they do the best that they can within the constraints of how government actually operates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDEALLY, government leaders are democratically selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, MOST adults are so disgusted by government that they RATIONALLY choose not to wait effort voting. Majorities are TERRIBLE ways to make choices – if you believe otherwise, try being the guy that the majority of the lynch mob wants to hang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of what the leader of the lynch mob wants the crowd to do, there is almost NEVER an actual need for government to take action … if the lynch mob wants action and needs government to forcefully, coercively take action, we can say with near certainty that there is a BETTER voluntary solution that makes more sense BECAUSE it is VOLUNTARY and makes obvious sense without needing to HURT the minority that is opposed to the coercive action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democracy IS a great thing IF one realizes that there are severe limits on how large a democracy can be before it becomes a mechanism for corruption and tyranny.  A couple thousand years ago, Plato nailed it – Plato earnestly believed that the optimal size for a democracy was 5,300 people.  This is about right – maybe the optimal size human-scale democracy is closer 53,000 but it is definitely not human scale any more at 530,000 or 5.3M or larger.  In other words, if something is a GREAT IDEA … why isn’t it VOLUNTARY … if you imagine that &lt;em&gt;voluntary&lt;/em&gt; cannot possibly work for your great idea, WHY does it need the coercive force of MORE than a human-scale 5300-person true democracy.  WHY does your great idea require the corruption and tyrannical power of more than 5300 people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your idea isn’t voluntary or requires the industrial coercive strength of more than 5300 people for adoption, there’s a good likelihood that your idea is IDIOTIC and DANGEROUS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/game/theory,/political/theory/2016/09/04/Why-Government-Sucks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/game/theory,/political/theory/2016/09/04/Why-Government-Sucks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>game</category>
        
        <category>theory,</category>
        
        <category>political</category>
        
        <category>theory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jupyter Lab, PhosphorJS ... and Getting Used to Swimming in the Deep End</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A government has a strategy. The people have counter strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It USED to be that governments had the inside edge on gathering the data and formulating better strategies – but increasingly that is no longer true – governments have inept, inflexible, archaic sub-optimal strategies, whereas people have smarter, more sophisticated, more intensely-responsive strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; why I am so intensely intrigued by things like new computer languages … I almost worry about the fascination sometimes … but I am engrossed in things that enable collaborative workflows like the Julia Language, or tools for collaborative language polyglottery such as the Jupyter (Julia-Python-R) Project, including both Jupyter Notebook, Jupyter Lab and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/howitworks.html&quot;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt; … but it’s mostly about how language enables thinking – that includes the data analysis that provides the sophistication and accuracies in the strategies of people … I am not particularly interested in policy prescriptions for governments, although I get that people [especially investors and fund managers] can benefit from having &lt;a href=&quot;http://quantecon.org/notebooks.html&quot;&gt;quantitative economic&lt;/a&gt; models [including models of government policy] for their own information and use in their own industries and economic spheres.  I TOTALLY understand that shiny new tools are dangerous for their distractive power and their POWER in providing the WRONG answers. Nothing sends people to the ER like the exuberance of a new power tool. But &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; we figure out how to use the power tool for maximum productivity and, maybe even more importantly, TIMELINESS … and one farmer can PERFECTLY plant more acres of a crop at exactly the right right time with his giant tractor pulling a sophisticated planting implement than armies of planters could have ever planted with their hoes and bags of seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.hackpad.com/&quot;&gt;Jupyter Hackpad &lt;/a&gt; because I believe that &lt;a href=&quot;http://jupyterlab-tutorial.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html&quot;&gt;Jupyter Lab&lt;/a&gt; is really a big deal … sort of like Linux really looked spooky big 25 years ago, when a new riff on the Minix clone of Unix was small enough to be ignored because the gold standard was still a PCs running DOS or Windows NT … but some could generally see that it was a big enough of an idea that you knew it was somehow GOING TO amount to something in the fall of 1991.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think Jupyter is going to be an even bigger deal because of things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.hackpad.com/collection/zCqMrBELzrv&quot;&gt;Jupyter Hackpad Weekly Dev Meetings&lt;/a&gt; … although I still suspect that Jupyter, like Linux, will ultimately be driven by an individual leading a small core development group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter-notebook.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/a&gt; was already a big deal because of what it means for team workflows … sharing and and walking through code and data science …and since those workflows change, what is important is how the Notebook extends the basic console-based approach to interactive computing in a qualitatively new direction, providing a web-based application suitable for capturing the whole computation process: developing, documenting, and executing code, as well as communicating the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jupyter Notebook combines two components: 1) A web application and 2) notebook documents.  The web application is a browser-based tool for interactive authoring of documents which combine explanatory text, mathematics, computations and their rich media output.  The notebook documents provide a representation of all content visible in the web application, including inputs and outputs of the computations, explanatory text, mathematics, images, and rich media representations of objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jupyter.org/2016/07/14/jupyter-lab-alpha/&quot;&gt;Jupyter Lab&lt;/a&gt; puts extensibility on steroids by making it easy to extend the already venerable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.safaribooksonline.com/library/view/jupyter-notebook-for/9781771375030/&quot;&gt;Jupyter notebook for data science teams&lt;/a&gt; and provide a foundation for continued extensions of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jupyter.org/about.html&quot;&gt;Project Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://phosphorjs.github.io/about.html&quot;&gt;the PhosphorJS libraries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;swimming&quot;&gt;SWIMMING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My curation of content is not what it should be … maybe it is, but what I am referring to is the explosion of really important ideas in the realm of data science … and the need to amp up one’s situational awareness of development in this professional realm of knowledge … using the tools of data science, ie a Jupyter notebook of notebooks, data visualizations, webinars, code repos and Github codegraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently started thinking that I need to spend a fair amount of time … maybe as much as four hours a day (&lt;em&gt;Is that way too much?!  NOT ENOUGH??!!&lt;/em&gt;) engaged in skimming / sipping / “swimming in the deep end” from what I call the “Data Science Ecosystem Firehose”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub / Gitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Udacity / CodeSchool / Cloud Academy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetups / Confs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn / Twitter (Lists)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogs (FooledByRandomness)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/phosphorjs/2016/09/01/PhosphorJS-Jupyter-Lab.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/phosphorjs/2016/09/01/PhosphorJS-Jupyter-Lab.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>PhosphorJS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Burn It Down FIRST -- Why Simulation and Critique Is Better Than Building Stupid Shit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I really, really, like simulations, but I really, really HATE criticism-free safe spaces! Safe, criticism-free zones might just be the most pathological development in American history – particularly since simulated alternatives are practically FREE … of course, the vast majority of simulations should be BURNT DOWN … before they use real resources and induce real distortions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://markbruns.github.io/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;You know that I like moldy ecosystems as much as the next guy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but … I am wondering,”So what if &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kasita.com/is-the-tiny-house-trend-dead/&quot;&gt;the tiny house trend is becoming ordinary, untrendy and boring&lt;/a&gt; … does that really matter if the tiny house trend dies as a trend and becomes a stable, mature and more solid STANDARD?” In a way, I think the demise of the trendiness would be a GREAT thing … the longer-term survival of the tiny house STANDARD might depend upon letting the more extreme and goofy ideas just die before they hurt anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardization sounds simple … as long as we can get others to standardize on our way of doing things … but standardization is HARD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standardization means that there are some hard, practical choices and decisions that some of the principal players might need to make … these decisions are VOLUNTARY choices, but they must be intensely considerate of other people’s ideas, in order to allow standardization to be possible.  Nothing gets accepted as STANDARD unless there is almost unanimous consensus … almost NO designers are considerate enough by nature to produce true STANDARDS.  They dream of producing a standard; they can imagine that they are the Kind of France and mandate their standard on everyone else, but in spite of how mortal designers love to imagine that they can have the power of Steve Jobs, the fact is that there was one Steve Jobs and he has left the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kasita.com/#about&quot;&gt;Kasita container-esque idea&lt;/a&gt; HAS TO escape the Austin cartoon of itself [or the Portlandia cartoon of Portland] orbit … as well as the tiny house trend orbit … or it will die. I believe Kasita homes and Kasita parks and the Kasita concept MIGHT have the capacity to do that – since, the Kasita concept is one of the VERY FEW tiny house ideas that could survive the collapse of the tiny house trend universe if that is actually happening … &lt;strong&gt;but I am SKEPTICAL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my skepticism is driven by Kasita designers’ iPhone-ey focus on design RATHER than than Android/Linux focus on open source STANDARDIZATION and very long-term extensibility … which is an intensely practical matter of function … and the next generation’s functionality … and functionality for the generations after that.  Most of my skepticism is driven by my skepticism for ALL design ideas … ALL political ideas … ALL ideas … especially those which are merely whimsical or quirky or trendy or hip.  Some people are attached to their moldy, funky non-standard ideas in the same way that hoarders are attached boxes full of unique crap covered in black mold … the uniquer, moldier and funkier, the deeper the attachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A lot of houses and ghettos of houses in the world of ideas that should be burnt down … before they hurt someone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My critique of ANY tiny house idea, especially a proprietary, non-standard or one-off quirky hipster idea, is driven by a simple, deliberately harsh and nasty question, “After I die, could the executor of my estate pick up the phone and call a listing agent or some sort of broker/auctioneer who would readily convince someone else to buy [or even just assume ownership of at no cost] the cute little toy and live in the box? Does the idea still work long after the joke’s not funny any more and everyone in the world thinks it’s just a boring, disgusting, ubiquitous piece of trash (ie worse than a some hoarder’s mobile home rats nest in a trailer park)?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remodeling, re-appliance-ing, re-customizing homes is a completely banal idea, but it is a significant standard, structural, strategic ADVANTAGE of residential construction that we should not ignore, any more than we should ignore how water expands when it freezes or how turds strongly prefer to flow downhill.  We should ask if the basic shell of idea re-saleable like a 20’ shipping container or is the cute little quirky rat’s nest a disgusting liability that somebody will either have to nuke and make the sand glow OR some poor slob sweating in a hazmat suit will have to dispose of, like a hoarder’s collection of potentially hazardous, too-precious-to-part-with trash?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW … have you tried a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ebay.com/bhp/20-ft-shipping-container&quot;&gt;20’ shipping container&lt;/a&gt; on for size recently?  I’m guessing that a shipping container would fit you better than anything else you will find in the tiny house menagerie of goofball ideas … and it’s probably is a good way to transport any possession you need anywhere in the world [and if you need more things than a 20’ shipping container, you might need to re-prioritize and 5S your life] … and guess what, unlike other tiny house ideas which are basically about as marketable as a used condom, there’s actually a pretty vibrant MARKET for used shipping containers, after you get done with your shipping container, regardless of what kind of hipster slob you are.  In other words, before you ask me to put my shoulder to the wheel or invest in any tiny house venture, convince me that the idea driving your business will make your business a better value than investing in a bunch of 20’ shipping containers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/open/source/2016/08/31/Burn-It-Down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/open/source/2016/08/31/Burn-It-Down.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>open</category>
        
        <category>source</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why go to Mars when there are fungi here we haven&#39;t met yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea for this post STARTED as sort of a riff on Feynman’s “There’s plenty of room at the bottom,” except the GIGANTIC difference is that a person cannot LIVE at the nano level … whereas a person can LIVE by spending a portion every single day becoming more knowledgable about things like soil and fungi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can START with the gigantic life-saving and life-improving stuff.  Understanding herbicide transformation is necessary for pesticide development for their safe and efficient use, as well as for developing pesticide bioremediation strategies for contaminated soil and water. Recent studies persuasively demonstrated the key role of soil white-rot fungi in biotransformation of various anthropogenic environmental contaminants. However, often this common knowledge is not associated with specific metabolic processes of fungi and therefore cannot be transformed into specific recommendations for agricultural practice.  Beyond just bioremediation of pollutants, think about how much more we don’t know about building and conditioning of soils for optimal productivity?  If we are so smart about soils, what stops us from making it possible for everyone to be surrounded by a luxurious garden and living foodscape?  The answer is that we are most decidedly NOT THAT SMART when it comes to soils and everything that soils could offer us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course oceans are very important, but since most humans live on land, human life is almost entirely based on what soil ecosystems.  Of course oceans are a significant source of protein and the importance of oceans certainly cannot be dismissed, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://core.ecu.edu/geology/woods/SEARESOURCES.htm&quot;&gt;less than 3% of the food consumed by humans comes from the oceans&lt;/a&gt;. – I have no problem whatsoever with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Ocean_Sampling_Expedition&quot;&gt;smart people who like oceans disagreeing with me on the importance of soils&lt;/a&gt;, as long as they are willing to back up their argument with actions and agree to move PERMANENTLY offshore. Very few humans live permanently on/in the ocean. It is interesting that oceans cover most of the Earth’s surface, but there has not been a universally accepted “Law of the Sea” and, frankly property rights do matter when it comes to caring for resource that is essential for sustaining life.  Soil sustains life.  What keeps a human alive should be something that every human knows something about. Soil should be one of those most important topics, something essential for EVERY human being to be at least somewhat knowledgable about … because soil issues drive life issues, food issues, water issues and climate issues. The LACK of this knowledge leads to some catastrophically erroneous choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people [erroneously] believe that the largest problem facing humanity involves carbon in the atmosphere … whether this is a concern or not, these people seem to completely ignore that 2,700 Gt of C stored in soils worldwide.  As almost all knowledgable gardeners or farmers would tell you, they would like to have more … MUCH more … organic material in their soil.  As anyone who loves growing things, anyone who loves having dirt under their fingernails, knows and there is a capacity to double, triple or quadruple the soil organic carbon in most soils under cultivation or in human use.  This is significant because there is only 780 Gt of C is in the atmosphere and a small percentage of humans believe that it should be two-thirds of that amount … guess what … taking 260 Gt of C from the atmosphere and sequestering it as soil organic matter represents less than a 10% increase C … never mind that the even with that extra 10%, those soils would still be C-deficient when compared with what would be optimum for productivity and health of those soils. This matters because if we assume that world’s oceans cannot be managed as a carbon sink [which is slightly debatable, but perhaps true because of property rights issues] it becomes clear that the carbon “problem” should be thought of as a globally distributed soil issue, not a matter of sequestering a giant amount of carbon is a single location.  It soil carbon is a matter that scales IF each human on the planet STARTS giving a tiny amount of thought to where and how the food is grown that they eat, ie the appropriate metaphor is not something cataclysmically moronic, eg visions of a pencil lead the size of New Mexico, but instead each citizen should be responsible for knowing enough about soil to produce their own food if they had to. In other words, the fear mongering of the climate change people is not at all helpful – FEAR-driven policy is catastrophic. KNOWLEDGE-driven policy is helpful. We can do a much better job of utilizing our soils for a variety of different issues – better knowledge of soils not only solves the carbon  issue, adding soil organic carbon will improve soil quality and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OTHER issue with soil ecosystems involves essential compounds like antibiotics that originated from studies of soils.  People fail to realize how fundamentally these discoveries have transformed human existence … the real problem with this fundamental ignorance is the lack of understanding that we have only just scratched the surface.  We do not understand a tenth or even one-percent of what soil ecosystems have to offer … we do not even understand enough to know how small the fraction of that one-percent is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of how incomplete our knowledge is, consider how soil has, for millions of years, provides the environment for many different fungal species. These different species play an absolutely role in recycling nutrients through decay and breaking down of materials. Of course, these fungi produce different compounds [many essential for other species] in their digestive process but they do not just recycle nutrients by digest decaying plant matter. Fungi are attacked by bacteria which favor the same growing conditions and food stocks, but molds have defense mechanisms such as antimicrobial agents that prevent of the bacteria from making new cell walls and reproducing … as Penicillium chrysogenum … the ability of P. chrysogenum to produce antimicrobial agent penicillin appears to have evolved over hundreds of thousands or millions of years in soils in damp, consistent temperature environments in temperate and subtropical regions [which also favor bacterial growth]. Even though most humans now take penicillin for granted … few know that the sexual stage of P. chrysogenum was discovered only a few years ago, in 2013, by mating cultures in the dark on oatmeal agar supplemented with biotin, after the mating types (MAT1-1 or MAT1-2) of the strains had been determined using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction&quot;&gt;PCR&lt;/a&gt; amplification … the tools and technologies to do meaningful things are still being invented, as we stumble into things that we can’t “see” yet …  so we really don’t even know that much at all yet about how we would begin to set up practical methods to select and breed what has been one of the most important fungi to human beings … but others species, with uses we haven’t really discovered or conceived of yet, are almost necessarily more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When one considers that approximately 70,000 fungal species have been described, but the total number of fungal species is estimated to be well over 1.5 million and then one begins to understand that human beings have only begun to select and breed a very limited number of these fungal species for specific compounds and uses … when we factor in the chemical, bacterial, plant and animal interactions inside our soil ecosystems … it becomes almost painfully clear that our knowledge of soil ecosystems is teensy, especially in comparison to the human-scale crops and livestock that humans developed and perfected for over ten thousand years before even understanding that things like bacteria and fungi existed. Part of the lack of understanding is scale – in order to really understand micro interactions, it’s necessary to be able to observe at the nano scale. But it’s also matter of understanding ecosystem complexities to frame the questions about co-evolution and stumbling into things, inventing new approaches and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Fleming#Accidental_discovery&quot;&gt;making those REALLY BIG  mistakes&lt;/a&gt;, eg, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.helmholtz-muenchen.de/ibis/&quot;&gt;bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metabolomics&quot;&gt;metabolomics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction&quot;&gt;PCR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metagenomics&quot;&gt;metagenomics&lt;/a&gt; … and doing everything to SCALE THE KNOWLEDGABLE EXPLORATION of how and why the microbial world of soil ecosystems works the way it does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bioremediation,/antibiotics,/enzymes,/metagenomics,/soil/ecosystems/2016/08/24/White-Rot.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>bioremediation,</category>
        
        <category>antibiotics,</category>
        
        <category>enzymes,</category>
        
        <category>metagenomics,</category>
        
        <category>soil</category>
        
        <category>ecosystems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The END of the old American Experiment; the BEGINNING of the new American Experiment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dodd-Frank COMPLETELY changed my retirement plans … in a small way, that’s okay, I guess … life SHOULD come along and completely change things for a person; the’s the beauty of life.  In a much larger way, though, it is a really bad deal for America, Americans and all those who are allies and friends of Americans … in a nutshell, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/dodd-franks-effect-on-small-banks-is-muted-1443993212&quot;&gt;Dodd-Frank has eliminated NEW banking or financial company startup genesis, it has driven banks to merge and consolidate and, unsurprisingly, fewer and larger banks have effective monopolies in some markets boosting their pricing power, so profits of the fewer and larger banks have increased even as customers pay more for a shrinking or stagnant array of services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Dodd-Frank was passed, I had planned to work like a fiend, save everything I earned, invest diligently and then keep re-investing until I could retire at 59 1/2 [since a large portion of what eventually would be my liquid net worth was in IRA/401(k) accounts] to develop an investment company and start-up accelerator [primarily for fintechs] to encourage others to work, save and invest in startups – of course that including getting others to start their own small banks and investment companies.  After Dodd-Frank, I decided to retire early, there was no longer a point in saving, I gave away most of my assets [except for enough to cover my expenses and not be destitute] and I decided to “go Galt” writing, doing research, improving my health, preparing for the inevitable COLLAPSE.  So far the collapse has been unfolding in an especially stagnant fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a high birthrate of new employer firms … there is absolutely NO WAY to get the growth that will be necessary to responsibly handle the debt and contingent liabilities our nation as acquired through its copious expansion of entitlements … a diverse financial ecosystem with robust array of capital alternatives are essential for spurring the birthrate and initial expansion of new employer firms …. Dodd-Frank has killed the goose that laid the golden eggs; look at the disaster it has caused in banking, particularly in small banking and small financial companies – there’s been fewer than a handful of new small banking and small financial companies formed since Dodd-Frank … I do not see an alternative to an inevitable COLLAPSE, but I believe that sooner would be much better than later … while there are still people who remember what banking was like before Dodd-Frank, before Sarbanes-Oxley, before … voters started imagining that government could somehow protect them from their own greed, ignorance and irrational fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I worry that I might be over-confident or lacking in humility, I spend time looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodd%E2%80%93Frank_Wall_Street_Reform_and_Consumer_Protection_Act&quot;&gt;public perception of Dodd-Frank, not just the legislation but the actual regulatory implementation&lt;/a&gt; … few things have the absolute soul-crushing, slit-your-wrists-and-hope-no-one-finds-you quality of Dodd-Frank&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/collapse,/retirement/2016/08/21/Dodd-Franked.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/collapse,/retirement/2016/08/21/Dodd-Franked.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>collapse,</category>
        
        <category>retirement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Antifragile Government</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been watching and re-watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civilization:_Is_the_West_History%3F&quot;&gt;Niall Ferguson’s series on the six killer apps of Western Civilization&lt;/a&gt;. As I have been watching this program, I have also been thinking and reading supporting historical materials with an eye to understanding the demise of different empires and I am almost dumbfounded by the degree to which most people in great empires have always tended to forget the importance of their empire’s foundations, what made them great in the first place.  Thus, I completely agree with the whole premise of the show and highly recommend that others watch and re-watch the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot know if the number of “killer apps” is exactly six or the degree to which these “apps” are interrelated and basically share other deeper dependencies, but six killer apps is probably a good way for framing the discussion.  I believe that we should emphasize some things about those apps differently – the show [like any show broadcast for popular consumption] was constructed [or watered down] TO BE POPULAR and thus avoid any controversy or appearance of toughness or antifragility that would cause people to dismiss the entire show or even question the BBC, Ferguson and those funding the production of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I don’t face the same “lowest-common-denominator” constraint that Ferguson and the BBC did in 2011, so I can state that the six killer apps that made western civilization more antifragile, thus likely to gain from the disorder of history are: 1) intense competition [as a substitute for war], 2) the scientific method and widespread practical discovery, research and debugging, especially outside of academia or domains coercively dominated by the church, governments or similar political/religious institutions, 3) property rights and the Constitutional rule of law [providing the foundation for economic/cultural mobility within the republic and the world], 4) evidence-based environmental health and safety, awareness of fitness [for greater productivity and discipline by key individuals] and some key medical technologies, 5) free markets providing creative destruction of less efficient businesses and diverse alternatives for consumers and employees, 6) freedom of religious or philosophical thought [which underpins the motivation for things like a strong work ethic].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I DISAGREE rather strongly with Ferguson on his conclusion, that we simply need to believe in ourselves … we do need understand our history; that need is what drives Ferguson’s conclusion, as well as his occupational choice … so it’s rather obvious that Ferguson’s conclusion is a HISTORIAN’s conclusion.  That would be fine, but to simply believe in ourselves, to revel in our own greatness … or, what is now, PAST greatness, PAST conquests, PAST victories … might work for a popular show on television, but as a practical operational code, it will create a bunch of backward-looking pride-filled entitled, but impotent little monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom of religion and the philosophical quest still matters … not for experts, academics, high-priests – but for EVERY SINGLE PERSON. It is necessary to understand that the important part of “freedom of religion” is the FREEDOM part … freedom of inquiry, freedom to doubt, freedom to question … but we should acknowledge the practical necessity of having some sort of a belief system. Demanding that everyone must give up their religion is nothing more than demanding conformance to a belief in giving up religion.  One form of zealotry is as EVIL as another. History is replete with examples of the oppression and then stagnation that comes from conformity or uniformity in adherence to any religion or absence or religion (eg, Atheism or ~absence of religion~ and unquestioning faith in authoritarian communist State was the state religion of the USSR).  Freedom of religion serves the purpose of looking forward, for the quest for appropriate vision. As a practical matter all humans must heuristically believe in some higher power, a greater good, a larger agenda or philosophical objective to aspire to and motivate practical plans and SMART goals for conquering the next frontier … it is entirely illogical, meaningless, circular happy talk to tell people we must aspire to believe in ourselves or our pasts … we must look forward.  That means believing in Reality as it really is, not as we hope it might be, fear it might be or as others want us to believe it might be.  We must OPTIMISTICALLY see Reality as our friend; Reality is the ONLY reason we are here. Reality is the ONLY way forward. Instead of boastfully believing in ourselves, I believe that we should humbly seek to understand Reality as it really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our future Reality involves crisis, probably greater crisis than we have experienced at any time in the last two-thirds of a century. It is becoming increasingly apparent some sort of really serious breakdown in the American government is almost certain, perhaps sooner rather than later.  If it is sooner, then something like even civil war [or at least a declaration of martial law, suspension of Constitutional rights] will be likely within the next decade. I am optimistic because I believe that disruption and chaos can be extremely transformative opportunities for human growth. That absolutely does NOT mean that they are easy; it means than disruption and growth is far, far better than stagnation and drudgery. We are heading into very interesting times; these times will not be one bit easy at all; people will suffer and die and wish for less interesting times BUT tough times are necessary to shed weakness, lay the foundation for future post-traumatic growth. There are those who will believe with their full hearts and souls that these times are “end times” but WE humans do not get to decide when THE END is … it is far more likely that these are simply extremely difficult times that will push us and everything about our human institutions harder than we can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to understanding the way forward lies in understanding the essential nature of antifragility and things that gain from disorder and chaos. Small things, like cockroaches, fungus or bacteria, gain from chaos and that applies to our institutions. It is the increasingly centralized nature of our institutions that makes them and the populations that depend upon them weak. The problems of centralization cannot be solved through the same modes of command-and-control thinking that created them. Instead, antifragile solutions will require distributed innovation from decentralized, diverse populations of freethinking innovators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human species can endure far more than any human would ever want to because although herds of dependent humans who look to experts are weak, independent humans who look to their direct experience and Reality-driven knowledge are antifragile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/government/2016/08/17/Antifragile-Government.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/government/2016/08/17/Antifragile-Government.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Government</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pine64 And thoughts on essential element of a building an active hobbyist community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My Pine64 boards showed up last week … actually before I expected to receive them … I have come to expect people who organize and run crowdfunding campaigns for hardware underestimate how difficult it will be to meet any significant project deadline … hardware is HARD.  Shipping hardware and dealing with all of the issues that come from customers attempting to use harder is REALLY hard … but building an open source community around open source hardware is HARDER still … maybe IMPOSSIBLY hard … THAT is WHY I backed the Kickstarter project, not to build and open source community … but maybe to watch it happen, maybe to help make it happen, MOSTLY to see how and why community building comes up short … or what can be done differently next time … and I am absolutely certain that there WILL BE a next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe cultivating an open source community seems to be a matter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.safaribooksonline.com/library/view/cultivate-conference-2016/9781491959701/&quot;&gt;cultivation of leadership&lt;/a&gt; when you do not have the authority to supervise, order or command behavior … but I think it is a lot more ORGANIC and something that requires patient cultivation, like soil building or at least &lt;strong&gt;worm farming&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean to equate hobbyists with &lt;em&gt;worms&lt;/em&gt; but the thing is that the hobbyists have to have basic materials to sustain the life of their interest.  The hobbyists you want in your community are the ones who will have a LOT of really good things to do with their time and interest, ie they will be patient to a degree but they will move on.  Also, the community of hobbyists will need to be left alone, to a degree, to digest what they they want to digest, to do what they want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are different things to think about … but mostly, I think it’s a matter of respecting entirely different interests, skill sets and contributions from others, ie if the developer could do it himself, why would he need any hobbyists?  Why is the project important enough to get people on board, why is the project important enough to motivate you to become a significant participant and leader?  (For example, I do not yet know if Pine64 is really worth my time … I was hopeful, so I forked over some cash to support the initial build, but beyond that … )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rewards are not monetary or recognition that is typically associated with other forms of work … how does the project maintain and cultivate a project heartbeat or momentum or something like a sense of progress on a shared fight that inspires and encourages collaborators?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a better way than GitHub to maintain decentralized, distributed control?  What are the shortcomings of Git?  Are there better ways than Git? Of course, there are, but those ways haven’t been invented yet – the open source community is still getting to that, but the thing about open source community is how the OPEN SOURCE COMMUNITY KEEPS GETTING TO THE THINGS THAT MATTER MOST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So does Pine64 matter enough? Maybe … but it’s not my decision … the ~community~ has to decide that it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/kickstarter/2016/06/05/Pine64.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kickstarter/2016/06/05/Pine64.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>KickStarter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personal Financial Independence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;1) The most essential thing to understand is personal finance is not about investments, it is about YOU, about your independence … YOUR independence means that you make the rules AFTER you pay your way … so personal finance is about YOU, your weaknesses, how much you need comfort, how much you depend upon reinforcement from others. It is certainly NOT about some investment or another, particularly not something that is popular with all of your friends, eg a home purchase.  The person who looks to the opinions of others or measures his wealth according to how well others are doing will NEVER have enough wealth and will always be impoverished. Stop being needy; stop groveling; stop whining, stop being an entitled victim. Do NOT waste ANY time making excuses or thinking that somebody else has it easy. Stop imagining that somebody else should bail you out or invest in your idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Ditch your addictions; ditch the relationships that are not going anywhere; ditch the baggage. First do no harm … especially to your independence. You are an adult and old enough to know that you should not impose your costs on other people. Addicts always have a way of rationalizing robberies, leaching from friends/parents or other ways that somebody else should pay for their addiction.  If you are addicted to bad things, you need to limit the damage those things are doing to you.  It’s not just about the obvious additions like heroin, alcohol or tobacco … addictions include things like tv watching, social media, worthless friends or some other non-value-added distraction. You might believe that you are not an addict, that you can take or leave the thing without any consequences – if that’s true, just avoid the thing for a couple months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Invest in your productivity every single day … do as much as what is possible for you, do not worry about the impossible – that will come. Get in shape so that you can get in shape so that you can get in shape and the impossible will become possible.  Whether you are a morning person or not, get up at 4:39 AM and CRUSH your workout … even if your workout is almost nothing. Physical fitness drives mental fitness. You do not need a gym or dojo membership or a lot of equipment – you can do burpees, pushups, do yoga, take the stairs, clean the house, do yard work. When you start CRUSHING each day’s workout, tomorrow’s workout will mattering and pulling you forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Invest in your health, nutrition and diet every single day … do what is possible, do not worry about the impossible.  Eat better today than you did yesterday and commit to doing this every day for the rest of your life. You know what you should eat; you know what you can afford. For most of eating better is a matter of eating LESS, particularly of one or two things we know we should avoid. If you slip up and have a Krispy Kreme or something you know you shouldn’t have eaten, do not dwell on it – just eat better tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Avoid distractions and costly habits and addictions; avoid friends with addictions who refuse to deal with their addictions. Instead work more on things of value to others that you enjoy. Most creative people and multi-millionaires are working fiendishly on seven to ten serious projects … none of these people are one-off wonders, none of the truly productive or creative people define themselves by the superior tastes in microbrews, food or art … they define themselves with their work. You cannot tell which of these projects will pay off or when it will pay off – the important thing is to keep working obsessively on what you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Control your projector. Inoculate your mind with the kinds of ideas that you want to shape your thinking. The best ideas are the old school ideas that have been around for 2000 years and still inspire current thinking. For example, read and internalize &lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2015/05/28/a-dozen-things-ive-learned-from-seneca-the-younger-about-venture-capital-startups-business-and-life/&quot;&gt;what Seneca said about wealth&lt;/a&gt; … Google “Seneca” routinely to find new reflections from brilliant people on how they apply the words of Seneca to their lives.  In order to escape poverty, it’s essential that you look HARD at how you are spending money and either invent, find or STEAL better ways to enjoy life more while spending less. When you have developed ways to get your cost of living down to $0/day, you don’t need much of a fortune to be fabulously wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) You are the average of your five closest old friends; since this applies to them as well, it is up to you to work with them to increase your average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Curate a set of 100 mentors … blogs, podcasts, YouTube channels … Nicolas Nassim Taleb, Barry Ritholz, Niall Ferguson, Milton Friedman, Thomas Sowell, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8RDCtMEHFLM&quot;&gt;Dave Grossman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkqcY4CAuBFNFho6JgygCnA&quot;&gt;Jocko Willink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/&quot;&gt;Bruce Schneier&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Curate a reading list of 100 books you are reading, re-reading … you do not necessarily need to start right away with Seth Klarman’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://files.leopolds.com/books/Margin.of.Safety.1st.Edition.1991.Klarman.pdf&quot;&gt;Margin of Safety&lt;/a&gt; but eventually you must read it because of what it has to say about discipline, effort, mindset and absolute control of emotions BEFORE investing large amounts of capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Be extremely careful with the use of credit … it is best if you can pay off your debts, but sometimes [eg an existing debt from the past, an accident, an unforeseen medical expense] that is just not feasible.  Realize that debt is not JUST about paying interest to use money, it is ALSO something that constrains your flexibility and options in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11) Before you have to … start thinking about how you are going to completely reinvent yourself.  The next phase of your life may not be what you expect. Your retirement almost certainly will not be what you expect.  Start thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2015/10/reinventing-yourself/&quot;&gt;writing your own guide for completely reinventing yourself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12) Be able to find your way around the world of patents … and scientific literature … and Github repos … and data APIs …  do not EVER, EVER, EVER trust some factcheck organization to give you the truth.  What all factcheck organizations specialize in is the evil art of crafting LIES that look sciencey, look like facts, look truthy. The scientific method still works but that means that YOU must use the method – the fundamental truth of the scientific method is that you do not ever simply trust anyone who claims that they have used the scientific method [so you needn’t check their work].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13) Money is not paper or metal or digital; money is TRUST. For most people, money is basically magic because they trust the system of currency even though it is far beyond anything that they can know well enough to trust. You may want to participate in traditional assets, but you should also invest in different things that you know and know that you can trust … tools, seeds, soil, knowledge, networks, weapons and other hard assets that give you options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14) As Teddy Roosevelt said, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/t/theodorero100965.html&quot;&gt;“Do what you can, with what you have, where you are.”&lt;/a&gt; This means taking honest, careful FULL inventory of what resources are available to you and instead of whining about not having the best, making the best of that stock of resources. ANY time spent being jealous or envious or wanting what someone else has, wanting something beyond your means or beyond what you can do with what you have is time WASTED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15) Read everything you can find to get ideas, but do not trust experts. Experts might be remarkable in their ability to generate ideas, but the ONLY way for you to trust something is for YOU to have TRIED it. Invest in what you KNOW works; do NOT invest heavily in what some expert you believe tells you will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16) Death is certain. Not just for humans, but we also know that the entropy of the universe is always increasing. Everything dies. What you can affect is the window of time before death … in other words, invest effort in appreciating, utilizing and exploiting NOW to the fullest and practice getting better at doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17) Beyond investing in your own productivity and accelerating the development of your own productivity (ie learning how to learn and improving your ability to learn how to learn), also work at investing the productivity of the team than you work with (eg, Github codegraph, GitHub for Teams, Github API).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18) Take a serious inventory of your skills while being mindful of our place in history. You are going to have workout, to get after it, to CRUSH your mental and physical workouts as you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/investor/2014/01/27/active-productive-assets-the-answer-to-the-conundrum-of-potential-financial-ruin/2/#487e43325be7&quot;&gt;skill yourself up&lt;/a&gt;. Invest in your own intellectual property.  Make yourself useful to others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/finance,/investment,/independence/2016/05/21/Personal-Finance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/finance,/investment,/independence/2016/05/21/Personal-Finance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>finance,</category>
        
        <category>investment,</category>
        
        <category>independence</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
